<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Stages 0 and 1</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Chapeau, &lt;a href="http://www.itv.com/sport/tourdefrance/"&gt;ITV4&lt;/a&gt;, for the live coverage, even if I can&amp;#8217;t see myself getting to watch much of it. The prologue stage has definitely whetted the appetite. I&amp;#8217;m pleased Cancellara won. &amp;#8220;My body worked at 100% for exactly ten minutes,&amp;#8221; he said. It&amp;#8217;s almost unthinkable that another expert clock-racer, Brad Wiggins, could drop almost a minute over such a short course, but he did. I&amp;#8217;ve read Wiggo&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Pursuit-Glory-Autobiography-Bradley-Wiggins/dp/0752884034"&gt;In Pursuit of Glory: The Autobiography&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; one for the fans, I think, but one thing I did take from it was how accurately Wiggo can calibrate his form on the track. He knows how long it takes for him to ride a kilometre in a covered velodrome to within a second. A wet road in Rotterdam is less predictable, and Wiggo wanted to avoid trouble. Cancellara has more panache and his bike-handling skills are sans pareil. So he won. Can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him attack the &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;cobbled roads&lt;/a&gt; in stage 3.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com/2010/04/09/2/img_0669_600.jpg" alt="Going. To. Be. Carnage"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hardened campaigner got going when the going got tough. Armstrong took a chunk out of Wiggins and other GC rivals in the &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr/2010/TDF/LIVE/us/0/classement/index.html"&gt;prologue&lt;/a&gt;. He also got the first strike in against Contador (let&amp;#8217;s not forget that he lost 22 seconds to the Spaniard over the same stage last year). I&amp;#8217;ll bet he rattles Contador some more on the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/17414049508"&gt;cobbles&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking forwards to the highlights of Stage One this evening, especially when it became obvious it would end with a bunch sprint. About time to see Cavendish stretch his legs. Except it didn&amp;#8217;t happen like that. Cav has had a rotten run-in to the Tour this year. Always volatile and unpredictable, he&amp;#8217;s turning into very a loose cannon. He tumbled on the final bend taking out rival Oscar Freire. Last year no one got close to Cav. And this year other riders would do well to stay away from him. With Cav down the other riders had to improvise the final kilometre and they made a spectacular mess of it, staging a mass pile up instead of a mass sprint. Quelle horreur!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1</link>
<category>Armstrong</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Someone race Cavendish, please</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/routes/overseas/345690/etape-du-tour-2009-route-recce.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/e/etape-2.jpg" width="540px" height="360px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France takes a rest today (though not for the riders in the &amp;Eacute;tape du Tour, who&amp;#8217;ll take on Mont Ventoux six days before the pros), giving me a chance to try and make sense of a strange and compelling weekend of racing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;#8217;s short sharp climb to Verbier made perfect sense and settled a few outstanding questions. Noone climbs like Contador, and the Madrile&amp;ntilde;o confirmed his position as race favourite and Astana team leader. The way he dances up the steepest slopes is truly thrilling. I can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him climb Ventoux. Armstrong rode with the elite riders, but I&amp;#8217;d say Kl&amp;ouml;den may well be shaping up as the Astana number 2 &amp;#8212; he&amp;#8217;s a strong time trial rider who looked in fine shape on the climb, edging Armstrong at the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about Brad Wiggins? &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/blog/2009/jul/19/bradley-wiggins-tour-de-france"&gt;Shedding 9% of his bodyweight&lt;/a&gt; has morphed him from track rider into Grand Tour contender. Best of all, he&amp;#8217;s enjoying himself. I think he could come out of Thursday&amp;#8217;s time trial &amp;#8212; his favourite discipline &amp;#8212; as Contador&amp;#8217;s main rival for yellow. Awesome!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/14/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france-stage-10"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2009/7/14/1247596770216/Mark-Cavendish-001.jpg" alt="Why isn't Cav in green?" width="460px" height="276px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday&amp;#8217;s stage was more complex. I&amp;#8217;m struggling to understand what Mark Cavendish was playing at. Cavendish already has a remarkable 4 stage victories in this year&amp;#8217;s Tour, matching the 4 he took last year. Well, the number is remarkable, but this year the sprint finishes have seemed routine: the Columbia train leads him out over the final few kilometres, then his team-mates peel away in sequence leaving him to deliver the killer blow. The trouble is, Cavendish&amp;#8217;s rivals have already rolled over and died.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Sport evolves and, if you go back to the 1970s, I never, ever had a lead-out man, not once,&amp;#8221; Hoban said this week. &amp;#8220;Everyone was there, man to man. The way they do it now, with a team like that, if they are leading out at 65kph very few people are going to come over that. Anyone to challenge Mark going at 65kph has got to do 70kph.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/19/tour-de-france-history-hoban-cavendish"&gt;Barry Hoban&lt;/a&gt;, quoted in the Observer newspaper
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d have thought this supremacy would leave Cavendish way out in front in the green jersey but he hasn&amp;#8217;t chased enough intermediate sprints. This leaves him (left him) head to head with the mighty Thor Hushovd in the points competition. My opinion? I don&amp;#8217;t think Cavendish relishes scrabbling for points and it&amp;#8217;s brought out his petulant side.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He says he&amp;#8217;s fastest. His rivals admit he&amp;#8217;s fastest. He is fastest. But he still wants a race!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we had a strange situation. Popular Columbia rider, George Hincapie, was in a breakaway and had a realistic shot at yellow. So team Columbia wanted to slow the chase. But team Columbia also wanted Cavendish to win the peloton sprint for the points given to the 13th place finisher; and so, once more, the train chugged down the final kilometre with everyone watching the clock. Cavendish barely bothered to race for the line. Yes, he blocked Hushovd when he could and should have flown away from him. He wanted to win but in as slow a time as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event Hincapie missed out on yellow by just 5 seconds. You can&amp;#8217;t blame Cavendish for that, but Cavendish is a team player and I suspect he cared more about his team missing yellow than his subsequent disqualification in the sprint. He just wasn&amp;#8217;t bothered about a race for 13th place.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, it&amp;#8217;s probably cost him the green jersey and taken the edge off the showdown next Sunday. I hope he stops feeling hard done by and comes out ready to race. I know he cares more about being fastest on the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es than the points competition.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-20</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race</link>
<category>Armstrong</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Attaque Armstrong!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/1/10162216-073.jpg" width="540px" height="340px" alt="On the same team?"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France 2009 is shaping up to be a truly great race. Any pretence that the Astana team is led by race favourite, Contador, has been dropped &amp;#8212; by Armstrong at least. The tough-talking Texan has spoken in several interviews about the team having more than one leader, in his (singletrack-)mind at least.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armstrong&amp;#8217;s legs did the talking on Monday, a flat 3rd stage of the race. Usually the peleton would stick together on such a stage and it would end with a bunch sprint, probably won by Cavendish, and there would be no changes to the general classification (i.e. the yellow jersey competition).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cavendish did indeed win the sprint but the big news of the day was the break in the peleton, something which can happen in high winds. After the split Armstrong rode in the front group; with Contador in the second group. The split extended to 40 seconds and by the end of the day Armstrong led Contador in the race by some 20 seconds. In the post-race interview shown on ITV4, did Armstrong say he should have dropped back to help Contador? Hell no, he accused Contador of tactical naivety, gaining unexpected support from a disgruntled French rider.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frenchman Christophe Le Mevel claimed it was Contador&amp;#8217;s failure to stick to the wheel in front of him which caused the split with around 30km to go. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/8137119.stm"&gt;BBC Sport report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In yesterday&amp;#8217;s team trial the Astana team rode well together to win the stage, and came within &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/381945/tour-de-france-analysis-why-contador-s-chances-rose-when-armstrong-missed-yellow.html"&gt;tenths of a second&lt;/a&gt; of grabbing the yellow jersey for Armstrong.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to note that had the field not split on Monday, Contador would have been in yellow in Montpellier. Before the Columbia-led move, to which Armstrong and team-mates loyal to him gratefully contributed, Contador was just 18 seconds down overall. Had the bunch stayed together, he&amp;#8217;d have been in yellow by 22 seconds after the team time trial. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/381945/tour-de-france-analysis-why-contador-s-chances-rose-when-armstrong-missed-yellow.html"&gt;Cycling News&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contador still looks the man to beat and yesterday&amp;#8217;s team time trial has set him up well over many of his rivals. Let&amp;#8217;s not forget how well he did in the prologue; let&amp;#8217;s see how he fares in the mountains. Armstrong may be able to needle and even outsmart him, but I can&amp;#8217;t seem him outriding him in the Pyrenees, the real start of the yellow jersey competition.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rider, Armstrong has been admired and feared more than loved. He&amp;#8217;s determined and ruthless rather than charismatic. During his 7 Tour wins he stunned his rivals to the point they even failed to capitalise on his mistakes. I suspect he&amp;#8217;ll be depending on mistakes now, and I can&amp;#8217;t see Contador making another. What&amp;#8217;s more, Armstrong will need charisma and love in his future political career.  He is turning the 2009 Tour into a great race, but one he will ultimately fail to win, and he will speak  truth in defeat; and we will, at last, love him for it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/attaque-armstrong</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/attaque-armstrong</link>
<category>Armstrong</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF prologue. Monaco. Lots of climbing. Epic!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t really get &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/thomasguest"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; yet but I&amp;#8217;ve enjoyed following &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong"&gt;@lancearmstrong&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#8217;s out training with Thor Hushovd. Following cycling results. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/1364794429"&gt;Eating pasta and eggs&lt;/a&gt; before the MSR. Posting a &lt;a href="http://twitpic.com/27op5"&gt;picture of himself&lt;/a&gt; at the top of the Col de la Madone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2883044474/" title="Another col bites the dust by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3078/2883044474_670a5528fb.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Another col bites the dust" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard (pictured above) says Lance Armstrong&amp;#8217;s autobiography is dull. He says it reads like:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In race. Cycle hard. Get to the front. Win race. Another race &amp;#8230; Win again. Train hard &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t read the book myself but this same laconic style of reporting becomes strangely compelling when read one tweet at a time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Done training. 5 hours. Went and previewed the prologue for this year&amp;#8217;s TdF. In Monaco, 10 miles with lots of climbing. Epic. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/1316585412"&gt;@lancearmstrong&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I feel about the news Armstrong had stepped out of retirement? Hard to say. Can he really do it, at the age of 37? Will his team want him back? Can he ride as a domestique for Contador? The official reason given for his return, that he wants to promote &lt;a href="http://www.livestrong.com"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:yellow;background:#333"&gt;LIVESTRONG.COM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I find hard to believe. It&amp;#8217;s not the whole story.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, hard to say. I guess road cycling wants to distance itself from the Armstrong era. Look at some of the other recent Tour &amp;#8220;winners&amp;#8221;. Landis, drugs cheat, stripped of the title. Pantani, drug abuser, tragic death. Ullrich, disgraced. Riis, admitted to doping. The list goes on &amp;#8230; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lance Armstrong has never tested positive for drug use and has probably been tested more thoroughly than anyone else. He&amp;#8217;s also managed to steer clear of the kind of accident which instantly puts paid to all those long hours of training. Luck plays a part, but so do quick wits and superb bike handling skills. &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtZhG2kWVLY"&gt;Watch&lt;/a&gt; how he avoids a crash to stay on route for victory in 2003. Truly epic!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/RtZhG2kWVLY&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/RtZhG2kWVLY&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#8217;s steered clear of injury until recently, that is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m alive! Broken clavicle (right). Hurts like hell for now. Surgery in a couple of days. Thanks for all the well wishes. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/1377776124"&gt;@lancearmstrong&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livestrong.com/lance-armstrong/video/5342-exclusive-postop-interview-lance/5342/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/lance-armstrongs-clavicle.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a post-op picture of his shattered collarbone, held together with a plate and pins. I grabbed it from a video on &lt;a href="http://www.livestrong.com/lance-armstrong/video/5342-exclusive-postop-interview-lance/5342/"&gt;livestrong.com&lt;/a&gt;. Not pretty. Whatever you feel about Armstrong, he&amp;#8217;s a fighter. This is some set-back, but it won&amp;#8217;t mark the end of his TdF ambitions. I think he fancies his chances in the prologue.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-03-27</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/lances-chances</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/lances-chances</link>
<category>Armstrong</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
