<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>The Secret Blackbird</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a treat, to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow.html&quot;&gt;back&lt;/a&gt; at the zoo education centre for the launch of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/secret-blackbird.html&quot;&gt;The Secret Blackbird &amp;mdash; the alarming case of the missing birds&lt;/a&gt;! The book investigates the summer-time absence of garden birds, but before considering this central mystery Geraldine posed some other puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do herons fly overhead when a ground mist covers the downs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do more long-tailed tits fly out of a bush than flew into it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do pied wagtails run in circles round lamp posts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never counted birds in and out of bushes but I reckon I know the answer to the second one: by the time you notice a tit fly into a bush there&amp;#8217;s probably a few others in there already; and you watch them all fly out. Geraldine suggests the discrepancy is always one &amp;#8212; the lone anchor bird which discreetly reconnoitres the bush before giving the others the OK to proceed. So you see, the mystery is all about point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for herons. When the downs are covered in mist Geraldine looks up more. Have you noticed, she added, the way wood-pigeons dive in and out of the mist, like a dolphin? Why do they do that? Lubrication, to stop their wings creaking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5752121266/&quot; title=&quot;Crowded nest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2365/5752121266_4af54dcacc_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; alt=&quot;Crowded nest&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pied wagtails in our garden do run in circles but not around things and not right now, they&amp;#8217;re too busy feeding five hungry fledglings. I&amp;#8217;d assumed it was a courtship display. Geraldine had no definitive answer either. By now, the audience was involved: where do swifts sleep, and what happens to swallows in winter? The swifts fly up high in the evening and wake lower down in the morning, still on the wing. The swallows conglobulate together, by flying round and round, and then all in a heap throw themselves under water, and lye in the bed of a river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dru read a haiku. Deborah Harvey read two poems from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indigodreamsbookshop.com/#/deborah-harvey/4552913959&quot;&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The birds, it turns out, aren&amp;#8217;t missing, they&amp;#8217;re moulting. Low on energy after the nesting season and barely able to fly due to lack of feathers, they lie low, avoiding predators. In the summer of 2010 Geraldine watched a blackbird &amp;#8212; the secret blackbird &amp;#8212; go through this process, and now she retold the story, reading from her book. Dru signalled the part of the bird using a set of semaphore flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more poems, the final one acted out with a soft toy and a star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a very fine book indeed. Dru has surpassed herself with the illustrations, which mix avian character studies and cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-05-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Still Lives, Lenkiewicz, summarised</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5781189874/&quot; title=&quot;Shrouded by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3033/5781189874_51379c43ec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; alt=&quot;Shrouded&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bumped into Nick in the RWA gallery at lunch time. He happened to be there because he wanted to see the damage done to the David Backhouse sculpture at the front of the building, and then he&amp;#8217;d realised there was an exhibition on, and entry was free. So why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told Nick he was lucky, this was the final day of the Lenkiewicz exhibition. It seemed ironic that the publicity resulting from an act of vandalism should draw someone into a show which should have been more than capable of generating its own buzz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve visited the show a number of times and I want to record my response now it&amp;#8217;s over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite stunning. It has been a privilege to enjoy the work of one person displayed with the space and scale it deserves. Lenkiewicz&amp;#8217;s skill as a painter is breathtaking. He paints people, fabrics, ghosts, lemons, interiors, mirrors, memento mori. He does colour. He arranges. He goes large. He paints details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/image-gallery/miscellaneous/1994-retrospective-birmingham-nec/mr-earl-funeral-director-and-family-co&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/files/images/15ROL_P75S.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; alt=&quot;Mr Earl, funeral director, and family, in coffin warehouse&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The huge canvases in the main halls which arrange vagrants, the elderly, the disabled, in classical tableaux; these were my favourites at first. I especially like the burial of John Kynance and the funeral director&amp;#8217;s family group portrait posed in the coffin warehouse. I tend to skip through the next room, the one where the artist paints himself with naked women draped around him. Increasingly I dwell in the final room, the one with the solo portraits. Here characters like Albert Ernest Fisher, known as &amp;#8220;The Bishop&amp;#8221;, who appear in various roles elsewhere in the exhibition, figure simply as themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/image-gallery/themed-projects/project-20-addictive-behaviour/robbie&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/files/images/20ROL_Robbie.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; alt=&quot;Robbie, by Robert Lenkiewicz&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-05-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-lenkiewicz-summarised</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-lenkiewicz-summarised</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/the-burial-of-john-kynance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Burial of John Kynance&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Pike; Death; Doc; Terence P. D. Stott aka &amp;#8216;Blue&amp;#8217;; James Foster aka &amp;#8216;Harmonica Jim&amp;#8217;; Taff; Barney; Victor Jonson/alias/James Howard aka &amp;#8216;Cockney Jim&amp;#8217;; Cyril Hocking aka &amp;#8216;Mephistopheles&amp;#8217;; Wee John; Ghost of Diogenes; and Edwin MacKenzie, aka Diogenes, attend the Burial of John Kynance in a painting by Robert Lenkiewicz currently on display in an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwa.org.uk/currexh.htm&quot; title=&quot;Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz, RWA Bristol&quot;&gt;exhibition&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the Royal West of England Academy, Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene is viewed from the coffin of the recently deceased John Kynance. Diogenes features twice, once as his ghost and once as himself. You&amp;#8217;ll find him elsewhere in the exhibition too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rwa.org.uk/currexh.htm&quot; title=&quot;Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz, RWA Bristol&quot;&gt;Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz&lt;/a&gt;, is a stunning exhibition. The RWA galleries are spacious, light and elegant &amp;#8212; well suited to displaying Lenkiewicz&amp;#8217;s masterful paintings. I will revisit this show many times over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Curious crow, cantankerous goose, life saving Puffin</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to be at the zoo education centre last night for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bristolzoo.org.uk/avon-gorge-and-downs-events&quot; title=&quot;Bristol Zoo event listings&quot;&gt;launch&lt;/a&gt; of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/&quot;&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt;. The evening included readings from the book, mince pies, soft toys, photography, clippings from the Bristol Evening Post, poetry, tea, dramatic reconstructions, slide shows, damson vodka. Yes, you had to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/&quot;&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful book, beautifully observed and exquisitely illustrated. For example, here&amp;#8217;s Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s picture of the fox which Geraldine Taylor saw on Zoo Banks, head back, catching hailstones in its mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2718/4293238314_17bce23898.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fox and hailstones&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geraldine Taylor produced a stuffed goose, prompting us to remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisisbristol.co.uk/news/Goose-terrorised-drinkers-remembered/article-2554802-detail/article.html&quot;&gt;Sylvester, Bristol harbour&amp;#8217;s most famous resident&lt;/a&gt;. When Sylvester died on the final day of this year&amp;#8217;s harbour festival the news made the front page of the Bristol Evening Post. Mr Rankin, who runs Number Seven Boat Trips, paid this handsome tribute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;He lived a full and eventful life attacking people outside various pubs &amp;#8230; We all loved him dearly but he had a big personality and pecked me in all sorts of places. We&amp;#8217;re going to make a coffin and he is going to be buried with full military honours.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sylvester did indeed get a maritime send off. He was ferried from the swan feeding station at Welsh Back down to the Ostrich pub, where he was buried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a break for refreshments Keith Taylor presented a slide show about pioneering wildlife photographers, the Kearton brothers. I think that&amp;#8217;s Richard Kearton supporting Cherry Kearton for a hedge nest shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam349.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;How to photograph a nest in a hedge&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There they are again, up a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam343.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photographing a nest in a tree&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick web search found the complete text of their book &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/index.html&quot; title=&quot;With Nature and a Camera&quot;&gt;With Nature and a Camera&lt;/a&gt; online at the Glasgow Digital Library. Like everything I encountered last night it&amp;#8217;s packed with character. The photos of birds nesting on the cliffs of St Kilda are stunning, all the more so when you see the lengths they took to get them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0213.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gannet and young&quot; style=&quot;align:top&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1102.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam336.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Method of descending a cliff&quot; style=&quot;align:top&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about this for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0312.htm&quot;&gt;bird-related escape&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago a girl, whilst watching the men collect eggs on the Doon, had her petticoats ballooned by a sudden squall of wind, and was lifted clean over the cliff. She fell one hundred and eighty feet without a break, and alighted on a ledge which was covered with earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cragsmen descended to pick up what they very naturally supposed to be the dead body of the poor child, but were surprised to find that she was still alive. Her head had entered a large Puffin burrow, and the force of the blow been expended upon her shoulders. This undoubtedly saved her, and although she hung a whole week between life and death in an unconscious condition, she ultimately made a complete recovery, and was a fine buxom lassie at the time of our visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-12-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Flash not Splash</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3009569427/&quot; title=&quot;pollock by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3032/3009569427_f22c2ee231.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;290&quot; alt=&quot;pollock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jacksonpollock.org&quot;&gt;http://jacksonpollock.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stamen.com/projects/splatter&quot;&gt;http://stamen.com/projects/splatter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/7bvi4/jackson_pollock/&quot;&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-11-07</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/flash-not-splash</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/flash-not-splash</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>2006 North Bristol Art Trail</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I suppose it&amp;#8217;s a bit late for me to recommend the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://northbristolartists.co.uk/&quot;&gt;2006 North Bristol Art Trail&lt;/a&gt;,
but if you didn&amp;#8217;t go, you should have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2006-11-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/2006-north-bristol-arts-trail</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/2006-north-bristol-arts-trail</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alex&#8217;s Tyrannosauruses</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Alex is four years old and into dinosaurs. Here&amp;#8217;s a picture of a mummy
tyrannosaurus, a daddy tyrannosaurus, six tyrannosaurus eggs and one
tyrannosaurus egg which has hatched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/files/tyrannosaurus_family.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Tyrannosaurus family&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2006-10-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-picture-of-tyrannosauruses</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-picture-of-tyrannosauruses</link>
<category>Art</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
