<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/20871409082/in/dateposted-friend/" title="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5776/20871409082_524894d533_z.jpg" width="451" height="640" alt="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in June I went to the launch of Paul Jones&amp;#8217; book &amp;#8220;A Corinthian Endeavour &amp;#8212; The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great talk and it&amp;#8217;s a great book. Here in the UK, we don&amp;#8217;t have Alpine cols or Pyrennean passes. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs"&gt;We have hills&lt;/a&gt;. Hills with erratic gradients and twisted names &amp;#8212; Nick-o-Pendle, Mow Cop, Pea Royd Lane &amp;#8212; hills which, at the end of the cycling season, draw nascent professionals and amateur specialists to battle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/18495855150/in/dateposted-public/" title="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/458/18495855150_4d6165f574_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones has the credentials to tell the tale: an unashamed fan and a talented writer, he is himself a tidy competitor. The book begins with him interviewing Vic Clarke, the man who finished second in the inaugural national hill climb championships in 1944 and who would go on to win the event three times. Also present is Lyn Hamel, a current competitor and multiple champion herself. When Jones offers biscuits (Marks and Spencers Belgian chocolate selection!) both champions decline: for climbers, gravity&amp;#8217;s pull is the enemy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gravity isn&amp;#8217;t the only enemy. Competitors don&amp;#8217;t race head to head. The courses are too short, the roads too narrow. Instead they square up to the clock. The fastest time wins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the book continues Jones deftly weaves the history of the championships around more stories from and interviews with their protagonists. There&amp;#8217;s Chris Boardman, who set and still holds several records. There are other less familiar names: Wilson, Sydney, Armitage, Dobbin, Pettinger.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/anti-gravity-specialists/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cyclinguphill.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Screen-Shot-2015-06-24-at-10.00.13.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered Paul Jones via his &lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/"&gt;Traumfahrrad&lt;/a&gt; cycling blog, a forum where he allows himself more freedom to poke fun and sound off. His blog describes the joy and pain of early morning training rides. He chortles at triathletes who get their socks wrong. You&amp;#8217;ll also find the details of his own assaults on the hill climbs: despite his self-effacement he&amp;#8217;s clearly a feared and respected rider. In the book, though, he reins himself in and logs the facts. The who, what, how and when are painstakingingly researched and recorded. Gear inches matter more to the author than, apparently, to Chris Boardman, who can barely remember if he took part in the races he won, let alone the number of teeth on his sprocket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, though, Jones takes a step back from the details. In one chapter he asks: &amp;#8220;When is a Hill not a Hill?&amp;#8221; A good championship course:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;#8230; should be run on closed roads [&amp;#8230;] Riders should be digging out their hill climb bikes and making &lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/marginal-gains-hill-climb-bike" title=""Tejvan Pettinger strips down his bike"&gt;absurd modifications&lt;/a&gt; for no real gain [&amp;#8230;] each competitor needs to be left flailing on a grass bank like a dying goldfish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contrast this to the 2011 championship on Long Hill:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/2015/08/24/below-the-line/"&gt;&lt;img style="width:500px" src="https://scontent-lhr3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xft1/v/t1.0-9/11796216_10207229514877458_7189614863695398022_n.jpg?oh=a2544be1e9e0a4883cd4531b8946519b&amp;oe=5671E221"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the last, Jones claims hill climbers are ascetics in search of transcendence who tilt their caps backwards. By battling time and human frailty paradoxically they escape it and themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first thing&lt;/br&gt;I have understood:&lt;/br&gt;Time is the echo of an axe&lt;/br&gt;Within a wood.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-08-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Secret Blackbird</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a treat, to be &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow.html"&gt;back&lt;/a&gt; at the zoo education centre for the launch of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/secret-blackbird.html"&gt;The Secret Blackbird &amp;mdash; the alarming case of the missing birds&lt;/a&gt;! The book investigates the summer-time absence of garden birds, but before considering this central mystery Geraldine posed some other puzzles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do herons fly overhead when a ground mist covers the downs?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do more long-tailed tits fly out of a bush than flew into it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do pied wagtails run in circles round lamp posts?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never counted birds in and out of bushes but I reckon I know the answer to the second one: by the time you notice a tit fly into a bush there&amp;#8217;s probably a few others in there already; and you watch them all fly out. Geraldine suggests the discrepancy is always one &amp;#8212; the lone anchor bird which discreetly reconnoitres the bush before giving the others the OK to proceed. So you see, the mystery is all about point of view.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for herons. When the downs are covered in mist Geraldine looks up more. Have you noticed, she added, the way wood-pigeons dive in and out of the mist, like a dolphin? Why do they do that? Lubrication, to stop their wings creaking!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5752121266/" title="Crowded nest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2365/5752121266_4af54dcacc_n.jpg" width="320" height="267" alt="Crowded nest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pied wagtails in our garden do run in circles but not around things and not right now, they&amp;#8217;re too busy feeding five hungry fledglings. I&amp;#8217;d assumed it was a courtship display. Geraldine had no definitive answer either. By now, the audience was involved: where do swifts sleep, and what happens to swallows in winter? The swifts fly up high in the evening and wake lower down in the morning, still on the wing. The swallows conglobulate together, by flying round and round, and then all in a heap throw themselves under water, and lye in the bed of a river.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dru read a haiku. Deborah Harvey read two poems from &lt;a href="http://www.indigodreamsbookshop.com/#/deborah-harvey/4552913959"&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The birds, it turns out, aren&amp;#8217;t missing, they&amp;#8217;re moulting. Low on energy after the nesting season and barely able to fly due to lack of feathers, they lie low, avoiding predators. In the summer of 2010 Geraldine watched a blackbird &amp;#8212; the secret blackbird &amp;#8212; go through this process, and now she retold the story, reading from her book. Dru signalled the part of the bird using a set of semaphore flags.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more poems, the final one acted out with a soft toy and a star.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a very fine book indeed. Dru has surpassed herself with the illustrations, which mix avian character studies and cartoons.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-05-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Curious crow, cantankerous goose, life saving Puffin</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to be at the zoo education centre last night for the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolzoo.org.uk/avon-gorge-and-downs-events" title="Bristol Zoo event listings"&gt;launch&lt;/a&gt; of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt;. The evening included readings from the book, mince pies, soft toys, photography, clippings from the Bristol Evening Post, poetry, tea, dramatic reconstructions, slide shows, damson vodka. Yes, you had to be there.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful book, beautifully observed and exquisitely illustrated. For example, here&amp;#8217;s Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s picture of the fox which Geraldine Taylor saw on Zoo Banks, head back, catching hailstones in its mouth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2718/4293238314_17bce23898.jpg" alt="Fox and hailstones"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geraldine Taylor produced a stuffed goose, prompting us to remember &lt;a href="http://www.thisisbristol.co.uk/news/Goose-terrorised-drinkers-remembered/article-2554802-detail/article.html"&gt;Sylvester, Bristol harbour&amp;#8217;s most famous resident&lt;/a&gt;. When Sylvester died on the final day of this year&amp;#8217;s harbour festival the news made the front page of the Bristol Evening Post. Mr Rankin, who runs Number Seven Boat Trips, paid this handsome tribute:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;He lived a full and eventful life attacking people outside various pubs &amp;#8230; We all loved him dearly but he had a big personality and pecked me in all sorts of places. We&amp;#8217;re going to make a coffin and he is going to be buried with full military honours.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sylvester did indeed get a maritime send off. He was ferried from the swan feeding station at Welsh Back down to the Ostrich pub, where he was buried.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a break for refreshments Keith Taylor presented a slide show about pioneering wildlife photographers, the Kearton brothers. I think that&amp;#8217;s Richard Kearton supporting Cherry Kearton for a hedge nest shot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam349.jpg" alt="How to photograph a nest in a hedge"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There they are again, up a tree.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam343.jpg" alt="Photographing a nest in a tree"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick web search found the complete text of their book &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/index.html" title="With Nature and a Camera"&gt;With Nature and a Camera&lt;/a&gt; online at the Glasgow Digital Library. Like everything I encountered last night it&amp;#8217;s packed with character. The photos of birds nesting on the cliffs of St Kilda are stunning, all the more so when you see the lengths they took to get them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0213.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam091.jpg" alt="Gannet and young" style="align:top"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1102.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam336.jpg" alt="Method of descending a cliff" style="align:top"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about this for a &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0312.htm"&gt;bird-related escape&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years ago a girl, whilst watching the men collect eggs on the Doon, had her petticoats ballooned by a sudden squall of wind, and was lifted clean over the cliff. She fell one hundred and eighty feet without a break, and alighted on a ledge which was covered with earth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cragsmen descended to pick up what they very naturally supposed to be the dead body of the poor child, but were surprised to find that she was still alive. Her head had entered a large Puffin burrow, and the force of the blow been expended upon her shoulders. This undoubtedly saved her, and although she hung a whole week between life and death in an unconscious condition, she ultimately made a complete recovery, and was a fine buxom lassie at the time of our visit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-12-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Rider, Kilometer 61-67</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Rider-Tim-Krabbe/dp/0747559414"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/the-rider-krabbe.jpg" alt="The Rider, book cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Rider-Tim-Krabbe/dp/0747559414" title="The Rider, Amazon.co.uk"&gt;The Rider&lt;/a&gt; is Tim Krabb&amp;eacute;&amp;#8217;s account of the fictional Tour de Mont Aigoual, &amp;#8220;the sweetest, toughest race of the season&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s a short book weighing in at around a page for each of the race&amp;#8217;s 137 kilometres. I&amp;#8217;m reading it as slowly as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central character is a rider named Krabb&amp;eacute;. The other characters make up a fictional peleton &amp;#8212; Barth&amp;eacute;lemy, Kl&amp;eacute;ber, Reilhan, etc. &amp;#8212; and their interrelationships build with the rhythm of the stage, overtaking, falling back, regrouping. Lebusque punctures at 55km, but I&amp;#8217;m sure he&amp;#8217;ll be back. At 61km the first descent starts. Krabb&amp;eacute; reflects on the downhill specialists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 1977 Tour de France, the Frenchman Rouxel was the best downhill man. During a descent of the Tourmalet that year, he bridged a gap of four and a half minutes &amp;#8212; in terms of distance, more than five kilometres!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rouxel says: &amp;#8220;I love going downhill. It&amp;#8217;s like skiing. You have to stay loose the whole time, never lock your knees &amp;#8212; they&amp;#8217;re your shock absorbers. You have to stay down on your bike, to keep your centre of gravity as low as possible. Sure, sometimes when I&amp;#8217;m doing ninety and both wheeels leave the ground, it gives me goose bumps too.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Lebusque and the rest, &lt;a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Rouxel"&gt;Charles Rouxel&lt;/a&gt; is as real as the Tour de France. Certainly he rode the 1977 Tour, though apparently he was eliminated on stage 17 for failing to make the cut-off time. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Col_du_Tourmalet" title="Col du Tourmalet, Wikipedia"&gt;The Tourmalet&lt;/a&gt; featured in the second stage of the race which ran from Auch to Pau. Rouxel may well have made up time on the descent but Lucien van Impe went on to take the stage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/charles-rouxel.jpg" alt="Charles Rouxel"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand what Rouxel has to say about technique, and I too love to go fast, but I&amp;#8217;m no descender. There&amp;#8217;s something terrifying about hurtling towards a bend you can&amp;#8217;t see around. Krabb&amp;eacute; puts it better:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have that kind of looseness. I take the curves like a wooden puppet, afraid that my centre of gravity is going to wind up in the ravine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-04-23</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rider-kilometer-6167</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rider-kilometer-6167</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>In Search of Robert Millar</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strangely, the cyclists who seem to cope least well when the curtain falls on their careers are the climbers. I mean the &lt;em&gt;pure&lt;/em&gt; climbers &amp;#8212; the very few who, when the road soars upwards, are able to take flight, as if they are fleeing those whom Millar nick-named the &amp;#8220;animals&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; all-rounders like Hinault, LeMond, Indurain, Armstrong. Necessarily, the climbing specialists are small, fragile, birdlike in build, power-to-weight ratio being all important in the mountains. And perhaps, in some cases, a rider&amp;#8217;s physical build is not so easily separated from his psychological make-up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Richard Moore, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X"&gt;&amp;#8220;In Search of Robert Millar&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/in-search-of-robert-millar.jpg" alt="Book cover. In Search of Robert Millar"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Moore_%28journalist%29"&gt;Richard Moore&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s superb book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X"&gt;&amp;#8220;In Search of Robert Millar&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, has provided me with the perfect come down after the thrills of this year&amp;#8217;s Tour de France.  Any talk of Bradley Wiggins being &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/384420/tour-comment-is-bradley-wiggins-the-best-ever-brit.html"&gt;the best ever British tour rider&lt;/a&gt; is premature: no one can seriously dispute the book&amp;#8217;s tagline, &amp;#8220;Unravelling the mystery surrounding Britain&amp;#8217;s most successful  Tour de France cyclist&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; unless, that is, they want to remove any qualification of Millar&amp;#8217;s achievements and nominate him simply as Britain&amp;#8217;s most successful road cyclist.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millar&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Millar#Palmares"&gt;palmares&lt;/a&gt; includes king of the mountains in the Giro and the Tour, a 4th place finish in the 1984 Tour, 2nd places in the Vuelta and the Giro, and victory in the Dauphin&amp;eacute; Lib&amp;eacute;r&amp;eacute;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is no hagiography. Millar is revealed as a complex and contradictory character; a man who defies any attempt to get close to him. He comes across as awkward, shy, and abrasive. Many people fail to get his sense of humour. Moore believes Millar had the ability and drive to win a grand tour but lacked the personality. Winning such a race requires the respect of your team and indeed of the peleton, political skills which Millar lacks; and Moore identifies this weakness as the main cause of the conspiracy which tricked him out of victory in the 1985 Vuelta. Millar eventually seemed happier as a super-domestique, a professional who would work for the team, but who remained capable of stealing stages.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millar refuses to play the media game. He has often been rude to commentators and journalists. Yet he has also proved himself to be an &lt;a href="http://www.rouleur.cc/recent-features/240-previewissue13"&gt;articulate thinker and writer&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since retiring from the sport Millar has again taken flight. Where is he now? What is he up to? Few people know. Email is the only way of reaching him, and in the book&amp;#8217;s epilogue Moore does at last make contact with Millar. He reprints their brief email exchange, ending his book with Millar&amp;#8217;s own words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;No more questions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a satisfying, thoroughly researched, well written book. Certainly it asks and investigates difficult questions, but the answers aren&amp;#8217;t always forthcoming. The story continues &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:gold;font-size:400%;"&gt;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-08-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/in-search-of-robert-millar</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/in-search-of-robert-millar</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Review: Becoming Drusilla</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/becoming-drusilla.jpg" alt="Becoming Drusilla cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s hard for me to be objective about &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;Becoming Drusilla&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info" title="Richard Beard's home page"&gt;friend of mine&lt;/a&gt; wrote it and I&amp;#8217;ve met its subject, Dru, a few times &amp;#8212; though she spelled her name &amp;#8220;Drew&amp;#8221; then, short for Andrew, and very male she appeared too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book centres on a journey which starts in Bristol then heads out of Chepstow on foot along &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Offa%27s_Dyke"&gt;Offa&amp;#8217;s Dyke&lt;/a&gt;. As the two of them walk, Richard mulls over his relationship with Dru, past and present, and tries to work out how it all happened. Dru identifies wildlife and knows all the words to some arcane songs. They squabble over directions. Mid-way, they abandon the Dyke, instead heading for St Davids, Pembrokeshire.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a cracking book, if something of a conundrum for book-sellers. On which shelf do you put a travel book which is also a biography and indeed an autobiography, which covers gender issues with wit and intelligence? Oh, and it also includes some rather good haiku and illustrations. &lt;strong&gt;So pile it high near the front, then!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.com/"&gt;&lt;img style="float:left;" src="http://www.facebook.com/profile/pic.php?uid=AAAAAQAQW2Pbi8-IS-Gq5OCcRAGQQwAAAAkNWQzqa9aqZz9B1znkyFAp" alt="Dru Marland, self-portrait"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;Becoming Drusilla&lt;/a&gt; has just been relaunched in paperback. Richard and Dru will be &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=85841341768" title="Becoming Drusilla, Bristol Launch. A Facebook group"&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt; from the book in the Green Room at the Tobacco Factory, Bristol, on Friday 8th May, 7:45 pm.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to meeting Dru again. It must be almost a decade since we last met in person. Now, of course, I&amp;#8217;ve read her biography. I&amp;#8217;m also her friend on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/people/Dru-Marland"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; which doesn&amp;#8217;t mean much since I barely use Facebook. She has a &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.com/"&gt;fine blog&lt;/a&gt; and her Flickr &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/belvedere/"&gt;photostream&lt;/a&gt; includes some beautiful photographs and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/belvedere/sets/72157594410663343/"&gt;illustrations&lt;/a&gt;. See you on Friday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: looks like Richard is unwell and won&amp;#8217;t be able to make it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-05-06</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-becoming-drusilla</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-becoming-drusilla</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Hobbit</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t think of many books which feature a burglar as a hero, but then Bilbo Baggins makes a rather reluctant hero &amp;#8212; for much of the story he finds himself wondering why everyone makes such a fuss about adventures, and wishing he were back at home in his comfortable hobbit hole with its well-stocked pantries.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tolkienbooks.net/html/the_hobbit.htm"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" src="http://www.tolkienbooks.net/images/thumbs/hobbit-1961-th.jpg" alt="The Hobbit cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The Hobbit&amp;#8221; is a book I was read, as a child. I can clearly remember my parents&amp;#8217; edition of the book, with its dark cover and yellowing pages. My mother tells me that was when I started to read for myself: one evening I just couldn&amp;#8217;t wait to hear what happened next, so I didn&amp;#8217;t.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hobbit"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.tolkienbooks.net/images/other/hobbit-binding.gif" alt="Cover of first edition of The Hobbit"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I&amp;#8217;ve just finished reading it to my own children. With its riddles, songs and last-gasp escapes, it reads aloud beautifully. We&amp;#8217;ve all thoroughly enjoyed it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-03-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-hobbit</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-hobbit</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rourke, wrestler, barfly, Bukowksi</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=" http://www.bafta.org/awards/film/film-nominations-in-2009,657,BA.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/mickey-rourke-bafta.jpg" alt="Mickey Rourke at the BAFTAs"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mickey Rourke shambles on stage, hunches over the mike, cusses a bit, thanks his best mates for sticking by him, shambles off again. Actors: you never know when they&amp;#8217;re acting and when they&amp;#8217;re not, and I&amp;#8217;m not convinced they do either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rourke&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.bafta.org/awards/film/film-nominations-in-2009,657,BA.html"&gt;best actor gong&lt;/a&gt; comes for his portrayal of Randy &amp;#8220;The Ram&amp;#8221; Robinson in &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1125849/"&gt;The Wrester&lt;/a&gt;, a film I watched with my brother a couple of weeks ago. It&amp;#8217;s a terrific film but makes for uncomfortable viewing: the wheezy soundtrack and out of focus imagery take us directly into Randy&amp;#8217;s world, a world where the wrestling matches may be staged, but the blood, scars and pain are all too real.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/mickey-rourke-the-wrestler.jpg" alt="Randy The Ram Robinson"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface it&amp;#8217;s about a faded wrestler who defies health problems for one last comeback bout; but it&amp;#8217;s tempting to see it as Rourke&amp;#8217;s own story. In The Ram&amp;#8217;s words.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just want to say to you all tonight I&amp;#8217;m very grateful to be here. A lot of people told me that I&amp;#8217;d never wrestle again and that&amp;#8217;s all I do. You know, if you live hard and play hard and you burn the candle at both ends, you pay the price for it. You know in this life you can lose everything you love, everything that loves you. Now I don&amp;#8217;t hear as good as I used to and I forget stuff and I aint as pretty as I used to be but god damn it I&amp;#8217;m still standing here and I&amp;#8217;m The Ram. As times goes by, as times goes by, they say &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s washed up&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s finished&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s a loser&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s all through&amp;#8221;. You know what? The only one that&amp;#8217;s going to tell me when I&amp;#8217;m through doing my thing is you people here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bukowski"&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/e2/Charles_Bukowski_smoking.jpg" alt="Charles Bukowksi" style="float:right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1987, at the peak of his success, Mickey Rourke chose to play writer &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bukowski"&gt;Charles Bukowski&lt;/a&gt; in the film &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092618/"&gt;Barfly&lt;/a&gt;. Bukowski is best known for his books about Henry Chinaski, a womanizing, gambling drunk who lurches from one dead-end job to the next. To what extent are these books autobiographical? I&amp;#8217;m not sure, but I do know Bukowski was sober enough to write a lot of great material. I particularly recommend his first novel, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0061177571?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;Post Office&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0061177571?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/postoffice.gif" alt="Post Office"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rourke shed his pretty boy looks and gained several kilos to play Bukowski in &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092618/"&gt;Barfly&lt;/a&gt;, a film which was also scripted by Bukowski, but now botched plastic sugery and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mickey_Rourke#From_actor_to_boxer"&gt;one bout too many in a boxing ring&lt;/a&gt; have spoiled his looks for real. He remains charismatic, a fine actor, but what other roles can there be for him? Henry Chinaski, fictional post office worker?
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-02-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/rourke-wrestler-barfly-bukowksi</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/rourke-wrestler-barfly-bukowksi</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Great books, 2008</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I enjoy reading a book I make a mental note to review it here, but somehow I haven&amp;#8217;t got round to writing all those reviews. The truth is, I find it very hard to put in words exactly why I like a book. So here are three books I read last year which I really must recommend.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Stuart, A Life Backwards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0007241771?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/stuart-a-life-backwards.jpg" alt="Stuart: A Life Backwards (cover)"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Masters&amp;#8217; book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0007241771?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;Stuart, A Life Backwards&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; starts with the death of its anti-hero, Stuart, a &amp;#8220;chaotic&amp;#8221; homeless person from Cambridge, then proceeds to tell his life story in reverse order. (Here the term &amp;#8220;chaotic&amp;#8221; is used to describe someone whose life is completely out of control: offender, chronic drug abuser, alcoholic). On the surface, this is a plainly written biography &amp;#8212; Stuart Shorter&amp;#8217;s true story written down directly by hostel worker Alexander Masters &amp;#8212; but you&amp;#8217;ll come to appreciate it as a cleverly constructed and well written novel. The reversed narrative works brilliantly: from the start we know what happens, but as the story unfolds we find out how and why (as much as there can ever be a how and why in such a sad story).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;English Passengers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/038549744X?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/english-passengers.jpg" alt="English Passengers"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Kneale&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/038549744X?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;English Passengers&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; is a rollicking adventure and historical novel which travels round the world, involving the brutal extermination of Tasmanian aboriginals, Victorian science, religion, and Manx smugglers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Life, A User&amp;#8217;s Manual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one niggle with &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/038549744X?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;English Passengers&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;: for me, it didn&amp;#8217;t particularly improve as I worked my way through it. For big books telling big stories, with multiple storylines and narrators, it&amp;#8217;s important that the story should gather momentum and pull you along to the ending.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0002719991?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://wordaligned.org/images/books/life-a-users-manual.jpg" alt="Life A User's Manual"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third book &amp;#8212; my book of 2008 &amp;#8212; doesn&amp;#8217;t just get better as you read through it, it gets better each time you read it. Georges Perec&amp;#8217;s masterpiece &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0002719991?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;Life, A User&amp;#8217;s Manual&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; is a big book which tells many stories. Utterly different from any other book I&amp;#8217;ve read, yet very accessible, it makes great reading out of both the quotidian and the fantastical. It&amp;#8217;s a compelling and moving story about human failure.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-01-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/great-books-2008</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/great-books-2008</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Brighton Rock</title>
<description>&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142437972?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/brighton-rock.png" alt="Brighton Rock"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back from holiday in Portugal, the cold and dark making us shiver, on checking the garden we discover the one pumpkin the slugs failed to destroy has also failed to ripen so Gail heads for the shops returning later with diabolical costumes for the children and I&amp;#8217;m reminded of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142437972?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;Graham Greene&amp;#8217;s Brighton Rock&lt;/a&gt;, a book I read whilst away, a book I&amp;#8217;ve read several times but which never fails to terrify, whose main character, Pinkie, is cruel and innocent and evil.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-10-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/brighton-rock</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/brighton-rock</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>We Need to Talk About Kevin</title>
<description>&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/006112429X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/we-need-to-talk-about-kevin.jpg" alt="We Need to Talk About Kevin"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read Lionel Shriver&amp;#8217;s powerful novel, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/006112429X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;We Need to Talk About Kevin&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, over the summer. The story centres on a school massacre and is narrated by Eva Khatchadourian, a mother who, in a series of letters to her estranged husband Franklin, comes to terms with the horrific murders committed by her son, Kevin. Even before he was born Eva had trouble with Kevin. She hated carrying him, never wanted him, resents him for spoiling her career, her marriage, her life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s just a story but school massacres are very real. At first I thought the novel might be an attempt to analyse a serious subject through fiction, in which case I&amp;#8217;d probably not have got to the end of it. In fact it&amp;#8217;s a thriller, a page-turner. From the outset we know &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; is going to happen but not &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;. Kevin doesn&amp;#8217;t want to be any old school murderer, he wants to do it with style, he wants to be the best. Details of the massacre he enacts are saved until last. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A horrible disturbing book. Recommended.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-09-29</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/we-need-to-talk-about-kevin</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/we-need-to-talk-about-kevin</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Run Away</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2744090734/" title="The Run Away front cover"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3291/2744090734_4fc4c79120_m.jpg" width="169" height="240" alt="The Run Away front cover" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2744090798/" title="The Run Away blurb"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3272/2744090798_3d75c16364_o.png" width="522" height="285" alt="The Run Away blurb" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-08-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-run-away</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-run-away</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>A Short History of Tractor Fishing in the Yemen</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Short-History-Tractors-Ukrainian/dp/0141020520/ref=pd_bbs_1/026-2389784-2367637?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1189585741&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;A Short History of Tractors in Ukrainian&lt;/a&gt; was one of my favourite books from last year, a fact which, funnily enough, put me off the similarly titled &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Salmon-Fishing-Yemen-Paul-Torday/dp/0753821788/ref=sr_1_1/026-2389784-2367637?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1189585930&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Salmon Fishing in the Yemen&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; I assumed the yemen-salmon book would be a flimsy me-too book, pushed out by publishers on the back of the ukrainian-tractor&amp;#8217;s success.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://ec1.images-amazon.com/images/I/51sLQq1kRLL._AA240_.jpg" alt="salmon book cover"/&gt;
   &lt;img src="http://ec1.images-amazon.com/images/I/51WRNVtcnOL._BO2,204,203,200_PIsitb-dp-500-arrow,TopRight,45,-64_OU02_AA240_SH20_.jpg" alt="tractor book cover"/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so. I greatly enjoyed the salmon book. Unlike the tractor book, salmon and salmon fishing are central to the the plot: Dr Alfred Jones, a government scientist, is roped into a crazy scheme to introduce salmon to the Yemen. It turns he&amp;#8217;s actually being manipulated by the Prime Minister and his director of communications, Alistair Campbell, oops Peter Maxwell I mean, who are desperate for a feel-good story in the Middle-East, though as the story continues, Jones falls increasingly under the influence of an inspirational sheik and his attractive assistant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a deftly-written satire. My only complaint is that, as a satire, it loses its bite as it continues: the best satires (The History Man, for example) should start with you laughing and end with you crying. This one left me laughing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://news.bbc.co.uk/olmedia/1040000/images/_1044800_historymanbbc300.jpg" alt="The History Man"/&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2007-09-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-short-history-of-tractor-fishing-in-the-yemen</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-short-history-of-tractor-fishing-in-the-yemen</link>
<category>Book</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
