<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>The last ever Pomphrey 5K</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On a warm summer evening I cycled out of Bristol on the railway path. The verges were overgrown, the air dense with insects. Coming through Staple Hill the path enters a tunnel, water falling from the arching roof and onto the tarmac.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I count the Pomphrey Sports 5K as unfinished business. Last time I ran it &amp;#8212; the only time I&amp;#8217;d run it, in fact, the only timed 5K I&amp;#8217;d ever run &amp;#8212; on a dark, blustery winter&amp;#8217;s evening it took me &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=70510&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Jan-13"&gt;18 minutes and 44 seconds&lt;/a&gt; to get round. Today, I had to do better. I wanted to test my speed ahead of the &lt;a href="http://www.swanseahalfmarathon.co.uk/"&gt;Swansea half&lt;/a&gt;. An email from race director, Chris Elson, warned me I wouldn&amp;#8217;t get another chance:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This race incorporates the Avon AA mob match with the winning team (20 to count) being awarded the Andrew Rawnsley Memorial Trophy. We hope there will be lots of Avon Clubs with teams! &lt;strong&gt;This race will be the last, after some 15 years&lt;/strong&gt;, to be held on the course but
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;plans are at an advanced stage to move the race to a flat fast course using the mile circuit at Aztec West.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short warm up around Pomphrey Hill playing fields, I joined the other runners at the start of the course. Fewer than I expected &amp;#8212; maybe a couple of hundred of us, and only seven from &lt;a href="http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk/"&gt;SRC&lt;/a&gt;. There was Sam Stone, a work colleague, running for &lt;a href="http://www.emersonsgreenrunningclub.co.uk/"&gt;Emersons Green&lt;/a&gt;. We gathered on the cycle track under the B4465 bridge over the ringroad. After a brief announcement, we were off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, 5K is a tough distance. It feels like I&amp;#8217;m running flat out the whole way. The track veers through a subway under the ringroad. At 1K, my watch showed 3:30. Now we skirted the new roundabout exit, trainers hitting plywood boards laid over fresh tarmac. Crossing the ringroad now on a pedestrian bridge. I hit 2K around 7 minutes in and realised my target, 18 minutes, was very much on. Matt was just ahead. Around us, red and white vests, Bristol and West. The track takes a left at the next roundabout and then at exactly 2.5K out doubles back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/157862063/embed/5f0a94ffb444a1ce7f5bffd483e08cd8159dbe32'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My legs felt tired in the final kilometre. Somehow sensing my weakness Matt opened a gap which 5 Bristol and West runners smartly filled. I checked my watch. A PB for sure. 18 minutes, definitely, but having got into this position how hard would I push for the finish? Did I really want to set a best time which would be out of reach in future? My legs felt ragged.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I crossed the line under the bridge over the ringroad and stopped my watch. 17:48, it said. 17:50, officially.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the presentation, Roger, one of the race directors, took the opportunity to talk about the history of the race which originated some 20 years ago to finance Bristol and West AC sending competitors all round the country, paying for petrol and entry fees. There was no roundabout, no ring road, no cycle track. The sports pavilion we sat in hadn&amp;#8217;t been built and so the Bridge Inn hosted the event which was run on dirt tracks around the former quarry.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first MV50 to finish, in 22nd place with an official time of 17:50, I picked up a &amp;pound;5 Easy Running voucher. Without me being aware of it the next two runners, just 4 and 13 seconds behind me, were also MV50&amp;#8217;s. Some race!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
1      15.23   John Ashcroft   Bristol University      SM
2      15.34   Matt Whitfield  Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
3      16.21   James Denne     Exeter Harriers         SM
4      16.33   Jarlath McKenna Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
5      16.35   Matthew Krelle  Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
6      16.48   Mark Edwards    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
7      17.06   Iain Stuart     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
8      17.08   Olly Sheppard   Team Bath AC            SM
9      17.09   Sam Hedley      Team Bath AC            SM
10     17.14   Jenny Jagger    Bristol &amp; West AC       SW
11     17.24   Anthony Hall    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
12     17.26   Torran Elson    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
13     17.34   Jacob Hayes     Bitton Road Runners    M40
14     17.35   Matt Burns      Southville              SM
15     17.37   Chris Palmer    Westbury Harriers       SM
16     17.38   Peter Gandon    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
17     17.40   Alexander Whittaker  Bristol &amp; West AC  SM
18     17.41   Helen Sharpe    Bristol &amp; West AC       SW
19     17.42   Phil Lucker     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
20     17.44   Jason Barry     Stroud &amp; District      M40
21     17.46   Ben Farrell     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
&lt;b&gt;22     17.50   Thomas Guest    Southville             M50&lt;/b&gt;
23     17.54   Gary Hughes     Team Bath AC           M50
24     18.03   Phil Westlake   Bitton Road Runners    M50
25     18.04   Julian Bailey-Gard Westbury Harriers    SM
26     18.06   C McQuade       Unattached              SM
27     18.08   Andrew Malloy   Bristol &amp; West AC      M40
...
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling back along the track which was once a railway I thought about Bristol traffic, transport and history. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-06-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Wrington Woodland Tyntesfield 10</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At the start of the month I attempted the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Wrington Woodland&lt;/a&gt; run. Conditions were warm and damp. The race starts with a gradual climb from Goblin Coombe. I was tracking the leaders at this stage. The rocky track became a river of viscous clay. A Frome runner slipped and slithered, his &lt;a href="http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/running_mens.htm"&gt;five fingers&lt;/a&gt; affording little traction. I moved past into second place.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=http://www.theracephotographer.com/2014/WWR/Set_A/large/image_a0007.jpg alt="WWR, theracephotographer.com/2014" width=640px /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own shoes &amp;#8212; my normally trusty Adidas swoop trail shoes &amp;#8212; skidded on the fast tarmac descent to Wrington. I slowed down then pushed on, determined to hold my position. On the second climb, the steep one up Bullhouse Lane, my right calf went. I limped, then walked, then tried to run through the injury, then walked again. I was in some pain. Runners passed me. I&amp;#8217;m fine, I said, it&amp;#8217;s cramp. The woods on top of Wrington Hill were packed with bluebells. A kindly marshal gave me a lift back to the HQ once the race had passed. My first ever DNF. I felt lousy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, three weeks later, I showed up for the &lt;a href="http://nailsearunningclub.org.uk/club-races/"&gt;Tyntesfield 10&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; a favourite event from last year. My calf still isn&amp;#8217;t 100% but I needed to get round the course to put Wrington behind me. I could surely do that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started easily on the first meadow circuit. We looped back to the house, swerving round the croquet lawn and flowerbeds, then back to the meadow again. My legs felt good. I pushed on towards the woods, passing runners as the track rose. Watch out for tree roots! Go on Southville! The track twists and swerves, hurdling fallen trees, ducking under branches. I was glad to be clear and able to pick my own route. Andy Malloy cruised past. I drafted him, pulling me into contention with a couple of other runners.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the woods and into long grass, nettles, thistles, rape. At this stage last year I&amp;#8217;d been wiped out. Today, a more cautious start had earned me something in reserve. To my surprise, Annabel Granger was in range, plus another couple of runners I didn&amp;#8217;t know. At last we reached the long descent bringing the route back home. I passed one runner. I passed two more, only for them to nip ahead when I misinterpreted a marshal&amp;#8217;s signal and turned the wrong way. Down the steps and on to the tarmac. I dug in on the final short climb, regaining my earlier position. On the finishing straight, for the first time in the race, I looked behind me. My position was safe. I crossed the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training mate Neil Williams was so close behind I didn&amp;#8217;t see him finish. I cheered in another friend, Steve Swan, drank the water and ate the minuscule cereal bar in the goodie bag.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14056237608" title="Tyntesfield 10k by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/14056237608_9b09156c0c_z.jpg" width="640" height="428" alt="Tyntesfield 10k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was 7th to finish and 1st in my category. My time, &lt;a href="https://www.fullonsport.co.uk/fos/index.php?module=results&amp;amp;eventId=4350&amp;amp;action=results" title="Race results"&gt;40:39&lt;/a&gt;, was 22 seconds faster than at the same event last year. Next up: the Welsh Castles Relay.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rich Kenington, &lt;a href="http://www.theracephotographer.com"&gt;theracephotographer.com&lt;/a&gt;, and Sally Johnson for the excellent action shots used on this page.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-05-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-tyntesfield-10</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-tyntesfield-10</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Blaise Blazer, from A to T, August 2013</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle estate, another great location for a multi-terrain race. I was looking forward to running in the third and last of Westbury Harriers&amp;#8217; &lt;a href="http://www.westburyharriers.co.uk/promotions.html"&gt;Blaise Blazer 2013 races&lt;/a&gt; for a couple of reasons: first, my knowledge of the estate&amp;#8217;s winding paths and trails could only be to my advantage; and second, I&amp;#8217;d be running for Southville Running Club, who I train with on Tuesday evenings, and who would be defending the Blazer Challenge Cup they won in 2012.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time, I&amp;#8217;d try not to arrive so early. It took a while to register everyone. Eventually, over 120 runners toed a wide starting line on the field looking down towards the mansion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/10859993384/" title="blaise-blazer by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7353/10859993384_334b3ce734_z.jpg" width="640" height="570" alt="blaise-blazer"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We charged across the grass to A hitting the path at B. I must have been about 20th at C, the foot of the first climb, and picked up a few places by H, where we switched from a well-surfaced path to a woodland trail. Matt, Mike, Mark and Tim &amp;#8212; all Southville runners &amp;#8212; were ahead, but not too far ahead. Climbing I, J, K, a treacherous uphill track, I passed Tim. I took the muddy descent from O to P carefully. Mike pulled away on the flat, Q, and somehow I was pulling away from Mark and staying in contact with Matt. Maybe I could have done more on the final climb to the castle, R, S, T, but maybe I didn&amp;#8217;t know the paths quite as well as I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I was glad to finish and cheer in the remaining runners.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half an hour later we were back at the Westbury Harriers club house and half an hour after that the results had been logged and checked. Southville retained the Challenge Cup, hooray! I finished 10th, the first MV40, in a time of 24:17.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/10859883155/" title="Southville Running Club, Blazer challenge cup holders 2013 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3755/10859883155_890e326008_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Southville Running Club, Blazer challenge cup holders 2013"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-09-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2013</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The TACH ticks talk</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Happily I recovered from flu in time to line up for the start of the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Wrington Woodland&lt;/a&gt; run. 100 or so of us queued on the footpath just outside Cleeve listening to a well rehearsed pre-race briefing: this is going to take 5 minutes so don&amp;#8217;t stare at me, I won&amp;#8217;t go any faster, a special announcement, Jim and Alfredo are running &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/10kX365"&gt;10km a day every day this year&lt;/a&gt; so like them on Facebook and when you shower check yourself for ticks, you&amp;#8217;re unlikely to have any and they&amp;#8217;re unlikely to be carrying Lyme disease, which can usually be treated, but if you do and they are and you aren&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8230; conditions &lt;strong&gt;downhill&lt;/strong&gt; are fine but uphill watch out for tree roots, loose stones etc. Honk! We were off!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path climbed steadily up Cleeve Hill. Matt hung behind the leaders then eased away hitting a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow. Andy passed me when the path levelled off. A tall runner from Weston AC bounded downhill on elastic legs. Hey, maybe I was still the first veteran runner on the course? If I was, I wasn&amp;#8217;t for long. I felt weary on the climb up Wrington Hill; Andrew Malloy (V40) and  Adrian Noble (V50) overtook. At last the track levelled and zigzagged downhill back to Cleeve. I clattered over a narrow wooden bridge and cleared a stile and ran on wobbly legs across one last field to the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done Matt for winning! Jim and Alfredo ran on through the finish, the route being a few metres short of 10k. Prize-giving was held in the Lord Nelson skittle alley. How we cheered!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9381867241/" title="About a mile into the Burrington Blaster by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3734/9381867241_da0013242e_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="About a mile into the Burrington Blaster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second race, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Burrington Blaster&lt;/a&gt;, found me in better form, which is just as well: the route took us from the Burrington Inn right up to the top of the Mendips in one long climb. The view at the summit was spectacular and although the urge to stop and admire it was strong I pushed on through gusting winds and boggy footing. 4th place was mine if I could negotiate the treacherous descent. I couldn&amp;#8217;t, falling a short way from the finish when my feet slid on loose stones. Nothing damaged, but physical and mental momentum destroyed. A couple of red and white vests &amp;#8212; Bristol and West &amp;#8212; passed. I held on for 6th.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fancied my chances in the third race, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Purdown Pursuit&lt;/a&gt;, my former training ground. When I lived in Cobourg Road, on Sunday mornings I&amp;#8217;d head out along Boiling Wells Lane and past the telecoms tower, attacking a selection of Purdown&amp;#8217;s short sharp hills before passing the UWE campus to head under the M32 and back through Frenchay and Snuff Mills. How could they fit 10k into Purdown, I wondered? The answer turned out to be a double loop; the first short circuit had me wondering how I&amp;#8217;d hang on for the second longer loop, this one covering the full length of the down, Stoke Lane to Muller Road and back again. Hold on I did, passing a pony-tailed Nailsea runner who took a wrong turn through the woods, and losing a place to Andrew Malloy (again!) on the final downhill swoop. I collapsed at the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9381881853/" title="Purdown pursuit by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5327/9381881853_858db6ec4d_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Purdown pursuit"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something different! Race four, closing the series, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Dundry Thunder&lt;/a&gt; run, started at the top of the hill. A prolonged spell of hot weather had broken into storms during the week and I wondered if the thunder would be more literal than alliterative, but the evening turned out just fine, clear, not too hot, as we gathered on the downs at foot of the radio masts. You could see all of Bristol, city and suburbs, the Clifton bridge, and beyond to the Severn estuary spanned by another suspension bridge and the angular second crossing. I warmed up, running the wrong way along the finishing straight, skipping over thistles and cowpats. The start was delayed whilst a local resident trimmed his hedge, destroying some route markings in the process.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race was a double loop: starting with a jostling descent down Littleton Lane towards Winford. Determined to hold something back for the second loop, I watched the leaders stride away from me. Behind a hedge, the sound of gunshots. We turned off the lane and looped back through fields up the hill to Dundry, negotiating uneven ground, gates and stiles. Skittish cattle stampeded across the course. I pulled back a couple of places on the climb and sped up when we reached the level section along Crabtree Lane, vaulting a gate at the same time as a Weston AC runner tried to open it. We waded through a field of oilseed rape, the heavy pods slapping our legs, then past another radio mast. The second extended downhill cut a diagonal through a barley field. More gates, stiles, streams. Now we were back on Littleton Lane for a final drag uphill to the finish. I was tired but the runners around me were too, maybe more so. The tall runner from Weston AC was walking. I went past. Further on, I passed Matt. Briefly I nosed ahead of Andrew Malloy but that spurred him to up his pace and pull away again. One last momentum-sapping stop-start through a gate and I could see the line. Was Matt on my heels or 50m away? Now would not be a good time to look back. I blundered through thistles and cowpats and crossed the line exhausted but in control. The 5th place I thought I&amp;#8217;d got turned out to be 4th. Result!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary: in the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;WW, BB, PP and DT&lt;/a&gt; races I came 9th 6th 5th 4th with times of 39:45, 37:11, 42:52 and 42:32.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the TACH team for organising such a great series of races with good humour and efficiency. I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to next year already. Four pubs did well to serve drinks to all those thirsty runners but I guess they did well out of it too. Thanks to Matt for transporting the Swansea Harriers team. Thanks also to Rachel Foyle and Emma Postlethwaite for allowing me to use their fine photos here. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-07-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>2012-2013 Cross Country season and some</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I recorded some of my race results since the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012.html"&gt;WCR, 2012&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next race was the &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk"&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt; opener at Newbridge Fields, Bridgend. I ran this same course the year before on a cold, blustery day, sheets of rain swirling. This time, the weather turned out unseasonably warm. I came &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm121i.htm"&gt;78th with a time of 38:22&lt;/a&gt;, an improvement of 26 places and 3 minutes over my previous outing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4531393735/" title="Whiteford Sands lighthouse by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2772/4531393735_eba09f0864.jpg" width="500" height="371" alt="Whiteford Sands lighthouse"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after I ran closer to home in the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;West Glamorgan League at Llanmadoc&lt;/a&gt;. Although the rain held off on the day, it hadn&amp;#8217;t over the past weeks and the track out to the lighthouse comprised a series of ponds linked by mud. I made a mistake lining up for the start some way from the front of the field and ended up jostled and sodden by the time the race stretched out and settled in. After, I hooked up with Ifan for a warm down; we ran the full route a second time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://westglamleague.co.uk/resources/_wsb_417x374_West+Glam+League+at+Llanmadoc.jpg" alt="puddles"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle, Bristol, for the 3rd fixture in the Gwent League. Isobel and Alex ran too. I tried to keep up with Eamon but he pulled away on the second lap. In the closing stages I looked over my shoulder to see Raul storming towards me. I had enough left, or he timed his surge for the line too late; either way I &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm123i.htm"&gt;finished ahead of him&lt;/a&gt;, but I can&amp;#8217;t see that happening next time we race together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was it, my cross country season over. I was supposed to run the Welsh regional cross country championships but didn&amp;#8217;t make it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of January this year I ran the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolandwestac.org/bridge-inn-5k"&gt;Bridge Inn 5K&lt;/a&gt; on a very windy night and did well to finish &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0BzIFRjtRS2vBVkE3b1dWV0RrUUU/edit"&gt;a few seconds&lt;/a&gt; before Matt Burns.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I ran the first of four alliterative &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;TACH races&lt;/a&gt;, the Wrington Woodland run, which I thoroughly enjoyed. The &lt;a href="http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/v2/181608257/218757"&gt;course&lt;/a&gt; started in Cleeve with a long but gradual climb up a woodland track. After a few dry weeks the surface was rocky and rutted. Matt (who I beat in the 5K, remember?) strode ahead a few minutes in, clocking a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow; and, as it turned out, noone else could either. As we crested the top of the climb Andy overtook me. On the descent to Wrington another runner bounded past. I wasn&amp;#8217;t feeling too fresh by Bullnose Lane, the second uphill section, and settled on trying to hold my place rather than catch anyone. Even that proved optimistic and a couple of runners pegged me back before the final descent back to Cleeve.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased with &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=wrington_result13.inc"&gt;9th place&lt;/a&gt;. Congratulations to Matt on his well deserved win! A diet of interval training and competitive racing have honed his form and after a series of top ten placings in recent events it came down to when not if.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.srcbristol.hostoi.com/images/sidebar/bristol_running_club_matt.jpg" alt="Burnsy" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Secret Blackbird</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a treat, to be &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow.html"&gt;back&lt;/a&gt; at the zoo education centre for the launch of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/secret-blackbird.html"&gt;The Secret Blackbird &amp;mdash; the alarming case of the missing birds&lt;/a&gt;! The book investigates the summer-time absence of garden birds, but before considering this central mystery Geraldine posed some other puzzles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do herons fly overhead when a ground mist covers the downs?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do more long-tailed tits fly out of a bush than flew into it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do pied wagtails run in circles round lamp posts?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never counted birds in and out of bushes but I reckon I know the answer to the second one: by the time you notice a tit fly into a bush there&amp;#8217;s probably a few others in there already; and you watch them all fly out. Geraldine suggests the discrepancy is always one &amp;#8212; the lone anchor bird which discreetly reconnoitres the bush before giving the others the OK to proceed. So you see, the mystery is all about point of view.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for herons. When the downs are covered in mist Geraldine looks up more. Have you noticed, she added, the way wood-pigeons dive in and out of the mist, like a dolphin? Why do they do that? Lubrication, to stop their wings creaking!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5752121266/" title="Crowded nest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2365/5752121266_4af54dcacc_n.jpg" width="320" height="267" alt="Crowded nest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pied wagtails in our garden do run in circles but not around things and not right now, they&amp;#8217;re too busy feeding five hungry fledglings. I&amp;#8217;d assumed it was a courtship display. Geraldine had no definitive answer either. By now, the audience was involved: where do swifts sleep, and what happens to swallows in winter? The swifts fly up high in the evening and wake lower down in the morning, still on the wing. The swallows conglobulate together, by flying round and round, and then all in a heap throw themselves under water, and lye in the bed of a river.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dru read a haiku. Deborah Harvey read two poems from &lt;a href="http://www.indigodreamsbookshop.com/#/deborah-harvey/4552913959"&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The birds, it turns out, aren&amp;#8217;t missing, they&amp;#8217;re moulting. Low on energy after the nesting season and barely able to fly due to lack of feathers, they lie low, avoiding predators. In the summer of 2010 Geraldine watched a blackbird &amp;#8212; the secret blackbird &amp;#8212; go through this process, and now she retold the story, reading from her book. Dru signalled the part of the bird using a set of semaphore flags.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more poems, the final one acted out with a soft toy and a star.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a very fine book indeed. Dru has surpassed herself with the illustrations, which mix avian character studies and cartoons.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-05-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Owls, trains, turkeys and other friends of the RWA</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803013211/" title="Wild Turkey by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7141/6803013211_5e35ca7ed2_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Wild Turkey"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bird stands in judgement outside the main gallery at the &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/" title="Royal West of England Academy"&gt;Royal West of England Academy&lt;/a&gt;. The glass on the bar once contained bourbon whiskey &amp;#8212; look closely and you can see an empty Wild Turkey miniature.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turkey&amp;#8217;s by &lt;a href="http://filthyluker.org/"&gt;filthy luker&lt;/a&gt;. He works with pigeons too &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://filthyluker.org"&gt;&lt;img src="http://filthyluker.org/wp-content/gallery/manifestations/08pigeon_english_by_filthy_luker_UK.jpg" alt="Urban birds" width="600px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; and monsters!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3364983737/" title="Kraken invades RWA by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3574/3364983737_cd574805b1.jpg" width="500" height="399" alt="Kraken invades RWA"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now filthy luker is &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/whats-on/exhibitions/2012/01/exhibitions-filthy-luker/"&gt;artist in residence&lt;/a&gt; at the RWA. Also in residence at the RWA &amp;#8212; just outside, on the balcony, where those tentacles were &amp;#8212; is Damien Hirst&amp;#8217;s outsize collection box, Charity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803014231/" title="Charity by Damien by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7024/6803014231_6b6b6665a3.jpg" width="500" height="323" alt="Charity by Damien"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean to say: the RWA is Bristol&amp;#8217;s finest exhibition space and it puts on Bristol&amp;#8217;s finest exhibitions. The juxtaposition of classical architecture and &lt;a href="http://www.crimesofpassion.info/"&gt;urban art&lt;/a&gt; works well. Classical paintings fit in superbly too: last year&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz.html"&gt;Robert Lenkiewicz&lt;/a&gt; retrospective was stunning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It costs to get in though. It cost &amp;pound;4 last year and now it costs &amp;pound;5. That&amp;#8217;s quite a lot for a show you&amp;#8217;re not sure you&amp;#8217;ll like. Often the shows you&amp;#8217;re not sure you&amp;#8217;ll like are the ones worth seeing, and seeing again. That&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;m a &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/support-us/friends-patrons/"&gt;Friend&lt;/a&gt;. I work around the corner and can head over whenever the computer screen makes me dizzy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6800313715/" title="Friend of the RWA by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7013/6800313715_c6755919bf.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Friend of the RWA"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Lane made the bird on the card from scrap metal. I&amp;#8217;m not sure &lt;a href="http://is.gd/fNQRas"&gt;what type of bird&lt;/a&gt; it is. An archetypal mix of hornbill/stork/flamingo maybe? In the gallery behind the turkey are more birds, owls, by Ivor Abrahams, along with his interesting 2&amp;#189; dimensional sculptures and some tiresome garden things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803013435/" title="One of Ivor Abrahams' owls by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7009/6803013435_0ba8e39b05.jpg" width="461" height="500" alt="One of Ivor Abrahams' owls"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quite liked the show until I read what he had to say on the &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/local/views/uploads/documents/1327919367_20120130102927_17542851114f2671071a0fd6_93619033_592086275_8114811666.pdf"&gt;&amp;#8220;interpretation panel&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sculptures, collages, prints and drawings of Ivor Abrahams occupy a very particular place in British 20th Century art. No other artist has attempted to do what he has done &amp;#8212; to create an entirely new kind of polychrome sculpture which operates effectively between painting and sculpture &amp;#8212; and achieved such a catalogue of notable successes in the process. Essentially subversive, Abrahams has also gained a reputation for a wicked wit and a generally argumentative demeanour. Nothing is sacred, particularly the established names of the past. As he has admitted: &amp;#8220;I always enjoyed the pomposity of academic sculpture, the grandiosity and rhetoric. The edifying or inspirational nature of the art has always led me to treat it with the greatest of disrespect.&amp;#8221; That irreverence has fuelled his career, and helped him make of the sum of destructions a newly-constructed vision of his own work. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidshepherd.com"&gt;&lt;img width="600px" src="http://www.davidshepherd.com/davidshepherd-elephantsatamboseli.jpg" alt="Elephants at Amboseli, David Shepherd" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside, and by contrast, are a number of paintings and prints by David Shepherd. They aren&amp;#8217;t to my taste but they most certainly were when I was younger (the animal ones, not the trains and planes). I can&amp;#8217;t argue with &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/whats-on/exhibitions/2012/02/exhibitions-david-shepherd/"&gt;his attitude&lt;/a&gt; either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Shepherd paints every day of his life. Now aged eighty, the famed wildlife, aviation and steam train artist describes his life as &amp;#8216;a series of disasters&amp;#8217; &amp;#8212; David Shepherd&amp;#8217;s career has been shaped by serendipity. Rejected by the Slade School of Art, David planned to train as a bus driver. A chance encounter with artist Robin Goodwin resulted in a three-year apprenticeship &amp;#8212; a first for Goodwin, who revelled in the challenge, and a life-changing opportunity for Shepherd.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodwin taught Shepherd commercially as well as artistically. &amp;#8220;Throwing paint at the wall and &amp;#8216;expressing yourself&amp;#8217; doesn&amp;#8217;t pay the bills&amp;#8221;, taught Robin. &amp;#8220;Artists, like everyone else, have to work eight hours and more a day, seven days a week, to meet their responsibilities.&amp;#8221; These words have informed Shepherd&amp;#8217;s work, and he is now one of the UK&amp;#8217;s most financially rewarded artists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidshepherd.com"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.davidshepherd.com/davidshepherd-overtheforth.jpg" width="600px" alt="Over the Forth, David Shepherd"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-02-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owls-trains-turkeys-and-other-friends-of-the-rwa</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owls-trains-turkeys-and-other-friends-of-the-rwa</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>what is happening to the Assyrian reliefs?</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a gloomy day! In need of colour I decided to revisit the &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/wildlife-photographer-year"&gt;wildlife photography exhibition&lt;/a&gt; in my lunchbreak.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think there must be two wildlife photography exhibitions, they come round so frequently, but now I understand there&amp;#8217;s only one; it&amp;#8217;s just that it stays on display for so long. It stays popular too, with good reason. I wish they&amp;#8217;d print larger versions of the photos though.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.nhm.ac.uk/resources-www/visit-us/whats-on/temporary-exhibitions/swpy/2011/popup/024.jpg" alt="The assassin, by Steve Mills"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photos come with the tales of their capture. Here&amp;#8217;s how &lt;a href="http://www.nhm.ac.uk/visit-us/whats-on/temporary-exhibitions/wpy/photo.do?photo=2717&amp;amp;category=3&amp;amp;group=1"&gt;Joe Bunni snapped a polar bear&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;After three days on a small boat looking for polar bears in Repulse Bay, Nunavut, Canada, Joe got lucky. &amp;#8216;We cruised at a distance, so we didn&amp;#8217;t disturb the bear. Once we were sure it was relaxed with our presence, I slipped quietly into the water with just a mask and fins, attached to the boat by a rope.&amp;#8217; The polar bear now started to swim towards the boat. It didn&amp;#8217;t appear to notice Joe, and for 20 minutes he was able to take photographs from the water. But then the bear caught sight of its own reflection in the dome port and swam up to Joe. &amp;#8216;It&amp;#8217;s amazing when a huge, powerful animal comes beside you.&amp;#8217; It came so close that its nose touched the housing, startling it. The second after Joe took this shot, the bear reached out and touched the dome with its paw. Then it turned and swam away, leaving Joe with an unforgettable image - symbolic &amp;#8216;of the power and elegance of a wonderful creature struggling to survive in a fast-changing climate&amp;#8217;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.nhm.ac.uk/resources-www/visit-us/whats-on/temporary-exhibitions/swpy/2011/popup/034.jpg" alt="Polar Power"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unforgettable indeed! If I were Joe I&amp;#8217;d have prioritised my own survival and admired the power and elegance at a distance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5017113982/" title="Polar bear skeleton, Bristol Museum by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4103/5017113982_008ec3e479.jpg" width="500" height="354" alt="Polar bear skeleton, Bristol Museum"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bristol museum&amp;#8217;s own polar bear has disappeared, making way for a new lift which is being installed just beyond the room holding the Assyrian reliefs. The reliefs remain on display &amp;#8212; at least, I could see them today &amp;#8212; but they&amp;#8217;ve been separated, strapped, and mounted on shock absorbers to reduce the risk of damage from vibrations whilst the lift works go on.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6476527801/" title="what is happening to the Assyrian reliefs? by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7009/6476527801_d297c4ac48.jpg" width="391" height="500" alt="what is happening to the Assyrian reliefs?"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assembly of ancient stones and modern fixings looked like a conceptual artwork. I tried to imagine the history of the reliefs, how they&amp;#8217;d been quarried, manoeuvred, carved, lifted, shipped &amp;#8212; how 8 tons of granite had ended up here in Clifton.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-12-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/what-is-happening-to-the-assyrian-reliefs</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/what-is-happening-to-the-assyrian-reliefs</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol, Cycling City?</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6544368391/" title="BETT... by
Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img
src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7165/6544368391_abd9703d60_m.jpg" width="230"
height="240" alt="BETT..."&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6544368593/" title="ER BY BIKE
by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img
src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7018/6544368593_f8ab7f7ba5_m.jpg" width="205"
height="240" alt="ER BY BIKE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2008 Greater Bristol was chosen as England&amp;#8217;s first Cycling City and received &amp;pound;11m from the Department for Transport to transform cycling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helped bring about a strong cycling renaissance in the city. New dedicated on-road cycle lanes, new traffic-free routes, 3400 new cycle parking spaces, as well as cycling training and lots of other &amp;#8216;softer measures&amp;#8217; projects encouraged thousands of people to saddle up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/cycling"&gt;http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/cycling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and I got a mug out of it, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/philmciver/2299981707/" title="Bristol: Queen Square by Phil McIver, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3062/2299981707_b94952f0ec.jpg" width="500" height="351" alt="Bristol: Queen Square"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, though, I cycled from &lt;a href="http://www.screwfix.com/jsp/tradeCounter/tradeCounterDetailsPage.jsp?id=66"&gt;Screwfix in Bedminster&lt;/a&gt; to my office in Clifton. How pleasant to cycle through the middle of Queen Square on a track which, less than 20 years ago, was a dual carriageway. And how enjoyable to continue on across Broad Quay and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Centre_(Bristol)#1998_remodelling"&gt;the centre&lt;/a&gt;, which used to be one great roundabout. Pedestrians and cyclists get the best routes and the best views and that&amp;#8217;s how it should be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6550510109/" title="The Queen Square of the Future by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7013/6550510109_e4f31684ba.jpg" width="500" height="243" alt="The Queen Square of the Future"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle parking area where I work is secure, free (in marked contrast to the car parking spaces), and recently doubled in size. It fills up, every day, even now winter has set in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree: there &lt;strong&gt;has&lt;/strong&gt; been a cycling renaissance but I think it&amp;#8217;s down to a number of factors. Primarily, it&amp;#8217;s lower incomes and the rising price of motoring which is getting people on their bikes. A secondary effect adds momentum: the more cyclists there are, the more people accept cycling, and the more cyclists there will be. The fantastic success of British cycling may have something to do with it, judging by the number of swish road bikes which spin round the Downs every evening. The &lt;a href="http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/TravelAndTransport/Cycling/DG_190101"&gt;government cycle to work scheme&lt;/a&gt; is a fine deal, though I suspect the main beneficiaries are people like me who&amp;#8217;ve always cycled to work. And technological improvements, like &lt;a href="http://traumradfahren.wordpress.com/2011/12/07/commuter-bicycle-race/"&gt;electrically assisted bikes&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; I see plenty of cyclists who wouldn&amp;#8217;t be cycling without these.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling city? &amp;pound;11m! Transformation!?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It annoys me that &amp;#8220;special&amp;#8221; funding should be needed to provide for cyclists. Cycle parking spaces should be built anyway. Any transport planning should naturally prioritise pedestrians and cyclists. I don&amp;#8217;t think &amp;pound;11m paid for the reworking of Queen Square and Broad Quay, yet these schemes have benefited cyclists far more than a new bike route from the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JG7Lv1Ipfz8" title="worth watching for the muzak and subtitles alone"&gt;Farm pub to B&amp;amp;Q&lt;/a&gt;. I would like bike theft to be eliminated. I would like to see car-free approaches to secondary schools in the mornings and afternoons. Get kids used to commuting on foot and by bike and they&amp;#8217;ll continue as adults.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cycling City money wasn&amp;#8217;t wasted but I&amp;#8217;d say the initiative contributed little to the increase in cycling and it&amp;#8217;s foolish to claim or think otherwise. Yes, there are more cyclists on the roads but there need to be far, far more. How can we maintain the momentum? The little things help, let&amp;#8217;s keep doing them, but really it&amp;#8217;s down to government policy, personal responsibility and intelligent transport planning.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-11-16</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-cycling-city</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-cycling-city</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alan Turing centenary exhibition at the Arnolfini</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chanceprojects/5489369688/" title="19 timeline by neil cummings, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5215/5489369688_3784823d18.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="19 timeline"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents are born in 1931 making them centenarians in 2031, the year in which &amp;#8212; according to the &lt;a href="http://www.arnolfini.org.uk/whatson/exhibitions/details/928"&gt;Arnolfini timeline&lt;/a&gt;, a colour-coded sequence of data sprites recording the Arnolfini&amp;#8217;s presence from the Bristol riots of 1831 to the gallery&amp;#8217;s own centenary in 2061 &amp;#8212; in 2031, coincidentally, life expectancy has risen to 100. In 2031 the Arnolfini also marks Alan Turing&amp;#8217;s centenary with an exhibition, Almost Real: Composite Consciousness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6216774835/" title="Almost Real: Composite Consciousness, Alan Turing centenary exhibition by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6158/6216774835_db9d268d22.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Almost Real: Composite Consciousness, Alan Turing centenary exhibition"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This confuses me since &lt;a href="http://www.turingcentenary.eu/"&gt;2012 is Turing&amp;#8217;s centenary&lt;/a&gt;. He is born in 1912. In 1931 he studies mathematics at Cambridge.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling for more on the Almost Real exhibition, which I have yet to see, I &lt;a href="http://criticalpracticechelsea.org/wiki/index.php?title=Arnolfini_timeline#2050._Almost_Real:_Composite_Consciousness.2C_Alan_Turing_centenary_exhibition"&gt;discover&lt;/a&gt; a bug in the timeline. 2031 should read &lt;strong&gt;2050&lt;/strong&gt;, 100 years after Turing publishes &lt;a href="http://mind.oxfordjournals.org/content/LIX/236/433.full.pdf+html" title="I propose to consider the question, 'Can machines think?' -- Turing's classic paper is published in 1950"&gt;Computing Machinery and Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, the paper in which he considers the question &amp;#8220;Can machines think?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details on &lt;a href="http://criticalpracticechelsea.org/wiki/index.php?title=Arnolfini_timeline#2050._Almost_Real:_Composite_Consciousness.2C_Alan_Turing_centenary_exhibition"&gt;Almost Real&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Composite Consciousness is a gift, a gift that constitutes the social identity of those that reciprocate, and in that reciprocation, the gift is the interval (the difference) between those present, and those not. The time of the disinterested gift is the time of memory &amp;#8212; it shifts the present into the future, or recollects the past into the present.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chanceprojects/5489369988/" title="20 timeline by neil cummings, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5020/5489369988_d7fd717347.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="20 timeline"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/alan-turing-centenary-exhibition-at-the-arnolfini</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/alan-turing-centenary-exhibition-at-the-arnolfini</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol Half Marathon, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The half marathon I enjoyed most was the first one I ran, the Bath half, back in &amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not even sure, 12 years ago? I didn&amp;#8217;t know if I&amp;#8217;d be able to finish because I hadn&amp;#8217;t run the distance in training, so I started slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the race progressed I realised I &lt;strong&gt;would&lt;/strong&gt; finish, no problem, and I remember overtaking people in the second loop and sprinting the last stretch along Great Pulteney Street, crossing the line with a time of 1:42:15. Oh, I felt just great!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I&amp;#8217;ve run a few more half marathons and at each one I&amp;#8217;ve gone faster. At first I hacked chunks from my personal best but as time went on I was reduced to chipping away smaller gains. In 2003 I went below an hour and a half at Bristol, beating Steve Cram. In 2006 I returned to Bath and clocked &lt;a href="bath_half_2006.pdf"&gt;1:23:14&lt;/a&gt;. Wow! I didn&amp;#8217;t think I could better that but running the same event in 2007 I got down to 1:21:58 &amp;#8212; which meant running the first 9 miles at a speed of 6 minutes and 15 seconds per mile and then running the final 4 miles at the same speed, even though at every step every bit of me wanted it to end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day I retired from half marathons. I couldn&amp;#8217;t go any faster and I couldn&amp;#8217;t face up to going any slower and I hurt and I had had enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept running though. Cross country is my favourite, all weather, all terrain. I started going out with a group close to where I live, on Gower. Sand dunes, wooded tracks, marshland. Cefn Bryn from all faces. I joined a club in Bristol, where I work, threading through the alleyways and parkland of North Bristol. Then I hooked up with some friends for training runs on Wednesday lunchtimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gavinedmonds/5830288813/" title="GBR_1140 by Gavin Edmonds, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5152/5830288813_bf2b13d048_z.jpg" width="426" height="640" alt="GBR_1140"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, 6 March 2011, and friends from all of these groups were running the Bath half marathon. The weather was good. I was in fine form. As I said in an email to Andy:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m thinking my build-up for the Bath half has been pretty much perfect, except for my failure to enter, that is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andy went on to finish the race in a time of 1:21:51 &amp;#8212; fully half a second a mile faster than I&amp;#8217;d ever run. That did it! Later that week I signed up for the Bristol half marathon, to be run on September 11th 2011.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years since I&amp;#8217;ve been away, the Bristol half has become a huge event. I&amp;#8217;d been assigned a white number which meant I&amp;#8217;d be starting in the first section of the first wave. It still took me over 30 seconds to pass beneath the start line and I spent the first couple of miles dodging joggers with ipods and sharp elbowed veterans. Beneath the suspension bridge the race stretched out. I galloped along the portway. Soon after doubling back at Shirehampton I pulled alongside someone I knew.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Is that Neil?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Tom, How&amp;#8217;s it going?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Too damn fast. I&amp;#8217;m going too fast.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Nah, you&amp;#8217;re fine!&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shook my head. I &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt; going too fast but I couldn&amp;#8217;t slow down. Even though I was hurting and hadn&amp;#8217;t even gone halfway I let momentum take me past Neil and on to Spike Island. Already I wanted it over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route came back to the centre of town then cruelly swerved out again on an unwelcome tour of the sights. Great for spectators. Cobbles. Ramps. &lt;a href="http://www.seenoevilbristol.co.uk/"&gt;Grafitti&lt;/a&gt;. I was being overtaken. Falling away. Neil came smoothly past.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well done mate,&amp;#8221; I muttered.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;400m to go. At least I had space around me. Noone passed me in the final straight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pressed the button on my stop watch and collapsed, wiped out. I hurt and I knew I was going to hurt more tomorrow and the day after. There was Neil. I eased up on to my feet, started moving, slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6137800028/" title="1:22:14.94 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6076/6137800028_a469bae0a1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:22:14.94"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:22:14 my watch said.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the event has grown bigger they&amp;#8217;ve figured out how to organise it. You aren&amp;#8217;t allowed to pile-up round the finish line snatching goodie bags and hugging loved ones. They keep the exhausted, elated runners moving past a succession of hand-outs: space blanket, water, medal, banana, T-shirt, energy drink, leaflet, bag &amp;#8230; and after this personal awards ceremony you emerge light-headed into the sunshine in millenium square.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil ran 1:22:06, comfortably. For him, this was a training run: he&amp;#8217;s looking for a fast time in Stroud. My official time, &lt;a href="http://www.runbristol.com/SearchResults.aspx"&gt;online now&lt;/a&gt;, is 1:22:15. That&amp;#8217;s over a second a mile slower than I&amp;#8217;ve run before. I give in.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-09-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Statues on the move</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5790058076/" title="Please give generously by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2224/5790058076_27f7c7efe1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Please give generously"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not every day you see a 6.7m statue being lifted on to a balcony so this morning I happily sat in the sunshine to watch the installation of Damien Hirst&amp;#8217;s Charity at the RWA.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5790056980/" title="Unveiled by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5147/5790056980_babc3ac3a1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Unveiled"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First the tarpaulins were pulled off her. The main crane made a blind pass, registering the location of the plinth on the balcony, judging the required extension. Now they attached chains around her neck and at the base, padding the neck with blankets. The strapping which fastened her to the trailer was removed removed. Slowly slowly she rose from supporting timbers on the tailer. They lowered her to the gound and tilted her on to her feet. The foreman wore a golden hat. It all seemed calm and controlled. Clearances were small. The pavement stayed open.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5789654042/" title="Charity on her way up by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5149/5789654042_82ffd4dbe6.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Charity on her way up"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to BBC Bristol &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-bristol-13502198" title="BBC Bristol reports: Damien Hirst's 22ft Charity statue coming to Bristol"&gt;Charity will be here for a year&lt;/a&gt;, adding:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The RWA said Bristol-born Hirst has &amp;#8220;scuffed her appearance and burgled her charity box to highlight the erosion of society&amp;#8217;s values&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the big statue rose slowly into position, smaller sculptures left the building, pushed out on trailers and bundled into the back of a van. The David Backhouse exhibition had ended.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the end too for the Backhouse sculpture so recently installed in the RWA forecourt. &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-bristol-13593918"&gt;Vandals had succeeded&lt;/a&gt; in separating the two figures at the top of the sculpture from the one at the base. Today, the base figure was unbolted from her low plinth then lifted and strapped down on an open trailer where the other two, who had been wrapped in sacking and left on the floor outside the building, rejoined her. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5789502725/" title="Broken and on the way out by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3483/5789502725_b983ab4680.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Broken and on the way out"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-06-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/statues-on-the-move</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/statues-on-the-move</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Still Lives, Lenkiewicz, summarised</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5781189874/" title="Shrouded by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3033/5781189874_51379c43ec.jpg" width="500" height="452" alt="Shrouded"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bumped into Nick in the RWA gallery at lunch time. He happened to be there because he wanted to see the damage done to the David Backhouse sculpture at the front of the building, and then he&amp;#8217;d realised there was an exhibition on, and entry was free. So why not?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told Nick he was lucky, this was the final day of the Lenkiewicz exhibition. It seemed ironic that the publicity resulting from an act of vandalism should draw someone into a show which should have been more than capable of generating its own buzz.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve visited the show a number of times and I want to record my response now it&amp;#8217;s over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite stunning. It has been a privilege to enjoy the work of one person displayed with the space and scale it deserves. Lenkiewicz&amp;#8217;s skill as a painter is breathtaking. He paints people, fabrics, ghosts, lemons, interiors, mirrors, memento mori. He does colour. He arranges. He goes large. He paints details.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/image-gallery/miscellaneous/1994-retrospective-birmingham-nec/mr-earl-funeral-director-and-family-co"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/files/images/15ROL_P75S.jpg" width="500px" alt="Mr Earl, funeral director, and family, in coffin warehouse"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The huge canvases in the main halls which arrange vagrants, the elderly, the disabled, in classical tableaux; these were my favourites at first. I especially like the burial of John Kynance and the funeral director&amp;#8217;s family group portrait posed in the coffin warehouse. I tend to skip through the next room, the one where the artist paints himself with naked women draped around him. Increasingly I dwell in the final room, the one with the solo portraits. Here characters like Albert Ernest Fisher, known as &amp;#8220;The Bishop&amp;#8221;, who appear in various roles elsewhere in the exhibition, figure simply as themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/image-gallery/themed-projects/project-20-addictive-behaviour/robbie"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/files/images/20ROL_Robbie.jpg" width="500px" alt="Robbie, by Robert Lenkiewicz"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-05-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-lenkiewicz-summarised</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-lenkiewicz-summarised</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/the-burial-of-john-kynance.jpg" alt="The Burial of John Kynance"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Pike; Death; Doc; Terence P. D. Stott aka &amp;#8216;Blue&amp;#8217;; James Foster aka &amp;#8216;Harmonica Jim&amp;#8217;; Taff; Barney; Victor Jonson/alias/James Howard aka &amp;#8216;Cockney Jim&amp;#8217;; Cyril Hocking aka &amp;#8216;Mephistopheles&amp;#8217;; Wee John; Ghost of Diogenes; and Edwin MacKenzie, aka Diogenes, attend the Burial of John Kynance in a painting by Robert Lenkiewicz currently on display in an &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/currexh.htm" title="Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz, RWA Bristol"&gt;exhibition&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the Royal West of England Academy, Bristol.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene is viewed from the coffin of the recently deceased John Kynance. Diogenes features twice, once as his ghost and once as himself. You&amp;#8217;ll find him elsewhere in the exhibition too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/currexh.htm" title="Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz, RWA Bristol"&gt;Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz&lt;/a&gt;, is a stunning exhibition. The RWA galleries are spacious, light and elegant &amp;#8212; well suited to displaying Lenkiewicz&amp;#8217;s masterful paintings. I will revisit this show many times over the next few weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Two and a bit pencils later</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/sketching-skeletons-at-bristol-museum.html" title="Sketching skeletons at Bristol Museum"&gt;Six months ago I decided&lt;/a&gt; to visit Bristol Museum on Wednesday evenings and draw interesting things until I got to the end of my sketchbook. Two and a half pencils and 51 pictures later, I&amp;#8217;m done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5474708308/" title="Two and a bit pencils later by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5059/5474708308_1297ba0e07.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Two and a bit pencils later" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ve made any great progress as an artist but I&amp;#8217;m happy at least to get my eye back in. Besides, in my day job, as a computer programmer, it&amp;#8217;s hard to truly finish anything, so it&amp;#8217;s good to &amp;#8212; well &amp;#8212; finish something.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="400" height="300"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2F&amp;set_id=72157624789595765&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=71649"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=71649" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2F&amp;set_id=72157624789595765&amp;jump_to=" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My appreciation of the museum has grown. I&amp;#8217;ve had time to read labels and walk through those quiet upper rooms filled with silverware and crockery. I&amp;#8217;ve noticed small details in familiar paintings. I can point out the scars in the stonework caused by war-time bomb damage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late opening on Wednesdays may be a recent idea but it&amp;#8217;s proved a rapid success. When I first started coming it seemed like I had the place to myself. Every so often a gallery attendant would drift by, but that was it. Now, though, I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who turns up to sketch, and on most Wednesdays it seems there&amp;#8217;s an event going on: &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/plinth-project-by-rob.html"&gt;statues have been unveiled&lt;/a&gt;, presentations made, films shown; the year of the rabbit kicked off; exhibitions have changed; and one evening the main hall was packed with dancing brownies and balloon-filled bin-liners were emptied on them from the first floor gallery. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-02-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/two-and-a-bit-pencils-later</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/two-and-a-bit-pencils-later</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>A night at the museum, Bristol style</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5391930761/" title="Horace Brodsky, by Gaudier-Brzeska, Bristol museum by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5137/5391930761_e413da3b83_z.jpg" width="469" height="640" alt="Horace Brodsky, by Gaudier-Brzeska, Bristol museum" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a perspex chair on the upper gallery by this sculpture. It&amp;#8217;s for the museum staff, obviously, but I didn&amp;#8217;t think they&amp;#8217;d mind me using it. I pulled it into position, sat down and began sketching.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;d arrived, half-past five-ish, the museum had been quiet. Not empty, but quiet. I knew a bit about the sculptor, Gaudier-Brezska, but who was his subject, Horace Brodsky? Certainly, he looked remarkable. I could hear activity in the entrance hall below, muted voices, footsteps. I drew in the gallery&amp;#8217;s stone rail, tracing it back to the bronze musicians and the bust of Henry Irving. One day I should try and draw those wonderful chandeliers properly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;d finished I walked down the stairs towards the British wildlife gallery. The noise levels had increased. The rear hall was packed out. Positive, laidback, funky, exciting, spectacular actually.  All the chairs were occupied, people were sitting on the floor and stairs, leaning on gallery rails. On the screen was the promo video for &lt;a href="http://mshed.org"&gt;M Shed&lt;/a&gt;, which will open &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/launching-cabot-circus.html"&gt;at last&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; in 2011.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title="YouTube video player" class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="560" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/DRb2_2P_lUI" frameborder="0" allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out, the main event wasn&amp;#8217;t about M Shed, it was about the work done digitising the South West&amp;#8217;s film archive followed by a screening of some of the archive&amp;#8217;s contents. It was the first of &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/ccm/content/Leisure-Culture/Museums-Galleries/late-night-opening-at-bristol-museum---art-gallery-.en"&gt;a series&lt;/a&gt; to be held on the last Wednesday of the month for next few months. I watched for a while. They were showing some archive footage of trams gliding around the centre Bristol, accompanied by piano music. Next up, a street party held to celebrate the coronation.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-01-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-night-at-the-museum-bristol-style</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-night-at-the-museum-bristol-style</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Curious crow, cantankerous goose, life saving Puffin</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to be at the zoo education centre last night for the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolzoo.org.uk/avon-gorge-and-downs-events" title="Bristol Zoo event listings"&gt;launch&lt;/a&gt; of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt;. The evening included readings from the book, mince pies, soft toys, photography, clippings from the Bristol Evening Post, poetry, tea, dramatic reconstructions, slide shows, damson vodka. Yes, you had to be there.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful book, beautifully observed and exquisitely illustrated. For example, here&amp;#8217;s Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s picture of the fox which Geraldine Taylor saw on Zoo Banks, head back, catching hailstones in its mouth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2718/4293238314_17bce23898.jpg" alt="Fox and hailstones"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geraldine Taylor produced a stuffed goose, prompting us to remember &lt;a href="http://www.thisisbristol.co.uk/news/Goose-terrorised-drinkers-remembered/article-2554802-detail/article.html"&gt;Sylvester, Bristol harbour&amp;#8217;s most famous resident&lt;/a&gt;. When Sylvester died on the final day of this year&amp;#8217;s harbour festival the news made the front page of the Bristol Evening Post. Mr Rankin, who runs Number Seven Boat Trips, paid this handsome tribute:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;He lived a full and eventful life attacking people outside various pubs &amp;#8230; We all loved him dearly but he had a big personality and pecked me in all sorts of places. We&amp;#8217;re going to make a coffin and he is going to be buried with full military honours.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sylvester did indeed get a maritime send off. He was ferried from the swan feeding station at Welsh Back down to the Ostrich pub, where he was buried.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a break for refreshments Keith Taylor presented a slide show about pioneering wildlife photographers, the Kearton brothers. I think that&amp;#8217;s Richard Kearton supporting Cherry Kearton for a hedge nest shot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam349.jpg" alt="How to photograph a nest in a hedge"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There they are again, up a tree.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam343.jpg" alt="Photographing a nest in a tree"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick web search found the complete text of their book &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/index.html" title="With Nature and a Camera"&gt;With Nature and a Camera&lt;/a&gt; online at the Glasgow Digital Library. Like everything I encountered last night it&amp;#8217;s packed with character. The photos of birds nesting on the cliffs of St Kilda are stunning, all the more so when you see the lengths they took to get them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0213.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam091.jpg" alt="Gannet and young" style="align:top"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1102.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam336.jpg" alt="Method of descending a cliff" style="align:top"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about this for a &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0312.htm"&gt;bird-related escape&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years ago a girl, whilst watching the men collect eggs on the Doon, had her petticoats ballooned by a sudden squall of wind, and was lifted clean over the cliff. She fell one hundred and eighty feet without a break, and alighted on a ledge which was covered with earth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cragsmen descended to pick up what they very naturally supposed to be the dead body of the poor child, but were surprised to find that she was still alive. Her head had entered a large Puffin burrow, and the force of the blow been expended upon her shoulders. This undoubtedly saved her, and although she hung a whole week between life and death in an unconscious condition, she ultimately made a complete recovery, and was a fine buxom lassie at the time of our visit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-12-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Plinth Project, by Rob</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://robertmanners.wordpress.com" title="Plinth, under construction"&gt;&lt;img src="http://robertmanners.files.wordpress.com/2010/08/the-plinth.jpg" alt="Vacant plinth, ready for installation"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the museum at 17:30 as usual. There was Rob in the entrance foyer, arranging chairs and looking rather hassled. I said hello but he obviously didn&amp;#8217;t have time so I went upstairs and drew some stuffed birds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5166348596/" title="Puffins by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1394/5166348596_25a3ec8598.jpg" width="361" height="500" alt="Puffins" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All seemed under control when I came back downstairs so I said hello again. The new sculpture on the &lt;a href="http://www.containerarts.org/plinth/"&gt;plinth&lt;/a&gt;: that was his. Congratulations, I said. Wow! When&amp;#8217;s it being unveiled? Well, now, he said. Stop for a drink.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up a leaflet. The plinth sculpture is called &amp;#8220;Under Construction Forever&amp;#8221;. If you visit &lt;a href="http://robertmanners.wordpress.com"&gt;http://robertmanners.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;#8217;ll see it taking shape &amp;#8212; under construction. I wonder if he&amp;#8217;ll keep working on it, now it&amp;#8217;s installed? I hadn&amp;#8217;t realised Rob was &lt;a href="http://www.robertmanners.co.uk" title="Robert Manners website"&gt;Robert Manners&lt;/a&gt;, artist and curator, and I hadn&amp;#8217;t seen his work in a while. It&amp;#8217;s superb.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertmanners.co.uk/site/index.php?/paintings/20089/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.robertmanners.co.uk/site/files/gimgs/9_ssr-s3web.jpg" alt="SSR S3 Acrylic and metal on canvas and wood 31x40cm 2010"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-11-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/plinth-project-by-rob</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/plinth-project-by-rob</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>A gorilla called Alfred</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day in London my train pulled into Temple Meads a few minutes early. I had time, just. A vampire and a zombie lurked in the trees fringing Queen Square. Heading up Park Street, a male streaker ran alongside me, hopping off the pavement and into the road to overtake pedestrians. I pulled away from him at the triangle, parked my bike at the office, swapped the laptop for a sketchbook.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late opening at the city museum is one of Bristol&amp;#8217;s best kept secrets. Turn up after 5 on a Wednesday and it&amp;#8217;ll be you, a few staff, and the empty galleries. This evening, though, the building was teeming with brownies. They were dancersizing in the rear hall. Thump went the speakers. Flash went the lights. I walked around them and up the stairs, past the sculpture of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5078330815"&gt;Eve at the fountain&lt;/a&gt;, past the case of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5078923064"&gt;Chinese ceramic horses&lt;/a&gt;, into the world wildlife gallery.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5100360372/" title="Western Lowland Gorilla (Alfred) by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1166/5100360372_e3845f7dd4_z.jpg" width="421" height="640" alt="Western Lowland Gorilla (Alfred)" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled a child-sized chair from the kids&amp;#8217; play area and drew it up in front of the Western Lowland Gorilla. I started sketching. Three brownies skittered past, quietening when they saw me. That&amp;#8217;s a good drawing, one said. The bright lights behind the case. The muted thudding of the disco music.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5102493516/" title="Elephants, this way by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4089/5102493516_1640318909_m.jpg" width="179" height="240" alt="Elephants, this way" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign for the Zoo on the triangle shows an elephant but there hasn&amp;#8217;t been an elephant there since &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/bristol/content/news/2002/09/12/news2/wendy.shtml"&gt;Wendy&lt;/a&gt; died, and there&amp;#8217;ll never be another. Gorillas, though, are very much present. They have their own island fitted out with  a gorilla-sized climbing frame. The silent specimen in the case is &amp;#8212; &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8212; Bristol&amp;#8217;s original gorilla, &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/ccm/content/Leisure-Culture/Museums-Galleries/collections---natural-history-department---city-museum-&amp;amp;-art-gallery.en?page=2"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;#8220;an international animal star &amp;#8230; an icon for the city through times of peace and war. His powerful persona and image have been etched on the collective memory of the city and have survived long after his death&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, powerful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alfred was regularly taken on walks round the zoo at the end of a collar and chain, often wearing a woollen jumper. He was said to dislike bearded men, double decker buses and aeroplanes. He died in 1948 after suffering from tuberculosis for over a year. He was then stuffed and displayed in the museum. In 1956 some &lt;a href="http://www.thisisbristol.co.uk/news/Theft-just-jolly-student-ape/article-1884224-detail/article.html"&gt;students stole him as a rag week stunt&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5100362244/" title="Western Lowland Gorilla (Alfred) by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1145/5100362244_fc40d3ec4d_z.jpg" width="466" height="640" alt="Western Lowland Gorilla (Alfred)" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gallery attendant walked round. No, I didn&amp;#8217;t have to go yet. She shut one of the doors so it would be easier for her to close up later, and when she came around again, a few minutes later, I did have to go. The party was still in full swing. I walked around the gallery. Brownie helpers looked down on the action. Leaning against the railing were black bin liners filled with balloons.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-10-20</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-gorilla-called-alfred</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-gorilla-called-alfred</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sketching skeletons at Bristol Museum</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Skeletons have interesting lines, corners and shadows, which is why I like drawing them. Here&amp;#8217;s a sketch of the Moa skeleton at Bristol museum, which you&amp;#8217;ll find just around the corner from the &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/england/7440296.stm"&gt;spiky plant-eating scelidosaurus&lt;/a&gt; and opposite the camarasaurus leg. (Courtesy of the BBC, here&amp;#8217;s a &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/bristol/content/panoramas/museum3_360.shtml"&gt;panorama&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4929241864/" title="Moa skeleton at Bristol museum by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4137/4929241864_17164a1ce5_z.jpg" width="454" height="640" alt="Moa skeleton at Bristol museum" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, no wings! Moas are &amp;#8212; were &amp;#8212; wingless, unlike other &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ratite"&gt;ratites&lt;/a&gt;, other birds even, but what really impressed me about this specimen were its powerful legs and hips, and its chunky feet &amp;#8212; which unfortunately stretched down below the bottom of my sketch book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attendant told me I was lucky, an hour ago the gallery was full of noisy kids, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to sit there and draw. I nodded. Long day? I thought. Where better for kids to go on a wet day at the end of the summer holidays? A few weeks ago I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to sit there and draw either, not after 5pm. Late opening on Wednesdays is a &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/ccm/content/press-releases/2010/jul/late-night-opening-at-city-museum---art-gallery.en"&gt;recent innovation&lt;/a&gt;. And a year ago I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to get into the museum without &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/banksy-vs-bristol-museum.html"&gt;queuing for three hours first&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I intend to fill my new sketch book, get my eye back in. Wednesdays are good. I&amp;#8217;ve started now. Here&amp;#8217;s a line drawing of The Wrestler, by Henri Gaudier-Brzeska, which reminds me of &lt;a href="http://www.kettlesyard.co.uk"&gt;Kettle&amp;#8217;s Yard&lt;/a&gt;. Wonderful sculpture, poor picture. I&amp;#8217;m working on it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4927073230/" title="The Wrestler, Henri Gaudier-Brzeska by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4120/4927073230_2a071fa6f2_b.jpg" width="510" height="766" alt="The Wrestler, Henri Gaudier-Brzeska" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-08-25</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/sketching-skeletons-at-bristol-museum</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/sketching-skeletons-at-bristol-museum</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
