<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Burrington Blaster, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It helps to have run the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/tach-races/"&gt;TACH races&lt;/a&gt; before, so you can gauge your effort for what&amp;#8217;s coming. I &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk"&gt;have run the Burrington Blaster previously&lt;/a&gt;, but just the once, three years ago. From memory, we were facing a never-ending uphill followed by a treacherous downhill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either my recollections were faulty or we&amp;#8217;d gone the wrong way, because, after an initial climb the route levelled then dipped. We were running full tilt downhill when, in my head, we should have been grinding uphill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was relieved when the course did turn upwards. My legs were ready. We shook off a few runners who&amp;#8217;d been seduced by the fast start. Now I ran with three training partners: Andy, Neil, Paul. How many times have we climbed Nightingale Valley together, only to find ourselves shoulder to shoulder in a race? Paul set the pace. I expected Andy to pull away &amp;#8212; he&amp;#8217;s been flying recently &amp;#8212; but eventually it was me who picked up the pace, passing Paul as the climb opened out from the woods and on to the top of the beacon.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time out this exposed section had been windy, wet and boggy. Today found the going still and dry. My chance was now! Convinced longer legs would catch me I hurled myself at the first open downhill, launching off ridges, sliding on bare earth, using the grassy verge to decelerate as needed. I knew my pursuers had me in view and didn&amp;#8217;t want them to think they were closing in. Now the patch narrowed and swerved though bracken, gorse, brambles, still downhill. Room for one only: noone could pass.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on my own anyway. No sight of anyone ahead. No sound of anyone behind &amp;#8212; even if you cannot hear a chaser directly, you can hear the spectators cheering them, or marshals guiding them. Of course you would never look back!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final woodland descent, I took carefully. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk"&gt;Three years ago&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#8217;d lost fourth place slipping and falling, and had considered myself lucky not to get hurt.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I finished unscathed, 4th overall and 1st veteran, with a time of 35:36.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/596847138/embed/f460412a76bccd67e8d4bc77103d289510c56a7f'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner, Chris McMillan, completed the course in a blistering time of 32:33, nearly two minutes clear of the next runner.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-06-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/burrington-blaster-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/burrington-blaster-2016</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tyntesfield 10, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;So unless the weather picks up a lot I&amp;#8217;m probably not going to spectate. Enjoy the rain!&amp;#8221; Andy emailed, despite the fact Hannah, his wife, would be running.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet again the event defied the forecast. Heavy showers had blown themselves out during the day. The sun shone. Tyntesfield&amp;#8217;s stone work gleamed. The lawns sparkled.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of laps of the lower meadow and formal gardens the race leaders had a substantial gap. From here, the course plays hide-and-seek through woods and rough pasture, and I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be seeing them until the finish. I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be looking back either, I&amp;#8217;d be playing my part in a racing allegiance of four:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     the tall veteran from Weston AC
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Bristol and West, wearing tights
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a North Somerset runner
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     me, the Southville second-claimer
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/27209354974/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Good gate work"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7595/27209354974_77d9158dac_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Good gate work"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
   &lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/27209958713/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Thanks for the support"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7642/27209958713_01bf73e786_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Thanks for the support"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bristol and West led us through the woods, ducking, skipping, dodging and sliding. A wrong turn was quickly corrected. He made an error trying to squeeze between gate and fence, failing to spot the barbed wire. That hurt! Now we skirted the furrowed side of a planted field.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weston charged into the downhill only to fall heavily on the wet mud. He was OK, he was up again. I dropped to the back of the group and chose my route carefully. North Somerset had built a clear lead.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short set of steps the course returns to a tarmaced road for the final section. There&amp;#8217;s an uphill, neither steep nor extended, but brutal after 6 miles of multi-terrain racing. I caught and passed Bristol and West and Weston.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/27211942965/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Don&amp;#x27;t look back"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7348/27211942965_69f31e1e12_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Don&amp;#x27;t look back"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see the finish line. Andy was there, with Sam and James. Giles with his boys too. They were cheering me on! I had better support but Bristol and West had a better sprint. He stormed past me to take 9th in the race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/26606516263/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Race for the line"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7529/26606516263_4e8c21f9f5_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Race for the line"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/27211933495/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Mugged by a man in tights"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7444/27211933495_c27ff8b6f0_z.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="Mugged by a man in tights"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came 10th overall with a time of 40:34, a little slower than last year. I was second veteran (behind Keiron Summers) and first MV50.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special mention to Harry Allen, a young runner who has been training with Southville &amp;#8212; let&amp;#8217;s hope he signs up! &amp;#8212; and who won the race in a time of 37:34, in the face of some very strong competition.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/580805263/embed/7386e7f4cd189360cd56eefd1f1ca0840265b0af'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rich Kenington, Dermot McCann and Phil Murray for the photographs
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tyntesfield-10-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tyntesfield-10-2016</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Wrington Woodland run, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is my fourth year of running the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/tach-races/"&gt;Tach summer series&lt;/a&gt;, four multi-terrain events held on Thursday evenings in May through to July. These races play to my strengths &amp;#8212; hills, uneven footing, twists and turns; long enough to require level-headed pacing, short enough to race the whole way. And when you look up, the scenery is spectacular.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wrington run starts with the steadiest of climbs on a woodland track. The leaders accelerated up the gradient and were soon out of sight. Some quality runners there, but did they realise how long this climb was, and how much tougher the following climb would be? Their enthusiasm carried me and I picked up my own pace.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In wetter weather there&amp;#8217;d be a section of energy-sapping clay towards the top. After an unusually dry spring, we danced past any remaining mud on the course. I had picked off Matt and Paul by now. I could see Mark Ducker, Southville captain, not so far ahead.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downhill transitions from footpath to farm track to tarmac. Then there&amp;#8217;s a level section along Ropers Lane. I was running just behind Keiron Summers and just ahead of Ben Anderson. We turned up Bullhouse Lane, a rocky path littered with leaf mould, branches and loose rocks. I passed Keiron but he was having none of it. The route swerved, the gradient sharpened.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on tarmac again, along the top of Wrington Hill. Views of the Severn Estuary. Ben passed me. The bluebells glowed in the evening sunlight. I could still see Mark.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught and passed Ben when the road surface deteriorated. Keiron was still in range. We hurtled down the final woodland descent, shooting across the narrow bridge, over the stile, then stumble-running across the meadow to the line. I finished 4th with a personal course record of 37:52.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/27152782793/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Finish, Wrington Woodland 2016"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7440/27152782793_08d0af6d05.jpg" width="333" height="500" alt="Finish, Wrington Woodland 2016"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/27152781383/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Wrington Woodland 2016, the finish"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7285/27152781383_74153c20bf.jpg" width="332" height="500" alt="Wrington Woodland 2016, the finish"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to John Cooper for the photos
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-05-05</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-run-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-run-2016</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Rise and Fall of Trail Running</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;During the Christmas break I went on a long, slow run from home, through Stembridge to Llanmadoc, heading back via Burry. The weather was unseasonably mild. After several days of rain, the going was heavy. Cresting Llanmadoc hill, 4 miles in, after a steep, slippery climb, the view opened out: far ahead, Black Mountain and the Brecon Beacons, the salt marsh to my left, its maze of waterways reflecting the pale light; then Whitford Sands, the green smudge of pine trees, the cast-iron lighthouse pinned against the Loughor estuary. The glow that comes with exercising outside spread through my body. Not long ago I had been picking my way through the marshy lowland and now I was up here. I had earned my view of this landscape. Covered in mud, I was part of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="The award winning Stormy Castle" href="https://www.architecture.com/StirlingPrize/Awards2014/Wales/StormyCastle.aspx"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/stormy-castle.jpg" alt="Stormy Castle"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahead of me stood an isolated building, plate glass windows, granite walls, rusting iron, concrete. My route skirted the perimeter joining the track which provided vehicle access. &lt;a href="https://www.architecture.com/StirlingPrize/Awards2014/Wales/StormyCastle.aspx"&gt;Stormy Castle&lt;/a&gt;, the nameplate read, gold on slate. Separate from the main building was what looked like a shed. Originally for livestock maybe? This too had grey stone walls; inset in the north wall was a floor-to-ceiling window. Looking in, I saw, placed in front of the window, a treadmill. Whoever inhabits Stormy Castle enjoys a gym with a view.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madness, I thought. Why run on the spot in this fish tank when you could be outside? Don&amp;#8217;t peer at the view, engage with it!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/heatheronhertravels/2479530671/in/photostream/" title="Abbots Pool, Bristol, Lake, Pond,"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3008/2479530671_55f30d3244_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Abbots Pool, Bristol, Lake, Pond,"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next week, back at work again in Bristol, I went on my regular long run, the &lt;a href="https://www.strava.com/activities/388964204"&gt;Abbots Pool Loop&lt;/a&gt;. St Mary Redcliffe&amp;#8217;s bell rang seven times as I passed through Queen Square. Usually I&amp;#8217;d hook up with one or more running friends here. Today, on a cloudy morning, 80 minutes before sunrise, I was on my own. I had no head torch. I ran through Millenium Square and along the harbour, negotiating steps and bridges to cross the harbour and river at Cumberland Basin. Soon I would be out of the city. My feet slipped as I left the access road to Ashton Court, the point where trail began. Road shoes which had been ideal for the pavements so far were now a liability. To my right I could just see the dark silhouettes of the red deer herd at rest. I could smell their damp, musky smell. At the northern boundary of the estate I crossed Beggars Bush Lane to continue along the farm track opposite.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uneven ground, downhill, too fast, a cross-slope. My left foot slid underneath me and I instantly knew I could not recover, and that the stony ground was going to hurt when I struck it. In those few airborne milliseconds I also had time to reflect this was a bad place for this to happen: on my own, without a phone, about as far from civilisation as you can get by running 40 minutes from the city centre. I fell forwards full length, somehow turning in the air to take the impact on my left elbow and the back of my shoulder. The mud which precipitated my fall also mitigated its effects. I slid rather than scraped. Head and face untouched. Wrists and hands OK. Legs fine. Elbow hurting and bloody, but that was the worst of it. I&amp;#8217;d been lucky.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I&amp;#8217;m not going to run on a treadmill, not even when it&amp;#8217;s dark and muddy. Especially not when it&amp;#8217;s dark and muddy. I&amp;#8217;ve tried head torches and they spoil my night vision. Have you run past Abbots Pool at dawn? Have you splashed through puddles on the towpath as the sun rises to colour in the Avon Gorge? You should. But I should be more careful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/388964204/embed/0903f50418446bf277f6e9531f55638a30c3a6ea'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.heatheronhertravels.com/"&gt;Heather Cowper&lt;/a&gt; for the photo of Abbots Pool, as seen in daylight, on a dry day.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-01-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rise-and-fall-of-trail-running</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rise-and-fall-of-trail-running</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>One week, three races</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I DNF the Cardiff half marathon. This year I went one worse and DNS the Swansea half. Consequently I was determined to turn up in good shape to complete this year&amp;#8217;s Cardiff half.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racing the week before probably wasn&amp;#8217;t a great idea &amp;#8230; but the race happened to be a short one and close to home &amp;#8230; and the weather was perfect &amp;#8230; and I hadn&amp;#8217;t raced in a while &amp;#8230; and Alex didn&amp;#8217;t have a rugby game and &amp;#8230; well, I went! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Llandmadoc is the first fixture of the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk"&gt;West Glamorgan cross country league&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s four and a half miles, out along a woodland trail then back on the beach. I tried to run within myself on the outward section and fell in with Peter Osborne, another V50 who I&amp;#8217;ve battled with on several occasions. He upped the pace as we hit the sloping sand around the point and then he was gone. Coming back along the beach in the blazing sun, there was a gap of 50m to the next group of runners &amp;#8212; a gap I reduced but never closed. Despite my conservative start, when we went through the wet sand I felt as energetic as one of the many stranded jellyfish which littered the course. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href="http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=147384&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Llanmadoc&amp;amp;date=27-Sep-15"&gt;finished 19th in a time of 28:32&lt;/a&gt;, officially first in my category but second really since Peter beat me and he&amp;#8217;s an age band up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21803789231/in/photostream/" title="Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5722/21803789231_138ac20159_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I avoided the track training session with Bristol and West on Monday evening &amp;#8212; the same session, last year, had been one too many. If I&amp;#8217;d had doubts about running the cross country race just a week before the half marathon, my main target for the year, then I had real concerns about testing myself at the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolandwestac.org/aztec-west-fast-5k/"&gt;Aztec West 5K&lt;/a&gt; on the Tuesday. I felt I was running well and knew a PB was possible on the fast Aztec West course, but did I want to know just how well I was running? A slow time would have rocked my confidence before Sunday&amp;#8217;s longer race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I went. As for times, I had no idea during the race because I forgot my watch. In contrast to Llanmadoc, my legs felt strong, decidedly sprightly in fact. I settled in with Will Smith and Paul Deaton, friends from Southville Running Club, and we barreled round the three lap course, overtaking some very decent runners who&amp;#8217;d started more quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21875414812/in/photostream/" title="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5816/21875414812_10a39d89f2_z.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21264629634/in/photostream/" title="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/569/21264629634_b53ab1d8aa_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will accelerated with 200m to go, attacking the next three runners, and Paul went with him. I let them go. After the final sharp left, Paul faded, enough encouragement for me to sprint past him. When the &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=146231&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Sep-15"&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; were announced I discovered I&amp;#8217;d won the V50 category with a PB of 17:22.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-footer="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21861865806/in/photostream/" title="Aztec West 5K. Charge for the line"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/728/21861865806_aa925a0096_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Charge for the line"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Cardiff. The race is bigger than ever &amp;#8212; twenty two thousand entrants in 2015. Despite this, it was straightforward getting to the start line warmed up and ready. The elite athletes (including me!) have their own baggage drop round the back of the castle in Bute Park. From there, it&amp;#8217;s a short stroll to the right start pen. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/406748447/embed/9e8c528271c129e91657b724a243c43d982c9342'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t think I set off too quickly but my 10K time was 37:10, on target for a 78:30 finish. I guess my legs were still dialled into my 5K pace. Ifan had set out even more quickly, but I caught him around the half way point. In a half marathon I usually feel a glow during the middle of the event; the sensation that I&amp;#8217;m going fast, but at a sustainable tempo. This time, the sensation never came. I wasn&amp;#8217;t glowing, I was aching. Enduring. Maintaining a steady pace seemed impossible and I found myself repeatedly dropping then being passed by the same group of runners. Why couldn&amp;#8217;t we team up and work together? I went through 10 miles in 1:00:25, still on course for a personal best but hurting badly. Ifan went past me again at around mile 11. I didn&amp;#8217;t even try and go with him. My muscles were sore, my feet were sore. I knew I&amp;#8217;d complete the course but I was no longer shooting for a personal best; I just wanted to finish without losing too much time. Actually, I just wanted to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the final turn I realised that 80 minutes was still on and managed to sprint for the line. My time, 79:43, was just 7 seconds off my PB.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Swansea half, aftermath</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014"&gt;Clocking a sub-80 half marathon at Swansea&lt;/a&gt; was my finest running performance in 2014. Things were bound to cool off after that.  Just four days later I showed up for the Purdown Pursuit, the final event of the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Tach summer series&lt;/a&gt;. The race started late and required re-routing; it was a sweltering evening and there&amp;#8217;d been a fire on the course. I took the downhill sections cautiously on sore legs but still managed &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=PP_result14.inc"&gt;4th place with a time of 42.39&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks later I finished 5th at the Blaise Blazer mob match. It&amp;#8217;s one of my favourite races and I set a personal best for the course of &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=106696&amp;amp;event=4MMT&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=4-Aug-14"&gt;23.51&lt;/a&gt;, picking runners off steadily in the final stages then holding on in the final sprint from the top of the steps to the folly. Southville RC put on a spirited defence of the team prize we&amp;#8217;d won the year before and, once the results had been counted and checked, to our surprise, it was announced we&amp;#8217;d retained the trophy. Later that evening after a recount the results were corrected; Westbury Harriers had, in fact, wrested the coveted Blazer Cup from our grasp.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mistake was not resting up over the summer. I wanted to go under 80 minutes for a second time at the Cardiff half marathon, a far more established and prestigious event than the one I&amp;#8217;d run in Swansea, and one at which friends from both Bristol and South Wales would compete. On the Monday before the race I tweaked my hamstring towards the end of a track session with Bristol &amp;amp; West at Whitehall. Not good. During the remainder of the week I rested before lining up on Sunday in Cardiff ready to race. I stormed the first mile in 5:40, hit a similar pace for the second, and then felt the injury ping. I pulled up and walked along the pavement, assessing the damage. I figured I could at least jog around the barrage to the Senedd but I couldn&amp;#8217;t. Instead I ended up limping from Pennarth to the centre, reaching the baggage collection around the time I should have been finishing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21815444008/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Masters XC 2015 by Alex Williams"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/644/21815444008_6cf2fe1c90_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Masters XC 2015 by Alex Williams"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t race again until the combined Welsh Inter-regional and Welsh Masters cross country championships. This is a proper cross-country course featuring mud, meadows, woodland tracks, slopes. The weather played its part: rain during the week and freezing temperatures on the day filled the puddles with ice; grass sparkled with frost as the sun broke through. I ran a measured race ending up with an individual &lt;a href="http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=118689&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Builth+Wells&amp;amp;date=13-Dec-14"&gt;silver in the MV50&lt;/a&gt; category just two seconds behind Peter Coles, the category winner. I &lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt; get a gold medal as one of Swansea Harriers&amp;#8217; winning MV50 team. In the inter-regional competition, we came second, I think. There are so many competitions being run in the same race it&amp;#8217;s hard to remember. What I do remember thinking is, what a shame such a great event gets such a low turnout. In an age where people part with serious money to tackle military-themed tough guy obstacle courses, for just a couple of quid you get to represent club and region on a challenging course in a fabulous setting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21382218343/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Welsh Masters XC 2014, Swansea Harriers gold medal V50 team"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5661/21382218343_9716029e5c_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Welsh Masters XC 2014, Swansea Harriers gold medal V50 team"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moustache, by the way, was for movember
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-07</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-aftermath</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-aftermath</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>A Corinthian Endeavour: The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/20871409082/in/dateposted-friend/" title="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5776/20871409082_524894d533_z.jpg" width="451" height="640" alt="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in June I went to the launch of Paul Jones&amp;#8217; book &amp;#8220;A Corinthian Endeavour &amp;#8212; The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great talk and it&amp;#8217;s a great book. Here in the UK, we don&amp;#8217;t have Alpine cols or Pyrennean passes. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs"&gt;We have hills&lt;/a&gt;. Hills with erratic gradients and peculiar names &amp;#8212; Nick-o-Pendle, Mow Cop, Pea Royd Lane &amp;#8212; hills which, at the end of the cycling season, draw nascent professionals and amateur specialists to battle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/18495855150/in/dateposted-public/" title="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/458/18495855150_4d6165f574_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones has the credentials to tell the tale: an unashamed fan and a talented writer, he is himself a tidy competitor. The book begins with him interviewing Vic Clarke, the man who finished second in the inaugural national hill climb championships in 1944 and who would go on to win the event three times. Also present is Lyn Hamel, a current competitor and multiple champion herself. When Jones offers biscuits (Marks and Spencers Belgian chocolate selection!) both champions decline: for climbers, gravity is the enemy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gravity isn&amp;#8217;t the only enemy. Competitors don&amp;#8217;t race head to head. The courses are too short and the roads too narrow. Instead they face off against the clock. The fastest time wins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the book continues Jones deftly weaves the history of the championships around more interviews with their protagonists. There&amp;#8217;s Chris Boardman, who set and still holds several records. There are other less familiar names: Wilson, Sydney, Armitage, Dobbin, Pettinger.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/anti-gravity-specialists/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cyclinguphill.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Screen-Shot-2015-06-24-at-10.00.13.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered Paul Jones via his &lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/"&gt;Traumfahrrad&lt;/a&gt; cycling blog, a forum where he allows himself more freedom to poke fun and sound off. His blog describes the joy and pain of early morning training rides. He chortles at triathletes who get their socks wrong. You&amp;#8217;ll also find the details of his own assaults on the hill climbs: despite his self-effacement he&amp;#8217;s clearly a feared and respected rider. In the book, though, he reins himself in and logs the facts. The who, what, how and when are painstakingingly researched and recorded. Gear inches matter more to the author than, apparently, to Chris Boardman, who can barely remember if he took part in a race which he won, let alone the number of teeth on his sprocket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, though, Jones takes a step back from the details. In one chapter he asks: &amp;#8220;When is a Hill not a Hill?&amp;#8221; A good championship course:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;#8230; should be run on closed roads [&amp;#8230;] Riders should be digging out their hill climb bikes and making &lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/marginal-gains-hill-climb-bike" title=""Tejvan Pettinger strips down his bike"&gt;absurd modifications&lt;/a&gt; for no real gain [&amp;#8230;] each competitor needs to be left flailing on a grass bank like a dying goldfish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contrast this to the 2011 championship on Long Hill:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/2015/08/24/below-the-line/"&gt;&lt;img style="width:500px" src="https://scontent-lhr3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xft1/v/t1.0-9/11796216_10207229514877458_7189614863695398022_n.jpg?oh=a2544be1e9e0a4883cd4531b8946519b&amp;oe=5671E221"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the last, Jones claims hill climbers are ascetics in search of transcendence who tilt their caps backwards. By battling time and human frailty paradoxically they escape it and themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first thing&lt;/br&gt;I have understood:&lt;/br&gt;Time is the echo of an axe&lt;/br&gt;Within a wood.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-08-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Dundry Thunder, 1-2-3</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days after a &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k"&gt;fast, flat 5K&lt;/a&gt;, I lined up for the 3rd of this year&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;TACH races&lt;/a&gt;, the Dundry Thunder, a tough and hilly 10K. Having run &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk"&gt;the race last year&lt;/a&gt; I expected livestock, farm machinery, gates, stiles, bridges, rutted mud, long grass, crops. Andy gave me a lift from Southville confessing he&amp;#8217;d be running to enjoy himself since he wasn&amp;#8217;t feeling great, he&amp;#8217;d picked up a bug of some sort.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first 100m or so I led the race. Once we hit Littleton Lane I eased up, picking my footing carefully across tarmac, stones, rubble, compacted refuse. Down, down we went, then down some more before eventually sweeping right and looping back up through the fields. There were 5 ahead of me now: Matt in the lead, 3 Bristol and West runners, including Neil, and one from Weston AC. By chance I&amp;#8217;d positioned myself well, catching runners as they bunched up through a sequence of gates.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/antony-clark/14328857659" title="Untitled by Antony in Bristol, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3860/14328857659_8ca7e1224e_z.jpg" width="640" height="424" alt="Untitled"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route levelled on to an overgrown path, single file only. You can&amp;#8217;t see me in the photo but I&amp;#8217;m right behind the Weston runner, who doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be enjoying the long grass. By now Matt had built a commanding lead, sensing and grasping his chance. On leaving the path we had an opportunity to accelerate on level, open terrain. The tall runner in the green vest behind me who I&amp;#8217;d assumed was Phil turned out to be Andy, who did indeed look to be enjoying himself. Past the radio mast, though a barley field, and then hurtling back down the hill with Chew Valley Lake and the Mendips ahead.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As on the first descent I chose to run alone allowing the leaders &amp;#8212; Matt and Andy &amp;#8212; to extend their lead. I had them in sight. I reckoned, when we hit the bottom of Littleton Lane, there were 10 minutes to go. This was where the race would be won. Last year, I&amp;#8217;d caught Matt on this climb, as well as a runner from Weston who&amp;#8217;d been reduced to walking; I&amp;#8217;d put time into Andy, and I&amp;#8217;d also caught Andy Malloy &amp;#8212; only for him to speed up and blow me away. This year, neither Matt nor Andy showed any sign of weakness. A couple of lads were playing on bikes towards the top of the climb. I hoped they wouldn&amp;#8217;t get in anyone&amp;#8217;s way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last I reached the top of Littleton Lane. Turn left, a marshal indicated. I wasn&amp;#8217;t quite sure which way to go at the next junction but chose right. Good, there was Andy! I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be catching him now but I couldn&amp;#8217;t see anyone catching me either. I heard a scream: had a runner tangled with those cyclists? No, there was Matt, &lt;strong&gt;sprinting&lt;/strong&gt; back towards the junction I&amp;#8217;d just navigated. He must have gone the wrong way. I considered slowing up to let him finish in his rightful place ahead of me, but having got this far I wanted to get to the end with a time to compare against last year&amp;#8217;s.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=DT_result14.inc"&gt;my time was 4 seconds&lt;/a&gt; faster than I ran last year. I&amp;#8217;ll take that. I&amp;#8217;ll also take 3rd place, one position higher than last year &amp;#8212; Andy and I gave the win to Matt, since we clearly wouldn&amp;#8217;t have caught him. Next up (and down, and up, and down), the Purdown Pursuit!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/antony-clark/14515494315" title="Untitled by Antony in Bristol, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3915/14515494315_d47bdff301_z.jpg" width="640" height="441" alt="Untitled"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s Andy, who can now see the finish but &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; Matt!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/antony-clark/14329050377" title="Untitled by Antony in Bristol, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3892/14329050377_27d79c711e_z.jpg" width="640" height="450" alt="Untitled"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dried mud &amp;#8212; hard work after the final climb. As you can see, having run the entire race in front, Matt has ended up behind me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/antony-clark/14514401152" title="Untitled by Antony in Bristol, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3844/14514401152_bea9b09b91_z.jpg" width="506" height="640" alt="Untitled"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gutted!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Antony Clark for the dramatic &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/antony-clark/sets/72157644970731957/"&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; used on this page.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-06-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/dundry-thunder-123</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/dundry-thunder-123</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The last ever Pomphrey 5K</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On a warm summer evening I cycled out of Bristol on the railway path. The verges were overgrown, the air dense with insects. Coming through Staple Hill the path enters a tunnel, water falling from the arching roof and onto the tarmac.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I count the Pomphrey Sports 5K as unfinished business. Last time I ran it &amp;#8212; the only time I&amp;#8217;d run it, in fact, the only timed 5K I&amp;#8217;d ever run &amp;#8212; on a dark, blustery winter&amp;#8217;s evening it took me &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=70510&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Jan-13"&gt;18 minutes and 44 seconds&lt;/a&gt; to get round. Today, I had to do better. I wanted to test my speed ahead of the &lt;a href="http://www.swanseahalfmarathon.co.uk/"&gt;Swansea half&lt;/a&gt;. An email from race director, Chris Elson, warned me I wouldn&amp;#8217;t get another chance:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;This race incorporates the Avon AA mob match with the winning team (20 to count) being awarded the Andrew Rawnsley Memorial Trophy. We hope there will be lots of Avon Clubs with teams! &lt;b&gt;This race will be the last, after some 15 years&lt;/b&gt;, to be held on the course but plans are at an advanced stage to move the race to a flat fast course using the mile circuit at Aztec West.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short warm up around Pomphrey Hill playing fields, I joined the other runners at the start of the course. Fewer than I expected &amp;#8212; maybe a couple of hundred of us, and only seven from &lt;a href="http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk/"&gt;SRC&lt;/a&gt;. There was Sam Stone, a work colleague, running for &lt;a href="http://www.emersonsgreenrunningclub.co.uk/"&gt;Emersons Green&lt;/a&gt;. We gathered on the cycle track under the B4465 bridge over the ringroad. After a brief announcement, we were off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, 5K is a tough distance. It feels like I&amp;#8217;m running flat out the whole way. The track veers through a subway under the ringroad. At 1K, my watch showed 3:30. Now we skirted the new roundabout exit, trainers hitting plywood boards laid over fresh tarmac. Crossing the ringroad now on a pedestrian bridge. I hit 2K around 7 minutes in and realised my target, 18 minutes, was very much on. Matt was just ahead. Around us, red and white vests, Bristol and West. The track takes a left at the next roundabout and then at exactly 2.5K out doubles back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/157862063/embed/5f0a94ffb444a1ce7f5bffd483e08cd8159dbe32'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My legs felt tired in the final kilometre. Somehow sensing my weakness Matt opened a gap which 5 Bristol and West runners smartly filled. I checked my watch. A PB for sure. 18 minutes, definitely, but having got into this position how hard would I push for the finish? Did I really want to set a best time which would be out of reach in future? My legs felt ragged.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I crossed the line under the bridge over the ringroad and stopped my watch. 17:48, it said.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the presentation, Roger, one of the race directors, took the opportunity to talk about the history of the race which originated some 20 years ago to finance Bristol and West AC sending competitors all round the country, paying for petrol and entry fees. Back then there was no roundabout, no ring road, no cycle track. The sports pavilion we sat in hadn&amp;#8217;t been built and so the Bridge Inn hosted the event, which was run on dirt tracks around the former quarry.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first MV50 to finish, in 22nd place with an official time of 17:50, I picked up a &amp;pound;5 Easy Running voucher. Without me being aware of it the next two runners, just 4 and 13 seconds behind me, were also MV50&amp;#8217;s. Some race!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
1      15.23   John Ashcroft   Bristol University      SM
2      15.34   Matt Whitfield  Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
3      16.21   James Denne     Exeter Harriers         SM
4      16.33   Jarlath McKenna Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
5      16.35   Matthew Krelle  Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
6      16.48   Mark Edwards    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
7      17.06   Iain Stuart     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
8      17.08   Olly Sheppard   Team Bath AC            SM
9      17.09   Sam Hedley      Team Bath AC            SM
10     17.14   Jenny Jagger    Bristol &amp; West AC       SW
11     17.24   Anthony Hall    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
12     17.26   Torran Elson    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
13     17.34   Jacob Hayes     Bitton Road Runners    M40
14     17.35   Matt Burns      Southville              SM
15     17.37   Chris Palmer    Westbury Harriers       SM
16     17.38   Peter Gandon    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
17     17.40   Alexander Whittaker  Bristol &amp; West AC  SM
18     17.41   Helen Sharpe    Bristol &amp; West AC       SW
19     17.42   Phil Lucker     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
20     17.44   Jason Barry     Stroud &amp; District      M40
21     17.46   Ben Farrell     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
&lt;b&gt;22     17.50   Thomas Guest    Southville             M50&lt;/b&gt;
23     17.54   Gary Hughes     Team Bath AC           M50
24     18.03   Phil Westlake   Bitton Road Runners    M50
25     18.04   Julian Bailey-Gard Westbury Harriers    SM
26     18.06   C McQuade       Unattached              SM
27     18.08   Andrew Malloy   Bristol &amp; West AC      M40
...
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling back along the track which was once a railway I thought about Bristol traffic, transport and history. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-06-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Wrington Woodland Tyntesfield 10</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At the start of the month I attempted the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Wrington Woodland&lt;/a&gt; run. Conditions were warm and damp. The race starts with a gradual climb from Goblin Coombe. I was tracking the leaders at this stage. The rocky track became a river of viscous clay. A Frome runner slipped and slithered, his &lt;a href="http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/running_mens.htm"&gt;five fingers&lt;/a&gt; affording little traction. I moved past into second place.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=http://www.theracephotographer.com/2014/WWR/Set_A/large/image_a0007.jpg alt="WWR, theracephotographer.com/2014" width=640px /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own shoes &amp;#8212; my normally trusty Adidas swoop trail shoes &amp;#8212; skidded on the fast tarmac descent to Wrington. I slowed down then pushed on, determined to hold my position. On the second climb, the steep one up Bullhouse Lane, my right calf went. I limped, then walked, then tried to run through the injury, then walked again. I was in some pain. Runners passed me. I&amp;#8217;m fine, I said, it&amp;#8217;s cramp. The woods on top of Wrington Hill were packed with bluebells. A kindly marshal gave me a lift back to the HQ once the race had passed. My first ever DNF. I felt lousy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, three weeks later, I showed up for the &lt;a href="http://nailsearunningclub.org.uk/club-races/"&gt;Tyntesfield 10&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; a favourite event from last year. My calf still isn&amp;#8217;t 100% but I needed to get round the course to put Wrington behind me. I could surely do that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started easily on the first meadow circuit. We looped back to the house, swerving round the croquet lawn and flowerbeds, then back to the meadow again. My legs felt good. I pushed on towards the woods, passing runners as the track rose. Watch out for tree roots! Go on Southville! The track twists and swerves, hurdling fallen trees, ducking under branches. I was glad to be clear and able to pick my own route. Andy Malloy cruised past. I drafted him, pulling me into contention with a couple of other runners.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the woods and into long grass, nettles, thistles, rape. At this stage last year I&amp;#8217;d been wiped out. Today, a more cautious start had earned me something in reserve. To my surprise, Annabel Granger was in range, plus another couple of runners I didn&amp;#8217;t know. At last we reached the long descent bringing the route back home. I passed one runner. I passed two more, only for them to nip ahead when I misinterpreted a marshal&amp;#8217;s signal and turned the wrong way. Down the steps and on to the tarmac. I dug in on the final short climb, regaining my earlier position. On the finishing straight, for the first time in the race, I looked behind me. My position was safe. I crossed the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training mate Neil Williams was so close behind I didn&amp;#8217;t see him finish. I cheered in another friend, Steve Swan, drank the water and ate the minuscule cereal bar in the goodie bag.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14056237608" title="Tyntesfield 10k by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/14056237608_9b09156c0c_z.jpg" width="640" height="428" alt="Tyntesfield 10k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was 7th to finish and 1st in my category. My time, &lt;a href="https://www.fullonsport.co.uk/fos/index.php?module=results&amp;amp;eventId=4350&amp;amp;action=results" title="Race results"&gt;40:39&lt;/a&gt;, was 22 seconds faster than at the same event last year. Next up: the Welsh Castles Relay.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rich Kenington, &lt;a href="http://www.theracephotographer.com"&gt;theracephotographer.com&lt;/a&gt;, and Sally Johnson for the excellent action shots used on this page.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-05-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-tyntesfield-10</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-tyntesfield-10</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Blaise Blazer, from A to T, August 2013</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle estate, another great location for a multi-terrain race. I was looking forward to running in the third and last of Westbury Harriers&amp;#8217; &lt;a href="http://www.westburyharriers.co.uk/promotions.html"&gt;Blaise Blazer 2013 races&lt;/a&gt; for a couple of reasons: first, my knowledge of the estate&amp;#8217;s winding paths and trails could only be to my advantage; and second, I&amp;#8217;d be running for Southville Running Club, who I train with on Tuesday evenings, and who would be defending the Blazer Challenge Cup they won in 2012.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time, I&amp;#8217;d try not to arrive so early. It took a while to register everyone. Eventually, over 120 runners toed a wide starting line on the field looking down towards the mansion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/10859993384/" title="blaise-blazer by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7353/10859993384_334b3ce734_z.jpg" width="640" height="570" alt="blaise-blazer"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We charged across the grass to A hitting the path at B. I must have been about 20th at C, the foot of the first climb, and picked up a few places by H, where we switched from a well-surfaced path to a woodland trail. Matt, Mike, Mark and Tim &amp;#8212; all Southville runners &amp;#8212; were ahead, but not too far ahead. Climbing I, J, K, a treacherous uphill track, I passed Tim. I took the muddy descent from O to P carefully. Mike pulled away on the flat, Q, and somehow I was pulling away from Mark and staying in contact with Matt. Maybe I could have done more on the final climb to the castle, R, S, T, but maybe I didn&amp;#8217;t know the paths quite as well as I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I was glad to finish and cheer in the remaining runners.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half an hour later we were back at the Westbury Harriers club house and half an hour after that the results had been logged and checked. Southville retained the Challenge Cup, hooray! I finished 10th, the first MV40, in a time of 24:17.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/10859883155/" title="Southville Running Club, Blazer challenge cup holders 2013 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3755/10859883155_890e326008_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Southville Running Club, Blazer challenge cup holders 2013"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-09-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2013</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The TACH ticks talk</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Happily I recovered from flu in time to line up for the start of the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Wrington Woodland&lt;/a&gt; run. 100 or so of us queued on the footpath just outside Cleeve listening to a well rehearsed pre-race briefing: this is going to take 5 minutes so don&amp;#8217;t stare at me, I won&amp;#8217;t go any faster, a special announcement, Jim and Alfredo are running &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/10kX365"&gt;10km a day every day this year&lt;/a&gt; so like them on Facebook and when you shower check yourself for ticks, you&amp;#8217;re unlikely to have any and they&amp;#8217;re unlikely to be carrying Lyme disease, which can usually be treated, but if you do and they are and you aren&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8230; conditions &lt;strong&gt;downhill&lt;/strong&gt; are fine but uphill watch out for tree roots, loose stones etc. Honk! We were off!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path climbed steadily up Cleeve Hill. Matt hung behind the leaders then eased away hitting a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow. Andy passed me when the path levelled off. A tall runner from Weston AC bounded downhill on elastic legs. Hey, maybe I was still the first veteran runner on the course? If I was, I wasn&amp;#8217;t for long. I felt weary on the climb up Wrington Hill; Andrew Malloy (V40) and  Adrian Noble (V50) overtook. At last the track levelled and zigzagged downhill back to Cleeve. I clattered over a narrow wooden bridge and cleared a stile and ran on wobbly legs across one last field to the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done Matt for winning! Jim and Alfredo ran on through the finish, the route being a few metres short of 10k. Prize-giving was held in the Lord Nelson skittle alley. How we cheered!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9381867241/" title="About a mile into the Burrington Blaster by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3734/9381867241_da0013242e_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="About a mile into the Burrington Blaster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second race, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Burrington Blaster&lt;/a&gt;, found me in better form, which is just as well: the route took us from the Burrington Inn right up to the top of the Mendips in one long climb. The view at the summit was spectacular and although the urge to stop and admire it was strong I pushed on through gusting winds and boggy footing. 4th place was mine if I could negotiate the treacherous descent. I couldn&amp;#8217;t, falling a short way from the finish when my feet slid on loose stones. Nothing damaged, but physical and mental momentum destroyed. A couple of red and white vests &amp;#8212; Bristol and West &amp;#8212; passed. I held on for 6th.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fancied my chances in the third race, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Purdown Pursuit&lt;/a&gt;, my former training ground. When I lived in Cobourg Road, on Sunday mornings I&amp;#8217;d head out along Boiling Wells Lane and past the telecoms tower, attacking a selection of Purdown&amp;#8217;s short sharp hills before passing the UWE campus to head under the M32 and back through Frenchay and Snuff Mills. How could they fit 10k into Purdown, I wondered? The answer turned out to be a double loop; the first short circuit had me wondering how I&amp;#8217;d hang on for the second longer loop, this one covering the full length of the down, Stoke Lane to Muller Road and back again. Hold on I did, passing a pony-tailed Nailsea runner who took a wrong turn through the woods, and losing a place to Andrew Malloy (again!) on the final downhill swoop. I collapsed at the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9381881853/" title="Purdown pursuit by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5327/9381881853_858db6ec4d_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Purdown pursuit"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something different! Race four, closing the series, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Dundry Thunder&lt;/a&gt; run, started at the top of the hill. A prolonged spell of hot weather had broken into storms during the week and I wondered if the thunder would be more literal than alliterative, but the evening turned out just fine, clear, not too hot, as we gathered on the downs at foot of the radio masts. You could see all of Bristol, city and suburbs, the Clifton bridge, and beyond to the Severn estuary spanned by another suspension bridge and the angular second crossing. I warmed up, running the wrong way along the finishing straight, skipping over thistles and cowpats. The start was delayed whilst a local resident trimmed his hedge, destroying some route markings in the process.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race was a double loop: starting with a jostling descent down Littleton Lane towards Winford. Determined to hold something back for the second loop, I watched the leaders stride away from me. Behind a hedge, the sound of gunshots. We turned off the lane and looped back through fields up the hill to Dundry, negotiating uneven ground, gates and stiles. Skittish cattle stampeded across the course. I pulled back a couple of places on the climb and sped up when we reached the level section along Crabtree Lane, vaulting a gate at the same time as a Weston AC runner tried to open it. We waded through a field of oilseed rape, the heavy pods slapping our legs, then past another radio mast. The second extended downhill cut a diagonal through a barley field. More gates, stiles, streams. Now we were back on Littleton Lane for a final drag uphill to the finish. I was tired but the runners around me were too, maybe more so. The tall runner from Weston AC was walking. I went past. Further on, I passed Matt. Briefly I nosed ahead of Andrew Malloy but that spurred him to up his pace and pull away again. One last momentum-sapping stop-start through a gate and I could see the line. Was Matt on my heels or 50m away? Now would not be a good time to look back. I blundered through thistles and cowpats and crossed the line exhausted but in control. The 5th place I thought I&amp;#8217;d got turned out to be 4th. Result!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary: in the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;WW, BB, PP and DT&lt;/a&gt; races I came 9th 6th 5th 4th with times of 39:45, 37:11, 42:52 and 42:32.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the TACH team for organising such a great series of races with good humour and efficiency. I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to next year already. Four pubs did well to serve drinks to all those thirsty runners but I guess they did well out of it too. Thanks to Matt for transporting the Swansea Harriers team. Thanks also to Rachel Foyle and Emma Postlethwaite for allowing me to use their fine photos here. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-07-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>2012-2013 Cross Country season and some</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I recorded some of my race results since the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012.html"&gt;WCR, 2012&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next race was the &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk"&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt; opener at Newbridge Fields, Bridgend. I ran this same course the year before on a cold, blustery day, sheets of rain swirling. This time, the weather turned out unseasonably warm. I came &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm121i.htm"&gt;78th with a time of 38:22&lt;/a&gt;, an improvement of 26 places and 3 minutes over my previous outing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4531393735/" title="Whiteford Sands lighthouse by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2772/4531393735_eba09f0864.jpg" width="500" height="371" alt="Whiteford Sands lighthouse"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after I ran closer to home in the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;West Glamorgan League at Llanmadoc&lt;/a&gt;. Although the rain held off on the day, it hadn&amp;#8217;t over the past weeks and the track out to the lighthouse comprised a series of ponds linked by mud. I made a mistake lining up for the start some way from the front of the field and ended up jostled and sodden by the time the race stretched out and settled in. After, I hooked up with Ifan for a warm down; we ran the full route a second time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://westglamleague.co.uk/resources/_wsb_417x374_West+Glam+League+at+Llanmadoc.jpg" alt="puddles"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle, Bristol, for the 3rd fixture in the Gwent League. Isobel and Alex ran too. I tried to keep up with Eamon but he pulled away on the second lap. In the closing stages I looked over my shoulder to see Raul storming towards me. I had enough left, or he timed his surge for the line too late; either way I &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm123i.htm"&gt;finished ahead of him&lt;/a&gt;, but I can&amp;#8217;t see that happening next time we race together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was it, my cross country season over. I was supposed to run the Welsh regional cross country championships but didn&amp;#8217;t make it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of January this year I ran the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolandwestac.org/bridge-inn-5k"&gt;Bridge Inn 5K&lt;/a&gt; on a very windy night and did well to finish &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0BzIFRjtRS2vBVkE3b1dWV0RrUUU/edit"&gt;a few seconds&lt;/a&gt; before Matt Burns.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I ran the first of four alliterative &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;TACH races&lt;/a&gt;, the Wrington Woodland run, which I thoroughly enjoyed. The &lt;a href="http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/v2/181608257/218757"&gt;course&lt;/a&gt; started in Cleeve with a long but gradual climb up a woodland track. After a few dry weeks the surface was rocky and rutted. Matt (who I beat in the 5K, remember?) strode ahead a few minutes in, clocking a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow; and, as it turned out, noone else could either. As we crested the top of the climb Andy overtook me. On the descent to Wrington another runner bounded past. I wasn&amp;#8217;t feeling too fresh by Bullnose Lane, the second uphill section, and settled on trying to hold my place rather than catch anyone. Even that proved optimistic and a couple of runners pegged me back before the final descent back to Cleeve.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased with &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=wrington_result13.inc"&gt;9th place&lt;/a&gt;. Congratulations to Matt on his well deserved win! A diet of interval training and competitive racing have honed his form and after a series of top ten placings in recent events it came down to when not if.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.srcbristol.hostoi.com/images/sidebar/bristol_running_club_matt.jpg" alt="Burnsy" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Secret Blackbird</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a treat, to be &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow.html"&gt;back&lt;/a&gt; at the zoo education centre for the launch of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/secret-blackbird.html"&gt;The Secret Blackbird &amp;mdash; the alarming case of the missing birds&lt;/a&gt;! The book investigates the summer-time absence of garden birds, but before considering this central mystery Geraldine posed some other puzzles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do herons fly overhead when a ground mist covers the downs?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do more long-tailed tits fly out of a bush than flew into it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do pied wagtails run in circles round lamp posts?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never counted birds in and out of bushes but I reckon I know the answer to the second one: by the time you notice a tit fly into a bush there&amp;#8217;s probably a few others in there already; and you watch them all fly out. Geraldine suggests the discrepancy is always one &amp;#8212; the lone anchor bird which discreetly reconnoitres the bush before giving the others the OK to proceed. So you see, the mystery is all about point of view.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for herons. When the downs are covered in mist Geraldine looks up more. Have you noticed, she added, the way wood-pigeons dive in and out of the mist, like a dolphin? Why do they do that? Lubrication, to stop their wings creaking!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5752121266/" title="Crowded nest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2365/5752121266_4af54dcacc_n.jpg" width="320" height="267" alt="Crowded nest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pied wagtails in our garden do run in circles but not around things and not right now, they&amp;#8217;re too busy feeding five hungry fledglings. I&amp;#8217;d assumed it was a courtship display. Geraldine had no definitive answer either. By now, the audience was involved: where do swifts sleep, and what happens to swallows in winter? The swifts fly up high in the evening and wake lower down in the morning, still on the wing. The swallows conglobulate together, by flying round and round, and then all in a heap throw themselves under water, and lye in the bed of a river.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dru read a haiku. Deborah Harvey read two poems from &lt;a href="http://www.indigodreamsbookshop.com/#/deborah-harvey/4552913959"&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The birds, it turns out, aren&amp;#8217;t missing, they&amp;#8217;re moulting. Low on energy after the nesting season and barely able to fly due to lack of feathers, they lie low, avoiding predators. In the summer of 2010 Geraldine watched a blackbird &amp;#8212; the secret blackbird &amp;#8212; go through this process, and now she retold the story, reading from her book. Dru signalled the part of the bird using a set of semaphore flags.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more poems, the final one acted out with a soft toy and a star.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a very fine book indeed. Dru has surpassed herself with the illustrations, which mix avian character studies and cartoons.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-05-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Owls, trains, turkeys and other friends of the RWA</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803013211/" title="Wild Turkey by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7141/6803013211_5e35ca7ed2_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Wild Turkey"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bird stands in judgement outside the main gallery at the &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/" title="Royal West of England Academy"&gt;Royal West of England Academy&lt;/a&gt;. The glass on the bar once contained bourbon whiskey &amp;#8212; look closely and you can see an empty Wild Turkey miniature.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turkey&amp;#8217;s by &lt;a href="http://filthyluker.org/"&gt;filthy luker&lt;/a&gt;. He works with pigeons too &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://filthyluker.org"&gt;&lt;img src="http://filthyluker.org/wp-content/gallery/manifestations/08pigeon_english_by_filthy_luker_UK.jpg" alt="Urban birds" width="600px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; and monsters!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3364983737/" title="Kraken invades RWA by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3574/3364983737_cd574805b1.jpg" width="500" height="399" alt="Kraken invades RWA"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now filthy luker is &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/whats-on/exhibitions/2012/01/exhibitions-filthy-luker/"&gt;artist in residence&lt;/a&gt; at the RWA. Also in residence at the RWA &amp;#8212; just outside, on the balcony, where those tentacles were &amp;#8212; is Damien Hirst&amp;#8217;s outsize collection box, Charity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803014231/" title="Charity by Damien by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7024/6803014231_6b6b6665a3.jpg" width="500" height="323" alt="Charity by Damien"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean to say: the RWA is Bristol&amp;#8217;s finest exhibition space and it puts on Bristol&amp;#8217;s finest exhibitions. The juxtaposition of classical architecture and &lt;a href="http://www.crimesofpassion.info/"&gt;urban art&lt;/a&gt; works well. Classical paintings fit in superbly too: last year&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz.html"&gt;Robert Lenkiewicz&lt;/a&gt; retrospective was stunning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It costs to get in though. It cost &amp;pound;4 last year and now it costs &amp;pound;5. That&amp;#8217;s quite a lot for a show you&amp;#8217;re not sure you&amp;#8217;ll like. Often the shows you&amp;#8217;re not sure you&amp;#8217;ll like are the ones worth seeing, and seeing again. That&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;m a &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/support-us/friends-patrons/"&gt;Friend&lt;/a&gt;. I work around the corner and can head over whenever the computer screen makes me dizzy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6800313715/" title="Friend of the RWA by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7013/6800313715_c6755919bf.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Friend of the RWA"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Lane made the bird on the card from scrap metal. I&amp;#8217;m not sure &lt;a href="http://is.gd/fNQRas"&gt;what type of bird&lt;/a&gt; it is. An archetypal mix of hornbill/stork/flamingo maybe? In the gallery behind the turkey are more birds, owls, by Ivor Abrahams, along with his interesting 2&amp;#189; dimensional sculptures and some tiresome garden things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803013435/" title="One of Ivor Abrahams' owls by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7009/6803013435_0ba8e39b05.jpg" width="461" height="500" alt="One of Ivor Abrahams' owls"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quite liked the show until I read what he had to say on the &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/local/views/uploads/documents/1327919367_20120130102927_17542851114f2671071a0fd6_93619033_592086275_8114811666.pdf"&gt;&amp;#8220;interpretation panel&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sculptures, collages, prints and drawings of Ivor Abrahams occupy a very particular place in British 20th Century art. No other artist has attempted to do what he has done &amp;#8212; to create an entirely new kind of polychrome sculpture which operates effectively between painting and sculpture &amp;#8212; and achieved such a catalogue of notable successes in the process. Essentially subversive, Abrahams has also gained a reputation for a wicked wit and a generally argumentative demeanour. Nothing is sacred, particularly the established names of the past. As he has admitted: &amp;#8220;I always enjoyed the pomposity of academic sculpture, the grandiosity and rhetoric. The edifying or inspirational nature of the art has always led me to treat it with the greatest of disrespect.&amp;#8221; That irreverence has fuelled his career, and helped him make of the sum of destructions a newly-constructed vision of his own work. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidshepherd.com"&gt;&lt;img width="600px" src="http://www.davidshepherd.com/davidshepherd-elephantsatamboseli.jpg" alt="Elephants at Amboseli, David Shepherd" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside, and by contrast, are a number of paintings and prints by David Shepherd. They aren&amp;#8217;t to my taste but they most certainly were when I was younger (the animal ones, not the trains and planes). I can&amp;#8217;t argue with &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/whats-on/exhibitions/2012/02/exhibitions-david-shepherd/"&gt;his attitude&lt;/a&gt; either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Shepherd paints every day of his life. Now aged eighty, the famed wildlife, aviation and steam train artist describes his life as &amp;#8216;a series of disasters&amp;#8217; &amp;#8212; David Shepherd&amp;#8217;s career has been shaped by serendipity. Rejected by the Slade School of Art, David planned to train as a bus driver. A chance encounter with artist Robin Goodwin resulted in a three-year apprenticeship &amp;#8212; a first for Goodwin, who revelled in the challenge, and a life-changing opportunity for Shepherd.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodwin taught Shepherd commercially as well as artistically. &amp;#8220;Throwing paint at the wall and &amp;#8216;expressing yourself&amp;#8217; doesn&amp;#8217;t pay the bills&amp;#8221;, taught Robin. &amp;#8220;Artists, like everyone else, have to work eight hours and more a day, seven days a week, to meet their responsibilities.&amp;#8221; These words have informed Shepherd&amp;#8217;s work, and he is now one of the UK&amp;#8217;s most financially rewarded artists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidshepherd.com"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.davidshepherd.com/davidshepherd-overtheforth.jpg" width="600px" alt="Over the Forth, David Shepherd"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-02-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owls-trains-turkeys-and-other-friends-of-the-rwa</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owls-trains-turkeys-and-other-friends-of-the-rwa</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>what is happening to the Assyrian reliefs?</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a gloomy day! In need of colour I decided to revisit the &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/wildlife-photographer-year"&gt;wildlife photography exhibition&lt;/a&gt; in my lunchbreak.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think there must be two wildlife photography exhibitions, they come round so frequently, but now I understand there&amp;#8217;s only one; it&amp;#8217;s just that it stays on display for so long. It stays popular too, with good reason. I wish they&amp;#8217;d print larger versions of the photos though.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.nhm.ac.uk/resources-www/visit-us/whats-on/temporary-exhibitions/swpy/2011/popup/024.jpg" alt="The assassin, by Steve Mills"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photos come with the tales of their capture. Here&amp;#8217;s how &lt;a href="http://www.nhm.ac.uk/visit-us/whats-on/temporary-exhibitions/wpy/photo.do?photo=2717&amp;amp;category=3&amp;amp;group=1"&gt;Joe Bunni snapped a polar bear&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;After three days on a small boat looking for polar bears in Repulse Bay, Nunavut, Canada, Joe got lucky. &amp;#8216;We cruised at a distance, so we didn&amp;#8217;t disturb the bear. Once we were sure it was relaxed with our presence, I slipped quietly into the water with just a mask and fins, attached to the boat by a rope.&amp;#8217; The polar bear now started to swim towards the boat. It didn&amp;#8217;t appear to notice Joe, and for 20 minutes he was able to take photographs from the water. But then the bear caught sight of its own reflection in the dome port and swam up to Joe. &amp;#8216;It&amp;#8217;s amazing when a huge, powerful animal comes beside you.&amp;#8217; It came so close that its nose touched the housing, startling it. The second after Joe took this shot, the bear reached out and touched the dome with its paw. Then it turned and swam away, leaving Joe with an unforgettable image - symbolic &amp;#8216;of the power and elegance of a wonderful creature struggling to survive in a fast-changing climate&amp;#8217;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.nhm.ac.uk/resources-www/visit-us/whats-on/temporary-exhibitions/swpy/2011/popup/034.jpg" alt="Polar Power"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unforgettable indeed! If I were Joe I&amp;#8217;d have prioritised my own survival and admired the power and elegance at a distance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5017113982/" title="Polar bear skeleton, Bristol Museum by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4103/5017113982_008ec3e479.jpg" width="500" height="354" alt="Polar bear skeleton, Bristol Museum"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bristol museum&amp;#8217;s own polar bear has disappeared, making way for a new lift which is being installed just beyond the room holding the Assyrian reliefs. The reliefs remain on display &amp;#8212; at least, I could see them today &amp;#8212; but they&amp;#8217;ve been separated, strapped, and mounted on shock absorbers to reduce the risk of damage from vibrations whilst the lift works go on.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6476527801/" title="what is happening to the Assyrian reliefs? by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7009/6476527801_d297c4ac48.jpg" width="391" height="500" alt="what is happening to the Assyrian reliefs?"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assembly of ancient stones and modern fixings looked like a conceptual artwork. I tried to imagine the history of the reliefs, how they&amp;#8217;d been quarried, manoeuvred, carved, lifted, shipped &amp;#8212; how 8 tons of granite had ended up here in Clifton.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-12-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/what-is-happening-to-the-assyrian-reliefs</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/what-is-happening-to-the-assyrian-reliefs</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol, Cycling City?</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6544368391/" title="BETT... by
Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img
src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7165/6544368391_abd9703d60_m.jpg" width="230"
height="240" alt="BETT..."&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6544368593/" title="ER BY BIKE
by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img
src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7018/6544368593_f8ab7f7ba5_m.jpg" width="205"
height="240" alt="ER BY BIKE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2008 Greater Bristol was chosen as England&amp;#8217;s first Cycling City and received &amp;pound;11m from the Department for Transport to transform cycling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helped bring about a strong cycling renaissance in the city. New dedicated on-road cycle lanes, new traffic-free routes, 3400 new cycle parking spaces, as well as cycling training and lots of other &amp;#8216;softer measures&amp;#8217; projects encouraged thousands of people to saddle up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/cycling"&gt;http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/cycling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and I got a mug out of it, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/philmciver/2299981707/" title="Bristol: Queen Square by Phil McIver, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3062/2299981707_b94952f0ec.jpg" width="500" height="351" alt="Bristol: Queen Square"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, though, I cycled from &lt;a href="http://www.screwfix.com/jsp/tradeCounter/tradeCounterDetailsPage.jsp?id=66"&gt;Screwfix in Bedminster&lt;/a&gt; to my office in Clifton. How pleasant to cycle through the middle of Queen Square on a track which, less than 20 years ago, was a dual carriageway. And how enjoyable to continue on across Broad Quay and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Centre_(Bristol)#1998_remodelling"&gt;the centre&lt;/a&gt;, which used to be one great roundabout. Pedestrians and cyclists get the best routes and the best views and that&amp;#8217;s how it should be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6550510109/" title="The Queen Square of the Future by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7013/6550510109_e4f31684ba.jpg" width="500" height="243" alt="The Queen Square of the Future"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle parking area where I work is secure, free (in marked contrast to the car parking spaces), and recently doubled in size. It fills up, every day, even now winter has set in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree: there &lt;strong&gt;has&lt;/strong&gt; been a cycling renaissance but I think it&amp;#8217;s down to a number of factors. Primarily, it&amp;#8217;s lower incomes and the rising price of motoring which is getting people on their bikes. A secondary effect adds momentum: the more cyclists there are, the more people accept cycling, and the more cyclists there will be. The fantastic success of British cycling may have something to do with it, judging by the number of swish road bikes which spin round the Downs every evening. The &lt;a href="http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/TravelAndTransport/Cycling/DG_190101"&gt;government cycle to work scheme&lt;/a&gt; is a fine deal, though I suspect the main beneficiaries are people like me who&amp;#8217;ve always cycled to work. And technological improvements, like &lt;a href="http://traumradfahren.wordpress.com/2011/12/07/commuter-bicycle-race/"&gt;electrically assisted bikes&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; I see plenty of cyclists who wouldn&amp;#8217;t be cycling without these.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling city? &amp;pound;11m! Transformation!?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It annoys me that &amp;#8220;special&amp;#8221; funding should be needed to provide for cyclists. Cycle parking spaces should be built anyway. Any transport planning should naturally prioritise pedestrians and cyclists. I don&amp;#8217;t think &amp;pound;11m paid for the reworking of Queen Square and Broad Quay, yet these schemes have benefited cyclists far more than a new bike route from the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JG7Lv1Ipfz8" title="worth watching for the muzak and subtitles alone"&gt;Farm pub to B&amp;amp;Q&lt;/a&gt;. I would like bike theft to be eliminated. I would like to see car-free approaches to secondary schools in the mornings and afternoons. Get kids used to commuting on foot and by bike and they&amp;#8217;ll continue as adults.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cycling City money wasn&amp;#8217;t wasted but I&amp;#8217;d say the initiative contributed little to the increase in cycling and it&amp;#8217;s foolish to claim or think otherwise. Yes, there are more cyclists on the roads but there need to be far, far more. How can we maintain the momentum? The little things help, let&amp;#8217;s keep doing them, but really it&amp;#8217;s down to government policy, personal responsibility and intelligent transport planning.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-11-16</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-cycling-city</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-cycling-city</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Alan Turing centenary exhibition at the Arnolfini</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chanceprojects/5489369688/" title="19 timeline by neil cummings, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5215/5489369688_3784823d18.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="19 timeline"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents are born in 1931 making them centenarians in 2031, the year in which &amp;#8212; according to the &lt;a href="http://www.arnolfini.org.uk/whatson/exhibitions/details/928"&gt;Arnolfini timeline&lt;/a&gt;, a colour-coded sequence of data sprites recording the Arnolfini&amp;#8217;s presence from the Bristol riots of 1831 to the gallery&amp;#8217;s own centenary in 2061 &amp;#8212; in 2031, coincidentally, life expectancy has risen to 100. In 2031 the Arnolfini also marks Alan Turing&amp;#8217;s centenary with an exhibition, Almost Real: Composite Consciousness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6216774835/" title="Almost Real: Composite Consciousness, Alan Turing centenary exhibition by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6158/6216774835_db9d268d22.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Almost Real: Composite Consciousness, Alan Turing centenary exhibition"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This confuses me since &lt;a href="http://www.turingcentenary.eu/"&gt;2012 is Turing&amp;#8217;s centenary&lt;/a&gt;. He is born in 1912. In 1931 he studies mathematics at Cambridge.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling for more on the Almost Real exhibition, which I have yet to see, I &lt;a href="http://criticalpracticechelsea.org/wiki/index.php?title=Arnolfini_timeline#2050._Almost_Real:_Composite_Consciousness.2C_Alan_Turing_centenary_exhibition"&gt;discover&lt;/a&gt; a bug in the timeline. 2031 should read &lt;strong&gt;2050&lt;/strong&gt;, 100 years after Turing publishes &lt;a href="http://mind.oxfordjournals.org/content/LIX/236/433.full.pdf+html" title="I propose to consider the question, 'Can machines think?' -- Turing's classic paper is published in 1950"&gt;Computing Machinery and Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, the paper in which he considers the question &amp;#8220;Can machines think?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details on &lt;a href="http://criticalpracticechelsea.org/wiki/index.php?title=Arnolfini_timeline#2050._Almost_Real:_Composite_Consciousness.2C_Alan_Turing_centenary_exhibition"&gt;Almost Real&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Composite Consciousness is a gift, a gift that constitutes the social identity of those that reciprocate, and in that reciprocation, the gift is the interval (the difference) between those present, and those not. The time of the disinterested gift is the time of memory &amp;#8212; it shifts the present into the future, or recollects the past into the present.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chanceprojects/5489369988/" title="20 timeline by neil cummings, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5020/5489369988_d7fd717347.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="20 timeline"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/alan-turing-centenary-exhibition-at-the-arnolfini</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/alan-turing-centenary-exhibition-at-the-arnolfini</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol Half Marathon, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The half marathon I enjoyed most was the first one I ran, the Bath half, back in &amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not even sure, 12 years ago? I didn&amp;#8217;t know if I&amp;#8217;d be able to finish because I hadn&amp;#8217;t run the distance in training, so I started slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the race progressed I realised I &lt;strong&gt;would&lt;/strong&gt; finish, no problem, and I remember overtaking people in the second loop and sprinting the last stretch along Great Pulteney Street, crossing the line with a time of 1:42:15. Oh, I felt just great!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I&amp;#8217;ve run a few more half marathons and at each one I&amp;#8217;ve gone faster. At first I hacked chunks from my personal best but as time went on I was reduced to chipping away smaller gains. In 2003 I went below an hour and a half at Bristol, beating Steve Cram. In 2006 I returned to Bath and clocked &lt;a href="bath_half_2006.pdf"&gt;1:23:14&lt;/a&gt;. Wow! I didn&amp;#8217;t think I could better that but running the same event in 2007 I got down to 1:21:58 &amp;#8212; which meant running the first 9 miles at a speed of 6 minutes and 15 seconds per mile and then running the final 4 miles at the same speed, even though at every step every bit of me wanted it to end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day I retired from half marathons. I couldn&amp;#8217;t go any faster and I couldn&amp;#8217;t face up to going any slower and I hurt and I had had enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept running though. Cross country is my favourite, all weather, all terrain. I started going out with a group close to where I live, on Gower. Sand dunes, wooded tracks, marshland. Cefn Bryn from all faces. I joined a club in Bristol, where I work, threading through the alleyways and parkland of North Bristol. Then I hooked up with some friends for training runs on Wednesday lunchtimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gavinedmonds/5830288813/" title="GBR_1140 by Gavin Edmonds, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5152/5830288813_bf2b13d048_z.jpg" width="426" height="640" alt="GBR_1140"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, 6 March 2011, and friends from all of these groups were running the Bath half marathon. The weather was good. I was in fine form. As I said in an email to Andy:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m thinking my build-up for the Bath half has been pretty much perfect, except for my failure to enter, that is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andy went on to finish the race in a time of 1:21:51 &amp;#8212; fully half a second a mile faster than I&amp;#8217;d ever run. That did it! Later that week I signed up for the Bristol half marathon, to be run on September 11th 2011.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years since I&amp;#8217;ve been away, the Bristol half has become a huge event. I&amp;#8217;d been assigned a white number which meant I&amp;#8217;d be starting in the first section of the first wave. It still took me over 30 seconds to pass beneath the start line and I spent the first couple of miles dodging joggers with ipods and sharp elbowed veterans. Beneath the suspension bridge the race stretched out. I galloped along the portway. Soon after doubling back at Shirehampton I pulled alongside someone I knew.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Is that Neil?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Tom, How&amp;#8217;s it going?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Too damn fast. I&amp;#8217;m going too fast.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Nah, you&amp;#8217;re fine!&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shook my head. I &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt; going too fast but I couldn&amp;#8217;t slow down. Even though I was hurting and hadn&amp;#8217;t even gone halfway I let momentum take me past Neil and on to Spike Island. Already I wanted it over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route came back to the centre of town then cruelly swerved out again on an unwelcome tour of the sights. Great for spectators. Cobbles. Ramps. &lt;a href="http://www.seenoevilbristol.co.uk/"&gt;Grafitti&lt;/a&gt;. I was being overtaken. Falling away. Neil came smoothly past.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well done mate,&amp;#8221; I muttered.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;400m to go. At least I had space around me. Noone passed me in the final straight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pressed the button on my stop watch and collapsed, wiped out. I hurt and I knew I was going to hurt more tomorrow and the day after. There was Neil. I eased up on to my feet, started moving, slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6137800028/" title="1:22:14.94 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6076/6137800028_a469bae0a1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:22:14.94"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:22:14 my watch said.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the event has grown bigger they&amp;#8217;ve figured out how to organise it. You aren&amp;#8217;t allowed to pile-up round the finish line snatching goodie bags and hugging loved ones. They keep the exhausted, elated runners moving past a succession of hand-outs: space blanket, water, medal, banana, T-shirt, energy drink, leaflet, bag &amp;#8230; and after this personal awards ceremony you emerge light-headed into the sunshine in millenium square.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil ran 1:22:06, comfortably. For him, this was a training run: he&amp;#8217;s looking for a fast time in Stroud. My official time, &lt;a href="http://www.runbristol.com/SearchResults.aspx"&gt;online now&lt;/a&gt;, is 1:22:15. That&amp;#8217;s over a second a mile slower than I&amp;#8217;ve run before. I give in.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-09-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Statues on the move</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5790058076/" title="Please give generously by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2224/5790058076_27f7c7efe1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Please give generously"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not every day you see a 6.7m statue being lifted on to a balcony so this morning I happily sat in the sunshine to watch the installation of Damien Hirst&amp;#8217;s Charity at the RWA.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5790056980/" title="Unveiled by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5147/5790056980_babc3ac3a1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Unveiled"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First the tarpaulins were pulled off her. The main crane made a blind pass, registering the location of the plinth on the balcony, judging the required extension. Now they attached chains around her neck and at the base, padding the neck with blankets. The strapping which fastened her to the trailer was removed removed. Slowly slowly she rose from supporting timbers on the tailer. They lowered her to the gound and tilted her on to her feet. The foreman wore a golden hat. It all seemed calm and controlled. Clearances were small. The pavement stayed open.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5789654042/" title="Charity on her way up by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5149/5789654042_82ffd4dbe6.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Charity on her way up"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to BBC Bristol &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-bristol-13502198" title="BBC Bristol reports: Damien Hirst's 22ft Charity statue coming to Bristol"&gt;Charity will be here for a year&lt;/a&gt;, adding:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The RWA said Bristol-born Hirst has &amp;#8220;scuffed her appearance and burgled her charity box to highlight the erosion of society&amp;#8217;s values&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the big statue rose slowly into position, smaller sculptures left the building, pushed out on trailers and bundled into the back of a van. The David Backhouse exhibition had ended.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the end too for the Backhouse sculpture so recently installed in the RWA forecourt. &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-bristol-13593918"&gt;Vandals had succeeded&lt;/a&gt; in separating the two figures at the top of the sculpture from the one at the base. Today, the base figure was unbolted from her low plinth then lifted and strapped down on an open trailer where the other two, who had been wrapped in sacking and left on the floor outside the building, rejoined her. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5789502725/" title="Broken and on the way out by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3483/5789502725_b983ab4680.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="Broken and on the way out"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-06-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/statues-on-the-move</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/statues-on-the-move</link>
<category>Bristol</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
