<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Jess Coulson, British half-marathon champion</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Strangely I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten the pain suffered in the final miles of the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races"&gt;Cardiff half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. What pain? I&amp;#8217;ll run it again and get the PB I missed by 10 seconds!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the event I caught up with the coverage on &lt;a href="http://bbc.in/1M9iTp2"&gt;iplayer&lt;/a&gt;. I knew the headlines &amp;#8212; that Kenyan athletes had won both the men&amp;#8217;s and women&amp;#8217;s race &amp;#8212; but didn&amp;#8217;t know how. Both races turned out to be fascinating and thrilling to watch, the women&amp;#8217;s race especially.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed the race would follow a standard script with the leader, Jerotich, ratcheting the pressure until she dropped her rivals, and then holding on. Soon after 10K a winning margin was established. The commentators were struggling to find anything to say. The kilometers ticked down. Jerotich runs with that efficient style the top endurance runners employ; quick, shuffling strides, feet barely clearing the tarmac. As a spectator you can sense the long hard miles of training and the long hard miles to come.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bbc.in/1M9iTp2"&gt;&lt;img width="640" src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/jerotich-areba-coulson.jpg" alt="jerotich areba coulson"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live coverage returned to the women&amp;#8217;s race coming along the straight road back from Roath. The winning margin remained in place, though it hadn&amp;#8217;t extended. Jerotich was frowning. What the commentators failed to notice was a yellow vest in the background. It could, of course, have been an elite male runner making a late surge, but the mystery athlete&amp;#8217;s hair was gathered into a swaying top-knot. Now the cameras went back to her. It&amp;#8217;s Rebecca Robinson, said the commentators, wrongly. It was Jess Coulson making her competitive half marathon debut and she was motoring, bouncing off her toes, eating the gap to the second runner, Areba. Wasteful, the commentators tutted, arms flapping all over the place. Maybe, but fast, gutsy and exciting to watch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess Coulson&amp;#8217;s effort brought the race back together. With 400m to go, suddenly three runners were in it. If Coulson wanted second place she may have struck a fraction early, passing Areba on the final left hander &amp;#8212; but she wanted first. It wasn&amp;#8217;t to be. Jerotich had something left and held on for the win; Areba came back for second; Coulson got third. Great race!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/jess-coulson-british-halfmarathon-champion</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/jess-coulson-british-halfmarathon-champion</link>
<category>Cardiff</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>One week, three races</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I DNF the Cardiff half marathon. This year I went one worse and DNS the Swansea half. Consequently I was determined to turn up in good shape to complete this year&amp;#8217;s Cardiff half.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racing the week before probably wasn&amp;#8217;t a great idea &amp;#8230; but the race happened to be a short one and close to home &amp;#8230; and the weather was perfect &amp;#8230; and I hadn&amp;#8217;t raced in a while &amp;#8230; and Alex didn&amp;#8217;t have a rugby game and &amp;#8230; well, I went! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Llandmadoc is the first fixture of the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk"&gt;West Glamorgan cross country league&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s four and a half miles, out along a woodland trail then back on the beach. I tried to run within myself on the outward section and fell in with Peter Osborne, another V50 who I&amp;#8217;ve battled with on several occasions. He upped the pace as we hit the sloping sand around the point and then he was gone. Coming back along the beach in the blazing sun, there was a gap of 50m to the next group of runners &amp;#8212; a gap I reduced but never closed. Despite my conservative start, when we went through the wet sand I felt as energetic as one of the many stranded jellyfish which littered the course. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href="http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=147384&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Llanmadoc&amp;amp;date=27-Sep-15"&gt;finished 19th in a time of 28:32&lt;/a&gt;, officially first in my category but second really since Peter beat me and he&amp;#8217;s an age band up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21803789231/in/photostream/" title="Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5722/21803789231_138ac20159_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I avoided the track training session with Bristol and West on Monday evening &amp;#8212; the same session, last year, had been one too many. If I&amp;#8217;d had doubts about running the cross country race just a week before the half marathon, my main target for the year, then I had real concerns about testing myself at the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolandwestac.org/aztec-west-fast-5k/"&gt;Aztec West 5K&lt;/a&gt; on the Tuesday. I felt I was running well and knew a PB was possible on the fast Aztec West course, but did I want to know just how well I was running? A slow time would have rocked my confidence before Sunday&amp;#8217;s longer race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I went. As for times, I had no idea during the race because I forgot my watch. In contrast to Llanmadoc, my legs felt strong, decidedly sprightly in fact. I settled in with Will Smith and Paul Deaton, friends from Southville Running Club, and we barreled round the three lap course, overtaking some very decent runners who&amp;#8217;d started more quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21875414812/in/photostream/" title="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5816/21875414812_10a39d89f2_z.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21264629634/in/photostream/" title="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/569/21264629634_b53ab1d8aa_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will accelerated with 200m to go, attacking the next three runners, and Paul went with him. I let them go. After the final sharp left, Paul faded, enough encouragement for me to sprint past him. When the &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=146231&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Sep-15"&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; were announced I discovered I&amp;#8217;d won the V50 category with a PB of 17:22.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-footer="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21861865806/in/photostream/" title="Aztec West 5K. Charge for the line"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/728/21861865806_aa925a0096_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Charge for the line"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Cardiff. The race is bigger than ever &amp;#8212; twenty two thousand entrants in 2015. Despite this, it was straightforward getting to the start line warmed up and ready. The elite athletes (including me!) have their own baggage drop round the back of the castle in Bute Park. From there, it&amp;#8217;s a short stroll to the right start pen. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/406748447/embed/9e8c528271c129e91657b724a243c43d982c9342'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t think I set off too quickly but my 10K time was 37:10, on target for a 78:30 finish. I guess my legs were still dialled into my 5K pace. Ifan had set out even more quickly, but I caught him around the half way point. In a half marathon I usually feel a glow during the middle of the event; the sensation that I&amp;#8217;m going fast, but at a sustainable tempo. This time, the sensation never came. I wasn&amp;#8217;t glowing, I was aching. Enduring. Maintaining a steady pace seemed impossible and I found myself repeatedly dropping then being passed by the same group of runners. Why couldn&amp;#8217;t we team up and work together? I went through 10 miles in 1:00:25, still on course for a personal best but hurting badly. Ifan went past me again at around mile 11. I didn&amp;#8217;t even try and go with him. My muscles were sore, my feet were sore. I knew I&amp;#8217;d complete the course but I was no longer shooting for a personal best; I just wanted to finish without losing too much time. Actually, I just wanted to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the final turn I realised that 80 minutes was still on and managed to sprint for the line. My time, 79:43, was just 7 seconds off my PB.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</link>
<category>Cardiff</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cross country catch up</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I posted these old race reports &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Inter-Regional &amp;amp; Masters Championships, Builth Wells, December 10th 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did say, at the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011.html"&gt;Fairwood race&lt;/a&gt;, I was invited to represent West Wales in the &lt;a href="http://www.welshathletics.org/competitions/events/cross-country/2011/12-dec/welsh-inter-regional-cross-country-championships.aspx"&gt;inter-regional championships&lt;/a&gt;? Well, the day had come, a chill December morning. White frost coated the meadow at Parkmill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ifan took the scenic route through Llandeilo and LLandovery &amp;#8230; I sank back into the passenger seat and watched the hills roll by. We parked outside the showground and crunched across ice and gravel to the race HQ where the tarpaulin they&amp;#8217;d laid down on the floor was already rucked and muddy. Red and white tapes zig-zagged up the hill, marking out the course.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collected my West Wales vest. When you get a heavy course, like today, one which includes sections of concrete and tarmac, Ifan said, use longer spikes here and shorter ones here, under the ball of the foot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just over an hour to go we jogged a warm-up lap, starting with an extended climb through the woods. You can push on here, he said, as we emerged from the trees and passed a static caravan, still climbing, it&amp;#8217;s downhill for a while after this. At the summit stood an enormous speaker, part of the showground&amp;#8217;s PA system. I could see the Builth Wells showground now &amp;#8212; the timber-clad buildings, the neat field, the high boundary fence &amp;#8212; like a stage in the centre of the immense ampitheatre formed by the surrounding hills.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunlight poked through the clouds as we lined up at the start, shivering, edgy. One short lap and two long ones. I found my place and settled in. On the first climb my way was blocked by a tall runner. I moved left to overtake. He moved left. I moved right. He moved right. I passed him by the caravan and extended my lead downhill. Briefly, our route intersected the U15 girls&amp;#8217; race and I was dodging elbows, legs, pony-tails. On the long flat section round the playing fields the tall runner pegged me back. I let him go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching the climb for the second time, the ground had softened. I went past a couple of runners who&amp;#8217;d gone out too fast. I dug in as the path steepened, skeetering wide through tree roots, leaf mould and brambles to pass him. I was clear now but there were two more in front to aim at. I remembered Ifan&amp;#8217;s advice and stumbled over the top on empty, relying on gravity to recharge my legs on the descent. I bounded down a final rocky path, arms flailing, and held on till the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6955236875/" title="13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7202/6955236875_2d6a00c8d9.jpg" width="500" height="335" alt="13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;West Glamorgan League, Margam, January 8th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/4.html"&gt;Margam&lt;/a&gt; at eleven in time to see the race start without me. Lesson being, the West Glamorgan races are organised differently. The sight of all those humans on the move had animated the park&amp;#8217;s deer herd. I watched them hurtle round their own short course. I ran the route anyway, slowly, and very boggy it was too. Next time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cardiff Cross Challenge, January 15th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://cardiffxchallenge.wordpress.com/the-event/"&gt;McCain Cardiff cross challenge&lt;/a&gt;, held just north of the city centre in Blackweir Fields, is &amp;#8220;one of the most prestigious Cross Country events in the UK&amp;#8221;. Isobel was running. Last time she&amp;#8217;d run, in the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011.html"&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt;, around a foul course in filthy weather, she&amp;#8217;d failed to finish, so it was a crucial event for her. We arrived in good time and registered. She&amp;#8217;d be wearing her Afan-Nedd-Tawe vest. I&amp;#8217;d be running for Swansea Harriers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the going looked fine. The sun was out, the wind was down. The course was flat, dry, sheltered. Isobel had a solid run, finishing strongly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, they&amp;#8217;d fine-tuned the schedule, overlapping races, closing and opening routes through the parkland, somehow without any runners getting trampled, confused or impeded, and so it was that the senior men&amp;#8217;s event, the last of the day, would be starting just an hour after Isobel had finished. With 5 minutes to go I made my way to the starting pen. Where was everyone? Suddenly the elite runners appeared, peeling off thermals, shaking long, elastic legs. We&amp;#8217;d be running four times round. I realised I was in danger of getting lapped.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/IwVLNiAQYps?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily I avoided any such ignominy. The course seemed tame &amp;#8212; where were the hills, swamps, trenches, wild animals? Isobel injected some welcome variety, appearing at random positions to cheer me on, and her encouragement helped me maintain my pace and place. I did pass one runner on the final lap and pushed hard to close the gap on the next, a tall lad in a black vest, but, closing in on the finish, he kicked away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Cross Country Championships, St Fagans, February 18th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6910503621/" title="Start and finished by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7053/6910503621_5807ae1e07.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Start and finished"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Torrential rain and wind during the morning made for very difficult conditions on an already tough course for the 108th running of the Welsh Cross Country Championships. While the junior races were run in these treacherous conditions, the rain had stopped by the time the senior athletes were on the starting line; the damage to the course, however, was already done. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.welshathletics.org/news--media/news/cross-country/2012/02-feb/jones-and-griffiths-clinch-cross-country-welsh-titles.aspx"&gt;Welsh Athletics race report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hats off to Isobel for getting round this one. She lasted longer than the inflatable start and finish markers, which were swiftly deflated and packed away before the wind ripped them up. After, she went with Gail and Alex to visit the &lt;a href="http://www.museumwales.ac.uk/en/stfagans/"&gt;National History Museum&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain had indeed stopped by the time the men&amp;#8217;s race started but the course was brutal. I slogged my way round one, two, three, four laps, and was glad when it ended. I pulled my bag from the mud and squelched back through the field to the road-side, texting Gail to collect me.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-06-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</link>
<category>Cardiff</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cardiff Half, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Michael&amp;#8217;s Tom Tom guided us from the M4 to Grangetown Station. We parked alongside the Taff. Michael ate a banana and changed into his Swansea City shorts, which he thought appropriate since the route would be passing &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=85440788632" title="Cardiff FC's stadium looks like legoland!!!"&gt;Legoland&lt;/a&gt;. We made fall-back plans where to meet after then set off on foot, falling into line with the gathering crowds heading the same way. Ahead rose the metallic curve of the national arts centre, gleaming in the sunlight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisbewick/2530299841/" title="Wales Millenium Centre by Chris Bewick, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3082/2530299841_d018dd7422.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Wales Millenium Centre"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it say on the front? That&amp;#8217;s a classic pub quiz question.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the stones sing in silence. I don&amp;#8217;t know. Something like that. It&amp;#8217;s in Welsh and English.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; ?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on then, what does it say?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know either, Michael admitted. Now we were right there beneath the imposing lettering but didn&amp;#8217;t bother checking. The runners village was swarming with runners getting ready. We had to prepare.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plas Roald Dahl is built on a scale to accommodate 15000 runners and supporters &amp;#8212; excepting toilet facilities. Queues for the portaloos folded back on themselves. We shook hands and separated. With half an hour to go I stripped off and deposited my kit bag. I made my way to the start, down to the waterfront, left, past the Senedd, left again, then tried to find the right starting pen. My number was blue, meaning an expected finishing time between 1:20 and 1:30. The instructions from the PA alternated between English and Welsh, happily noting the sun had come out, there was no wind, the route was flat &amp;#8212; the event record could well be broken.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In amongst the packed athletes I discovered Mike Rimmer, Mark, Pippa and Michael (again). They were huddled close to the 1:30 pace-maker. Push up, Mike ordered, and I don&amp;#8217;t want to see you till the end of the race! I squeezed and twisted and wriggled a few metres forward then gave up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a welcome message from the mayor we were off, shuffling, walking, striding, jogging, running. After &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html" title="Bristol half marathon, 2011, when I got my pace all wrong"&gt;Bristol&lt;/a&gt;, I took it easy to begin with, settling into the race rather than wasting energy trying to weave through the pack. Soon the roads broadened, proper city avenues and boulevards, and I could run my own pace.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro-cyclist David Millar recently tweeted about his specialism, time-trialling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;TT&amp;#8217;s are weird. Imagine the best long-distance runners being set off at 1min intervals to TT 20km. Be considered mad. Cycling = Madness. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125523908874084353"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A TT generally involves the athlete emptying their tank completely in order to post the fastest time they are physically capable of. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125528302248136704"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A mass-start race involves tactics and economising of effort in order to cross the finish-line first. Winner often the freshest at the end. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125529177037348864"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting, as far as it goes &amp;#8212; but in a regular bike race tactics and positioning are paramount and in athletics a strong athlete can run off the front. For me, the half marathon is a time trial. I&amp;#8217;m racing against the clock and emptying the tank. I look for the mile markers and check my time as I pass them. A 6:10 pace would bring me in at around 1 hour and 21 minutes, just under.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miles 8 and 9, the route heads in then out on the same arterial road, doubling back at a spectator-packed roundabout. It gives you a chance to watch faster runners, some really fast runners &amp;#8212; and to appreciate the scale of the event. Go on Ifan! I shouted. His head stayed down, he was working hard. He&amp;#8217;d heard me. My legs still felt good. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At mile 10 there&amp;#8217;s a climb. It&amp;#8217;s not so steep but it&amp;#8217;s long enough and it comes at just the wrong stage of the race. I&amp;#8217;d slipped a few seconds. The arithmetic was getting harder. Dig in!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gordonplant/2705863581/" title="Cardiff Bay by gordonplant, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3260/2705863581_e4ce2d5006.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Cardiff Bay"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the final stretch, along the Cardiff Bay barrage. You&amp;#8217;re exposed to the wind but today there wasn&amp;#8217;t any, just a fabulous approach to the capital, towards the Norwegian Church, the Assembly, the &lt;a href="http://images.google.com/search?tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=cardiff+armadillo"&gt;Armadillo&lt;/a&gt;. Those efforts along the Avon towpath, the interval sessions on Oxwich beach &amp;#8212; now they make sense: you know how it feels to run at tempo when legs are burning and lungs are heaving. I was going to do it!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6329991144/" title="1:21:31.07 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6053/6329991144_2e8410288b.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:21:31.07"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:21:31:07 it said on my watch. My official chip time, received in a text message an hour or so later, was 1:21:30, a personal best by almost half a minute. I was wiped out but not hurting, not like &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html" title="Bristol half marathon, 2011, when I got my pace all wrong"&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d finished 110th.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6330006162/" title="Cardiff half marathon 2011 race results for Thomas Guest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6117/6330006162_8acba32865.jpg" width="500" height="321" alt="Cardiff half marathon 2011 race results for Thomas Guest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gordonplant/" title="gordonplant's photostream, on flickr"&gt;gordonplant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisbewick"&gt;Chris Bewick&lt;/a&gt; for allowing me to use their fine photos of Cardiff Bay and the Millenium Centre in this article.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cardiff-half-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cardiff-half-2011</link>
<category>Cardiff</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
