<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Following the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As ever, I&amp;#8217;m watching the Tour de France &amp;#8212; or maybe I should say I&amp;#8217;m &lt;strong&gt;following&lt;/strong&gt; the tour, since I get much of my fix online, direct from &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/geraintthomas86" title="Geraint Thomas"&gt;riders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://inrng.com" title="The Inner Ring"&gt;commentators&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com" title="Cycling News"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I like the mountain stages. The scenery, the history, the combat. Winners and losers. The Pyrenees have disappointed with the favourites marking each other and no one prepared to make a sustained attack. We had this in 2010, and we still don&amp;#8217;t know who won that race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll on the Alps. As &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/inrng" title="The Inner Ring, on Twitter"&gt;@inrng&lt;/a&gt; points out, the &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage19" title="Inner Ring analysis of stage 19"&gt;Alpe d&amp;#8217;Huez stage is just under 110km&lt;/a&gt;, a sprint. Andy Schleck: don&amp;#8217;t look back!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2011/jul/09/team-sky-bradley-wiggins"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2011/7/9/1310205980831/Team-Skys-Bradley-Wiggins-007.jpg" alt="Bradley Wiggins, crashed out on stage 7"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrible to see Bradley Wiggins collapsed on the tarmac nursing a broken collarbone and knowing his race was over. What if? He&amp;#8217;d shed so much weight in preparation for the mountains there wasn&amp;#8217;t much left of him but what remained &amp;#8212; self-belief, humour, quality &amp;#8212; well, the climbers wouldn&amp;#8217;t have dropped him and he&amp;#8217;d have smashed them in the final time trial. There may yet be positives. Geraint Thomas is off the leash and riding with flair and abandon. He&amp;#8217;s no threat in the GC and could well grab a breakaway stage. Team Sky will build and regroup and throw everything at the Vuelta where Wiggo could yet become the first Briton to win a Grand Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the flatter stages have provided better racing. Cavendish has been a great winner. He also lost well, to Greipel, just the once. For the fourth consecutive year, he&amp;#8217;s fastest. Victory margins haven&amp;#8217;t been massive but to end up in green you have to run a marathon and a sprint, repeatedly. Is all about conserving energy. He can do it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Liggett and Paul Sherwen are putting in a solid performance. Ned Boulting too. Chris Boardman sounds dull, especially when voicing the sponsors&amp;#8217; messages which bookend the ad breaks:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve often wondered, why do they have second and third place on the podium? &amp;#8230; Yellow isn&amp;#8217;t a colour, it&amp;#8217;s a state of mind &amp;#8230; When my team had to lift me off my bike at the end of a stage, I knew I&amp;#8217;d done enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take (some of) it back about Chris Boardman: his analysis of &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage16"&gt;stage 16&lt;/a&gt;, the one which finished with a treacherous descent into Gap, was spot on. There&amp;#8217;s Andy Schleck moaning people don&amp;#8217;t want to see a race won downhill, yet he hasn&amp;#8217;t raced uphill either, not really. Or as CB described it: throwing the toys out of his pram.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 11, sprint battle</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What battle? Understandably lost in the controversy is the fact that Mark Cavendish has roared back into the form he had last year. He leapt away from the pack and took the stage comfortably. No, the real battle was 500m from the line, fought between Cav&amp;#8217;s lead-out man, Mark Renshaw from HTC Columbia, and Julian Dean from Garmin-Transitions. You could see it coming &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;d been barging and shoving on very a fast run-in. Everyone was wound up tight. Dean cut across Renshaw. Either Renshaw had to back down, or he had to force Dean away, or there&amp;#8217;d be an almighty pile-up. Renshaw was furious. He lost his head. He used his head, butting Dean three times with it. Then &amp;#8212; and this did not look good &amp;#8212; he cut in front of Tyler Farrar, the Garmin-Transitions sprinter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this happened in a couple of seconds, at high speed. It did look brutal. At least no one got hurt, but the judges came down hard. Mark Renshaw has been eliminated from the Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sprint finish is all about the individual who gets to the line first, but it&amp;#8217;s also all about the team. Cavendish always stresses his wins are team victories: the HTC Columbia train sets him up, he just has to finish the job. HTC Columbia had already lost one rider, Adam Hansen, on stage 2, evidently without too many adverse effects, but can they do without the world&amp;#8217;s best lead-out man, Mark Renshaw? More importantly, how will Cav respond? He&amp;#8217;s hot-headed and impetuous. I hope he doesn&amp;#8217;t do something stupid.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-11-sprint-battle.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-11-sprint-battle.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Stages 0 and 1</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Chapeau, &lt;a href="http://www.itv.com/sport/tourdefrance/"&gt;ITV4&lt;/a&gt;, for the live coverage, even if I can&amp;#8217;t see myself getting to watch much of it. The prologue stage has definitely whetted the appetite. I&amp;#8217;m pleased Cancellara won. &amp;#8220;My body worked at 100% for exactly ten minutes,&amp;#8221; he said. It&amp;#8217;s almost unthinkable that another expert clock-racer, Brad Wiggins, could drop almost a minute over such a short course, but he did. I&amp;#8217;ve read Wiggo&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Pursuit-Glory-Autobiography-Bradley-Wiggins/dp/0752884034"&gt;In Pursuit of Glory: The Autobiography&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; one for the fans, I think, but one thing I did take from it was how accurately Wiggo can calibrate his form on the track. He knows how long it takes for him to ride a kilometre in a covered velodrome to within a second. A wet road in Rotterdam is less predictable, and Wiggo wanted to avoid trouble. Cancellara has more panache and his bike-handling skills are sans pareil. So he won. Can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him attack the &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;cobbled roads&lt;/a&gt; in stage 3.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com/2010/04/09/2/img_0669_600.jpg" alt="Going. To. Be. Carnage"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hardened campaigner got going when the going got tough. Armstrong took a chunk out of Wiggins and other GC rivals in the &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr/2010/TDF/LIVE/us/0/classement/index.html"&gt;prologue&lt;/a&gt;. He also got the first strike in against Contador (let&amp;#8217;s not forget that he lost 22 seconds to the Spaniard over the same stage last year). I&amp;#8217;ll bet he rattles Contador some more on the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/17414049508"&gt;cobbles&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking forwards to the highlights of Stage One this evening, especially when it became obvious it would end with a bunch sprint. About time to see Cavendish stretch his legs. Except it didn&amp;#8217;t happen like that. Cav has had a rotten run-in to the Tour this year. Always volatile and unpredictable, he&amp;#8217;s turning into very a loose cannon. He tumbled on the final bend taking out rival Oscar Freire. Last year no one got close to Cav. And this year other riders would do well to stay away from him. With Cav down the other riders had to improvise the final kilometre and they made a spectacular mess of it, staging a mass pile up instead of a mass sprint. Quelle horreur!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Someone race Cavendish, please</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/routes/overseas/345690/etape-du-tour-2009-route-recce.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/e/etape-2.jpg" width="540px" height="360px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France takes a rest today (though not for the riders in the &amp;Eacute;tape du Tour, who&amp;#8217;ll take on Mont Ventoux six days before the pros), giving me a chance to try and make sense of a strange and compelling weekend of racing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;#8217;s short sharp climb to Verbier made perfect sense and settled a few outstanding questions. Noone climbs like Contador, and the Madrile&amp;ntilde;o confirmed his position as race favourite and Astana team leader. The way he dances up the steepest slopes is truly thrilling. I can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him climb Ventoux. Armstrong rode with the elite riders, but I&amp;#8217;d say Kl&amp;ouml;den may well be shaping up as the Astana number 2 &amp;#8212; he&amp;#8217;s a strong time trial rider who looked in fine shape on the climb, edging Armstrong at the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about Brad Wiggins? &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/blog/2009/jul/19/bradley-wiggins-tour-de-france"&gt;Shedding 9% of his bodyweight&lt;/a&gt; has morphed him from track rider into Grand Tour contender. Best of all, he&amp;#8217;s enjoying himself. I think he could come out of Thursday&amp;#8217;s time trial &amp;#8212; his favourite discipline &amp;#8212; as Contador&amp;#8217;s main rival for yellow. Awesome!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/14/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france-stage-10"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2009/7/14/1247596770216/Mark-Cavendish-001.jpg" alt="Why isn't Cav in green?" width="460px" height="276px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday&amp;#8217;s stage was more complex. I&amp;#8217;m struggling to understand what Mark Cavendish was playing at. Cavendish already has a remarkable 4 stage victories in this year&amp;#8217;s Tour, matching the 4 he took last year. Well, the number is remarkable, but this year the sprint finishes have seemed routine: the Columbia train leads him out over the final few kilometres, then his team-mates peel away in sequence leaving him to deliver the killer blow. The trouble is, Cavendish&amp;#8217;s rivals have already rolled over and died.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Sport evolves and, if you go back to the 1970s, I never, ever had a lead-out man, not once,&amp;#8221; Hoban said this week. &amp;#8220;Everyone was there, man to man. The way they do it now, with a team like that, if they are leading out at 65kph very few people are going to come over that. Anyone to challenge Mark going at 65kph has got to do 70kph.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/19/tour-de-france-history-hoban-cavendish"&gt;Barry Hoban&lt;/a&gt;, quoted in the Observer newspaper
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d have thought this supremacy would leave Cavendish way out in front in the green jersey but he hasn&amp;#8217;t chased enough intermediate sprints. This leaves him (left him) head to head with the mighty Thor Hushovd in the points competition. My opinion? I don&amp;#8217;t think Cavendish relishes scrabbling for points and it&amp;#8217;s brought out his petulant side.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He says he&amp;#8217;s fastest. His rivals admit he&amp;#8217;s fastest. He is fastest. But he still wants a race!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we had a strange situation. Popular Columbia rider, George Hincapie, was in a breakaway and had a realistic shot at yellow. So team Columbia wanted to slow the chase. But team Columbia also wanted Cavendish to win the peloton sprint for the points given to the 13th place finisher; and so, once more, the train chugged down the final kilometre with everyone watching the clock. Cavendish barely bothered to race for the line. Yes, he blocked Hushovd when he could and should have flown away from him. He wanted to win but in as slow a time as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event Hincapie missed out on yellow by just 5 seconds. You can&amp;#8217;t blame Cavendish for that, but Cavendish is a team player and I suspect he cared more about his team missing yellow than his subsequent disqualification in the sprint. He just wasn&amp;#8217;t bothered about a race for 13th place.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, it&amp;#8217;s probably cost him the green jersey and taken the edge off the showdown next Sunday. I hope he stops feeling hard done by and comes out ready to race. I know he cares more about being fastest on the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es than the points competition.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-20</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Attaque Armstrong!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/1/10162216-073.jpg" width="540px" height="340px" alt="On the same team?"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France 2009 is shaping up to be a truly great race. Any pretence that the Astana team is led by race favourite, Contador, has been dropped &amp;#8212; by Armstrong at least. The tough-talking Texan has spoken in several interviews about the team having more than one leader, in his (singletrack-)mind at least.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armstrong&amp;#8217;s legs did the talking on Monday, a flat 3rd stage of the race. Usually the peleton would stick together on such a stage and it would end with a bunch sprint, probably won by Cavendish, and there would be no changes to the general classification (i.e. the yellow jersey competition).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cavendish did indeed win the sprint but the big news of the day was the break in the peleton, something which can happen in high winds. After the split Armstrong rode in the front group; with Contador in the second group. The split extended to 40 seconds and by the end of the day Armstrong led Contador in the race by some 20 seconds. In the post-race interview shown on ITV4, did Armstrong say he should have dropped back to help Contador? Hell no, he accused Contador of tactical naivety, gaining unexpected support from a disgruntled French rider.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frenchman Christophe Le Mevel claimed it was Contador&amp;#8217;s failure to stick to the wheel in front of him which caused the split with around 30km to go. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/8137119.stm"&gt;BBC Sport report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In yesterday&amp;#8217;s team trial the Astana team rode well together to win the stage, and came within &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/381945/tour-de-france-analysis-why-contador-s-chances-rose-when-armstrong-missed-yellow.html"&gt;tenths of a second&lt;/a&gt; of grabbing the yellow jersey for Armstrong.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to note that had the field not split on Monday, Contador would have been in yellow in Montpellier. Before the Columbia-led move, to which Armstrong and team-mates loyal to him gratefully contributed, Contador was just 18 seconds down overall. Had the bunch stayed together, he&amp;#8217;d have been in yellow by 22 seconds after the team time trial. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/381945/tour-de-france-analysis-why-contador-s-chances-rose-when-armstrong-missed-yellow.html"&gt;Cycling News&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contador still looks the man to beat and yesterday&amp;#8217;s team time trial has set him up well over many of his rivals. Let&amp;#8217;s not forget how well he did in the prologue; let&amp;#8217;s see how he fares in the mountains. Armstrong may be able to needle and even outsmart him, but I can&amp;#8217;t seem him outriding him in the Pyrenees, the real start of the yellow jersey competition.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rider, Armstrong has been admired and feared more than loved. He&amp;#8217;s determined and ruthless rather than charismatic. During his 7 Tour wins he stunned his rivals to the point they even failed to capitalise on his mistakes. I suspect he&amp;#8217;ll be depending on mistakes now, and I can&amp;#8217;t see Contador making another. What&amp;#8217;s more, Armstrong will need charisma and love in his future political career.  He is turning the 2009 Tour into a great race, but one he will ultimately fail to win, and he will speak  truth in defeat; and we will, at last, love him for it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/attaque-armstrong.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/attaque-armstrong.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mark Cavendish, le Mozart du onze-dents</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In a year (2008) when British cyclists cleaned up at the Beijing Olympics, the undoubted sporting highlight, for me, was Mark Cavendish winning 4 stages of the world&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr" title="Tour de France"&gt;greatest race&lt;/a&gt;. Leading out, chasing back, with his team, alone &amp;#8212; he dominated the sprint finishes, reading the final metres like no one else. He&amp;#8217;s an astonishing racer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember him being astonished, too, when he realised that despite crushing the other sprinters he trailed them in the points competition. Even if he made it over the Alps and on to Paris, winning yet more stages on the way, he wouldn&amp;#8217;t be wearing the coveted maillot vert. So he left, to prepare for the Olympics, a decision &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2008/nov/23/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france"&gt;he now describes as&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The biggest regret of my career&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thefirstpost.co.uk/47798,news,mark-cavendish-could-become-a-cycling-great"&gt;&lt;img src="http://photos.thefirstpost.co.uk/assets/library/426-cavendish--124332656686951800.jpg" alt="Mozart"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never really got the points competition. To be honest, I&amp;#8217;ve never cared much about it, preferring the more obvious excitement of the mountain stages, sprint finishes and time-trials, but &amp;#8230; well &amp;#8230; now we&amp;#8217;ve got a contender, things are different!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tour_de_France#Points_classification"&gt;points competition&lt;/a&gt; is more of a marathon than a sprint. For a start, you have to complete the race &amp;#8212; a feat requiring supreme endurance and not a little luck &amp;#8212; and over the course of three weeks you have to niggle and scrape points at every opportunity. The green jersey is about pacing yourself, restraint. It would seem a better fit for a calculating rider (Chris Boardman, say) than the instinctive, headstrong cyclist that is Mark Cavendish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else, though, Cavendish is stubborn. I&amp;#8217;m convinced his sights have been set on the maillot vert ever since the point last year when he realised he couldn&amp;#8217;t have it. I&amp;#8217;m sorry he&amp;#8217;s abandoned the Giro. I would have imagined completing the course to be the best possible preparation for &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr/indexus.html"&gt;July&lt;/a&gt;. How else can you learn what it feels like to race for 3500km split over 21 stages? 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thefirstpost.co.uk/47798,news,mark-cavendish-could-become-a-cycling-great"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/campag-casette.jpg" alt="Campagnolo casette with 11T sprocket"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;#8217;t know. Here&amp;#8217;s to seeing &lt;a href="http://www.thefirstpost.co.uk/47798,news,mark-cavendish-could-become-a-cycling-great" title="le Mozart du onze-dents"&gt;&amp;#8220;le Mozart du onze-dents&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; in green on the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-05-27</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mark-cavendish-le-mozart-du-onzedents.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mark-cavendish-le-mozart-du-onzedents.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mark Cavendish wins Milan San Remo</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Amazing, awesome result! The Milan San Remo classic &amp;#8212; 190 miles, the Poggio and Cipressa mountains, six hours in the saddle, average speed of 27 mph &amp;#8212; won by the width of a tyre. The way Mark Cavendish hunts down Heinrich Haussler and throws his bike at the line. Unbelievable, what a finish! I&amp;#8217;ve been hunting down the best video on YouTube. If you can forgive the naff music and cheesy words, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eCAUo-oUlj4"&gt;this montage&lt;/a&gt; nails the moment and its impact.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/eCAUo-oUlj4&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/eCAUo-oUlj4&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sad to say, news coverage here in the UK has been underwhelming. As Lance Armstrong tweets:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the Sunday Times Sports section on the flight. Pages and pages of rugby, soccer, cricket and barely a mention of Cavendish. Pitiful. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/1370874928"&gt;@lancearmstrong&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guardian sports blog has a &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/blog/2009/mar/24/richard-williams-column-mark-cavendish"&gt;good article&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can Mark Cavendish maintain this form? I think he&amp;#8217;s figured out how to finish the Tour de France in green!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-03-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mark-cavendish-wins-milan-san-remo.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mark-cavendish-wins-milan-san-remo.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mark Cavendish regrets</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2008/nov/23/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france"&gt;
   &lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Observer/Pix/pictures/2008/11/22/cavendish460x276.jpg" alt="Mark Cavendish"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2008/nov/23/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france"&gt;a fine interview with sprint champion Mark Cavendish&lt;/a&gt; in today&amp;#8217;s Observer. Despite British success in the Olympics, the most exciting sporting moments for me this year were Cavendish&amp;#8217;s 4 thrilling, awesome, stage victories in the Tour de France.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the TV interviews which followed these victories. After his 3rd stage win he was psyched up to make it all the way to Paris (something the sprint specialists don&amp;#8217;t always manage) and as &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour-completes-a-hattrick.html"&gt;I wrote at the time&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to see him storming round the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es &amp;#8212; if he gets there, he&amp;#8217;ll win the final stage too. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;But after his 4th stage win, he became subdued and tetchy, and all of a sudden he&amp;#8217;d quit the race to stay fresh for the Olympics. Ironically his Olympic partner in the Madison, Bradley Wiggins, was the one lacking freshness &amp;#8212; hardly surprising since he&amp;#8217;d already won two gold medals in the &lt;a href="http://en.beijing2008.cn/venues/lsv/index.shtml"&gt;Laoshan Velodrome&lt;/a&gt;, setting a world record in the process &amp;#8212; and Cavendish now regrets his decision.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;The biggest regret of my career is quitting the Tour de France,&amp;#8217; Cavendish continues, looking back on his decision to leave this year&amp;#8217;s race after stage 14 so that he would be fresh for the Olympics. &amp;#8216;I feel massively let down, I&amp;#8217;m still bitter now. To leave the Tour de France to do that. You sit there, sit there, you&amp;#8217;re the last event on, every single member of the team has got a medal, the pressure&amp;#8217;s on you and, boom, it goes. You don&amp;#8217;t get it, even though I still think I was the best rider on the track. It&amp;#8217;s quite hard to accept really.&amp;#8217;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.beijing2008.cn/venues/lsv/index.shtml"&gt;&lt;img src="http://images.beijing2008.cn/20071206/Img214210796.jpg" alt="Laoshan velodrome"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-11-23</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mark-cavendish-regrets.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mark-cavendish-regrets.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>No stopping Mark Cavendish</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;That makes &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; once he hit the front there was no stopping him as he confirmed his status as the fastest finisher on the planet. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/7514166.stm"&gt;BBC Sport&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/no-stopping-mark-cavendish.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/no-stopping-mark-cavendish.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Fastest sprinter in the Tour completes a hat-trick!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.markcavendish.com"&gt;&lt;img width="500px" src="http://www.markcavendish.com/images/banner1.jpg" alt="Mark Cavendish"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another classic finish as the Tour hurtled at top speed into the centre of Narbonne today. &lt;a href="http://www.markcavendish.com"&gt;Mark Cavendish&lt;/a&gt; crossed the line first, which means he&amp;#8217;s won more stages in a single Tour than anyone else from the UK. I knew he&amp;#8217;d do it, but I didn&amp;#8217;t know he&amp;#8217;d do it so soon after Saturday&amp;#8217;s awesome display of power. The big question now: Can he make it over the Alps? A freak accident made the Pyrennees tough going, and he had to dig deep today. I&amp;#8217;d love to see him storming round the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es &amp;#8212; if he gets there, he&amp;#8217;ll win the final stage too. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-17</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour-completes-a-hattrick.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour-completes-a-hattrick.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Fastest sprinter in the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/7503565.stm"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" src="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/44827000/jpg/_44827299_cavendishap226.jpg" alt="[Mark Cavendish]"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Cavendish left the other sprinters for dead today, winning his second stage of this year&amp;#8217;s Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/7503565.stm"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; impressed me too:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And after the race he confirmed his intention to complete this year&amp;#8217;s Tour before joining his GB Olympics team-mates at their track training camp.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m okay and I will keep going for as long as I can,&amp;#8221; said Cavendish. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone remember Mario Cipollini heading home after the first week of the tour? I reckon Cavendish is chasing a hat-trick
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour.html</link>
<category>Cavendish</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
