<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 15, fear and respect</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees.html&quot;&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about the failures and disappointments which made the opening week of this year&amp;#8217;s tour so compelling, and complained that the action had dropped when it should have peaked, in the mountains. Having shaken off the field, Contador and Schleck seemed unable to get to grips with each other. That all changed on stage 15, though again failure and disappointment underpinned the racing. Schleck sprang away from the elite climbers on the Port de Bal&amp;egrave;s, with Contador in hot pursuit. Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain came off but the momentum of his attack continued &amp;#8212; now carried by Contador and a few other elite riders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve already seen Schleck doesn&amp;#8217;t have the team support Contador does; but he looked cruelly exposed on that mountain road, struggling to re-fit his chain. It took a couple of goes. He had to fend off a motorbike. He needed help from a couple of spectators to shove him back on course. By then, the leader on the road was Contador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last we were treated to the sight of Schleck racing uphill. He tore up the road. He nearly caught Contador, but the Spaniard was lucky to be in the perfect group for a super-fast descent. At the end of that descent, the end of the stage, Contador had the yellow jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleck was furious. He &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; furious. I think he&amp;#8217;s also wiped out, physically and emotionally. Anger fuelled his final climb up the Bal&amp;egrave;s but a tankful of anger won&amp;#8217;t get take over the Tourmalet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview afterwards Contador was asked if he was afraid of Schleck. Fear? No, he said. Respect, yes. Contador lost a lot of respect for attacking when the race leader suffered a mechanical failure. Maybe even self-respect. He was jeered on the podium. He &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingnews.com/news/contador-defends-his-attack-on-the-bales&quot;&gt;toughed it out with the press&lt;/a&gt;, claiming he hadn&amp;#8217;t known about Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain falling off. Later on, from his hotel room, he posted a public apology on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XdOJLuePexs&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain hadn&amp;#8217;t come off? I think Contador would have caught him. Schleck was already looking back to see who was where. He needed to face forwards and give it everything. I also thought Contador would attack on the final Pyrenean stage. He&amp;#8217;s been holding something back. I thought that he was too classy to accept winning the Tour by beating the clock in a time trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m not so sure he would have attacked, when defence and a decent time-trial would have sufficed. He will attack, if only to regain some respect. Sadly, I doubt Schleck has enough left.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect</link>
<category>Contador</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 14, Pyrenees</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The first week of the Tour is normally a prelude to the real action &amp;#8212; someone unexpected wears yellow, sprinters stretch their legs, commentators and journalists clock up a few words, everyone looks forward to the real race. This year has seen a first week like no other. Looking back, amazingly, it&amp;#8217;s the failures and disappointments which stand out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cav&amp;#8217;s failure to contest the opening sprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Armstrong&amp;#8217;s poor luck and subsequent inability to follow the leaders (and now look how far he has fallen!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frank Schleck&amp;#8217;s broken shoulder, meaning he won&amp;#8217;t be there for his brother&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yellow jersey Cancellara cancelling the sprint finish at the end of stage 2. How could he do that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on. If this opening week offered so much drama, what would we get when the route hit the mountains?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story unfolds. Unimaginably, Andy Schleck beat Contador in the first Alpine stage, and in the next stage the two of them &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers.html&quot;&gt;toyed with each other&lt;/a&gt; briefly then teamed up to demolish any wannabes. Now we&amp;#8217;re in the Pyrenees, where the tour should be decided. Yesterday Contador and Schleck reached stalemate, again, like a joke with no punchline. Come on guys, this race deserves better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On the subject of Armstrong, has he really cracked, or is he trying to drop so far down the GC that he&amp;#8217;ll be allowed a break-away stage win?)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees</link>
<category>Contador</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 9, dancing climbers</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The best climbers seem to dance up the slopes and today, on the Madeleine, two of the very best performed a wonderful pas de deux. Schleck flashed, Contador darted. The elastic between them pinged and sang. Might their rivals not take advantage of this energy-sapping flirtation? What rivals! A gruelling stage had already unravelled them. Contador and Schleck stopped playing and chased home. The race is between them now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If I attacked one more time I would have dropped myself,&amp;#8221; said Andy Schleck afterwards, but he looked as if he&amp;#8217;d just stepped out of the shower after a good night&amp;#8217;s sleep, rather than completed a mountain stage of the world&amp;#8217;s toughest race. Bring on the Pyrenees. Contador is too classy a rider to win the tour in a time trial. He&amp;#8217;s getting stronger. Watch him attack!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers</link>
<category>Contador</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Week One</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, a rest day today, after a week of quite literal thrills and spills. Yesterday provided a fitting finale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember last year, that final mountain stage on Mont Ventoux? It was meant to decide the general classification but by then Contador, already in yellow, had enough of a lead to ride defensively and cover the attacks. Andy Schleck couldn&amp;#8217;t shake him off. The stage was effectively neutralised. Yesterday, on the first Alpine stage, it looked like Schleck hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped at the summit of Ventoux at all. There he was, still poised on Contador&amp;#8217;s shoulder, a fresh-faced skinny executioner kitted out in white. This time Contador didn&amp;#8217;t look so clever. Schleck may not have taken much time out of his rival but he beat him convincingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingnews.com/races/97th-tour-de-france-gt/stage-8/results&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com//2010/07/11/2/bettiniphoto_0056537_1_full_600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Schleck the skinny executioner&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</link>
<category>Contador</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Someone race Cavendish, please</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/routes/overseas/345690/etape-du-tour-2009-route-recce.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/e/etape-2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;540px&quot; height=&quot;360px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France takes a rest today (though not for the riders in the &amp;Eacute;tape du Tour, who&amp;#8217;ll take on Mont Ventoux six days before the pros), giving me a chance to try and make sense of a strange and compelling weekend of racing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;#8217;s short sharp climb to Verbier made perfect sense and settled a few outstanding questions. Noone climbs like Contador, and the Madrile&amp;ntilde;o confirmed his position as race favourite and Astana team leader. The way he dances up the steepest slopes is truly thrilling. I can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him climb Ventoux. Armstrong rode with the elite riders, but I&amp;#8217;d say Kl&amp;ouml;den may well be shaping up as the Astana number 2 &amp;#8212; he&amp;#8217;s a strong time trial rider who looked in fine shape on the climb, edging Armstrong at the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about Brad Wiggins? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/blog/2009/jul/19/bradley-wiggins-tour-de-france&quot;&gt;Shedding 9% of his bodyweight&lt;/a&gt; has morphed him from track rider into Grand Tour contender. Best of all, he&amp;#8217;s enjoying himself. I think he could come out of Thursday&amp;#8217;s time trial &amp;#8212; his favourite discipline &amp;#8212; as Contador&amp;#8217;s main rival for yellow. Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/14/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france-stage-10&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2009/7/14/1247596770216/Mark-Cavendish-001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Why isn&#x27;t Cav in green?&quot; width=&quot;460px&quot; height=&quot;276px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday&amp;#8217;s stage was more complex. I&amp;#8217;m struggling to understand what Mark Cavendish was playing at. Cavendish already has a remarkable 4 stage victories in this year&amp;#8217;s Tour, matching the 4 he took last year. Well, the number is remarkable, but this year the sprint finishes have seemed routine: the Columbia train leads him out over the final few kilometres, then his team-mates peel away in sequence leaving him to deliver the killer blow. The trouble is, Cavendish&amp;#8217;s rivals have already rolled over and died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Sport evolves and, if you go back to the 1970s, I never, ever had a lead-out man, not once,&amp;#8221; Hoban said this week. &amp;#8220;Everyone was there, man to man. The way they do it now, with a team like that, if they are leading out at 65kph very few people are going to come over that. Anyone to challenge Mark going at 65kph has got to do 70kph.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/19/tour-de-france-history-hoban-cavendish&quot;&gt;Barry Hoban&lt;/a&gt;, quoted in the Observer newspaper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d have thought this supremacy would leave Cavendish way out in front in the green jersey but he hasn&amp;#8217;t chased enough intermediate sprints. This leaves him (left him) head to head with the mighty Thor Hushovd in the points competition. My opinion? I don&amp;#8217;t think Cavendish relishes scrabbling for points and it&amp;#8217;s brought out his petulant side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He says he&amp;#8217;s fastest. His rivals admit he&amp;#8217;s fastest. He is fastest. But he still wants a race!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we had a strange situation. Popular Columbia rider, George Hincapie, was in a breakaway and had a realistic shot at yellow. So team Columbia wanted to slow the chase. But team Columbia also wanted Cavendish to win the peloton sprint for the points given to the 13th place finisher; and so, once more, the train chugged down the final kilometre with everyone watching the clock. Cavendish barely bothered to race for the line. Yes, he blocked Hushovd when he could and should have flown away from him. He wanted to win but in as slow a time as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event Hincapie missed out on yellow by just 5 seconds. You can&amp;#8217;t blame Cavendish for that, but Cavendish is a team player and I suspect he cared more about his team missing yellow than his subsequent disqualification in the sprint. He just wasn&amp;#8217;t bothered about a race for 13th place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, it&amp;#8217;s probably cost him the green jersey and taken the edge off the showdown next Sunday. I hope he stops feeling hard done by and comes out ready to race. I know he cares more about being fastest on the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es than the points competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-20</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race</link>
<category>Contador</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Attaque Armstrong!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/1/10162216-073.jpg&quot; width=&quot;540px&quot; height=&quot;340px&quot; alt=&quot;On the same team?&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France 2009 is shaping up to be a truly great race. Any pretence that the Astana team is led by race favourite, Contador, has been dropped &amp;#8212; by Armstrong at least. The tough-talking Texan has spoken in several interviews about the team having more than one leader, in his (singletrack-)mind at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armstrong&amp;#8217;s legs did the talking on Monday, a flat 3rd stage of the race. Usually the peleton would stick together on such a stage and it would end with a bunch sprint, probably won by Cavendish, and there would be no changes to the general classification (i.e. the yellow jersey competition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cavendish did indeed win the sprint but the big news of the day was the break in the peleton, something which can happen in high winds. After the split Armstrong rode in the front group; with Contador in the second group. The split extended to 40 seconds and by the end of the day Armstrong led Contador in the race by some 20 seconds. In the post-race interview shown on ITV4, did Armstrong say he should have dropped back to help Contador? Hell no, he accused Contador of tactical naivety, gaining unexpected support from a disgruntled French rider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frenchman Christophe Le Mevel claimed it was Contador&amp;#8217;s failure to stick to the wheel in front of him which caused the split with around 30km to go. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/8137119.stm&quot;&gt;BBC Sport report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In yesterday&amp;#8217;s team trial the Astana team rode well together to win the stage, and came within &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/381945/tour-de-france-analysis-why-contador-s-chances-rose-when-armstrong-missed-yellow.html&quot;&gt;tenths of a second&lt;/a&gt; of grabbing the yellow jersey for Armstrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to note that had the field not split on Monday, Contador would have been in yellow in Montpellier. Before the Columbia-led move, to which Armstrong and team-mates loyal to him gratefully contributed, Contador was just 18 seconds down overall. Had the bunch stayed together, he&amp;#8217;d have been in yellow by 22 seconds after the team time trial. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/381945/tour-de-france-analysis-why-contador-s-chances-rose-when-armstrong-missed-yellow.html&quot;&gt;Cycling News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contador still looks the man to beat and yesterday&amp;#8217;s team time trial has set him up well over many of his rivals. Let&amp;#8217;s not forget how well he did in the prologue; let&amp;#8217;s see how he fares in the mountains. Armstrong may be able to needle and even outsmart him, but I can&amp;#8217;t seem him outriding him in the Pyrenees, the real start of the yellow jersey competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rider, Armstrong has been admired and feared more than loved. He&amp;#8217;s determined and ruthless rather than charismatic. During his 7 Tour wins he stunned his rivals to the point they even failed to capitalise on his mistakes. I suspect he&amp;#8217;ll be depending on mistakes now, and I can&amp;#8217;t see Contador making another. What&amp;#8217;s more, Armstrong will need charisma and love in his future political career.  He is turning the 2009 Tour into a great race, but one he will ultimately fail to win, and he will speak  truth in defeat; and we will, at last, love him for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/attaque-armstrong</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/attaque-armstrong</link>
<category>Contador</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
