<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Cross country catch up</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I posted these old race reports &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Inter-Regional &amp;amp; Masters Championships, Builth Wells, December 10th 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did say, at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011.html&quot;&gt;Fairwood race&lt;/a&gt;, I was invited to represent West Wales in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.welshathletics.org/competitions/events/cross-country/2011/12-dec/welsh-inter-regional-cross-country-championships.aspx&quot;&gt;inter-regional championships&lt;/a&gt;? Well, the day had come, a chill December morning. White frost coated the meadow at Parkmill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ifan took the scenic route through Llandeilo and LLandovery &amp;#8230; I sank back into the passenger seat and watched the hills roll by. We parked outside the showground and crunched across ice and gravel to the race HQ where the tarpaulin they&amp;#8217;d laid down on the floor was already rucked and muddy. Red and white tapes zig-zagged up the hill, marking out the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collected my West Wales vest. When you get a heavy course, like today, one which includes sections of concrete and tarmac, Ifan said, use longer spikes here and shorter ones here, under the ball of the foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just over an hour to go we jogged a warm-up lap, starting with an extended climb through the woods. You can push on here, he said, as we emerged from the trees and passed a static caravan, still climbing, it&amp;#8217;s downhill for a while after this. At the summit stood an enormous speaker, part of the showground&amp;#8217;s PA system. I could see the Builth Wells showground now &amp;#8212; the timber-clad buildings, the neat field, the high boundary fence &amp;#8212; like a stage in the centre of the immense ampitheatre formed by the surrounding hills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunlight poked through the clouds as we lined up at the start, shivering, edgy. One short lap and two long ones. I found my place and settled in. On the first climb my way was blocked by a tall runner. I moved left to overtake. He moved left. I moved right. He moved right. I passed him by the caravan and extended my lead downhill. Briefly, our route intersected the U15 girls&amp;#8217; race and I was dodging elbows, legs, pony-tails. On the long flat section round the playing fields the tall runner pegged me back. I let him go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching the climb for the second time, the ground had softened. I went past a couple of runners who&amp;#8217;d gone out too fast. I dug in as the path steepened, skeetering wide through tree roots, leaf mould and brambles to pass him. I was clear now but there were two more in front to aim at. I remembered Ifan&amp;#8217;s advice and stumbled over the top on empty, relying on gravity to recharge my legs on the descent. I bounded down a final rocky path, arms flailing, and held on till the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6955236875/&quot; title=&quot;13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7202/6955236875_2d6a00c8d9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; alt=&quot;13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;West Glamorgan League, Margam, January 8th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at &lt;a href=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk/4.html&quot;&gt;Margam&lt;/a&gt; at eleven in time to see the race start without me. Lesson being, the West Glamorgan races are organised differently. The sight of all those humans on the move had animated the park&amp;#8217;s deer herd. I watched them hurtle round their own short course. I ran the route anyway, slowly, and very boggy it was too. Next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cardiff Cross Challenge, January 15th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://cardiffxchallenge.wordpress.com/the-event/&quot;&gt;McCain Cardiff cross challenge&lt;/a&gt;, held just north of the city centre in Blackweir Fields, is &amp;#8220;one of the most prestigious Cross Country events in the UK&amp;#8221;. Isobel was running. Last time she&amp;#8217;d run, in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011.html&quot;&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt;, around a foul course in filthy weather, she&amp;#8217;d failed to finish, so it was a crucial event for her. We arrived in good time and registered. She&amp;#8217;d be wearing her Afan-Nedd-Tawe vest. I&amp;#8217;d be running for Swansea Harriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the going looked fine. The sun was out, the wind was down. The course was flat, dry, sheltered. Isobel had a solid run, finishing strongly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, they&amp;#8217;d fine-tuned the schedule, overlapping races, closing and opening routes through the parkland, somehow without any runners getting trampled, confused or impeded, and so it was that the senior men&amp;#8217;s event, the last of the day, would be starting just an hour after Isobel had finished. With 5 minutes to go I made my way to the starting pen. Where was everyone? Suddenly the elite runners appeared, peeling off thermals, shaking long, elastic legs. We&amp;#8217;d be running four times round. I realised I was in danger of getting lapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/IwVLNiAQYps?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily I avoided any such ignominy. The course seemed tame &amp;#8212; where were the hills, swamps, trenches, wild animals? Isobel injected some welcome variety, appearing at random positions to cheer me on, and her encouragement helped me maintain my pace and place. I did pass one runner on the final lap and pushed hard to close the gap on the next, a tall lad in a black vest, but, closing in on the finish, he kicked away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Cross Country Championships, St Fagans, February 18th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6910503621/&quot; title=&quot;Start and finished by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7053/6910503621_5807ae1e07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Start and finished&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torrential rain and wind during the morning made for very difficult conditions on an already tough course for the 108th running of the Welsh Cross Country Championships. While the junior races were run in these treacherous conditions, the rain had stopped by the time the senior athletes were on the starting line; the damage to the course, however, was already done. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.welshathletics.org/news--media/news/cross-country/2012/02-feb/jones-and-griffiths-clinch-cross-country-welsh-titles.aspx&quot;&gt;Welsh Athletics race report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hats off to Isobel for getting round this one. She lasted longer than the inflatable start and finish markers, which were swiftly deflated and packed away before the wind ripped them up. After, she went with Gail and Alex to visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.museumwales.ac.uk/en/stfagans/&quot;&gt;National History Museum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain had indeed stopped by the time the men&amp;#8217;s race started but the course was brutal. I slogged my way round one, two, three, four laps, and was glad when it ended. I pulled my bag from the mud and squelched back through the field to the road-side, texting Gail to collect me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-06-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</link>
<category>Cross country</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cross country, Singleton Park 2011</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday 4th December was the 3rd of 5 league cross county fixtures at home in Singleton Park where all the ideal cross country ingredients were available, rain, hail, long steep hills and thick muddy bogs, very many congratulations to everyone who competed on one of the toughest cross country courses around.
&amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk&quot;&gt;http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6435309037/&quot; title=&quot;Gwent League cross country, December 2011, Singleton Park Swansea by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7167/6435309037_fe064f27e6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;387&quot; alt=&quot;Gwent League cross country, December 2011, Singleton Park Swansea&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Swansea harriers website&quot;&gt;Swansea Harriers&lt;/a&gt; had turned out for the previous Gwent League event, held a month ago in Bath, and team manager Kevin Corcoran expected a good showing for today&amp;#8217;s event &amp;#8212; a home fixtur in Singleton Park. The going will be heavy, his email said, bring spikes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly we&amp;#8217;d help boost the numbers. Alex would be racing his first race for the club, the novice boys at 12:06, to be followed immediately by Isobel in the U13 girls at 12:15. The Senior men&amp;#8217;s race &amp;#8212; me! &amp;#8212; wouldn&amp;#8217;t start until 14:50. Because of the time gaps and the wintry weather Gail decided to drive the kids, getting there in time to register and then head back with them as soon as they&amp;#8217;d run. I&amp;#8217;d travel independently by bike: a good way to warm up and cool down, I reckoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rain spat as I started my journey. A fresh wind pushed clouds across the sky. Half an hour later I pedalled through the crowded car park at Bishop Gore school, locked my bike to the railings, then made my way to the club tent.  Take it slowly to start with, I told Alex, save something for the finish. He doesn&amp;#8217;t have running spikes and I had suggested he wore his rugby boots, but he wanted to wear his trainers. He doesn&amp;#8217;t have a club vest either and was wearing a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skins.net&quot;&gt;thermal top&lt;/a&gt;. There he stood, black top, black shorts, anxious, ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route starts with a climb then loops around the park back to the start and climbs again to the finish. He was going well. Dan turned up with Fynn, Cai and Schnorbie. We cheered, Alex responded, passing four people at speed on the final muddy climb. Rain slashed down in a sudden squall. He crossed the line, exhausted, breathless, on the verge of tears. I wanted to get to him and get him warm and dry but he had to follow the finish-line protocol: waiting in line to collect his token, waiting again to hand it over to the team manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bundled Alex into the tent and pulled dry clothes over the top of his wet  muddy kit. It had been a tough race for him. Isobel&amp;#8217;s race had already started &amp;#8212; two laps for her. She was in trouble on the first climb, looking to us, shaking her head. She&amp;#8217;s pulled out, Gail said. What? Never! Isobel&amp;#8217;s already an experienced runner: she knows how to pace herself. But it was true, she was walking back, in tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#8217;t breathe, she said. You&amp;#8217;re not cross with me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course not. I hugged her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made our way back to the car. I reassured Isobel. It happened. Now you know, and you&amp;#8217;ll know what to do next time. It won&amp;#8217;t happen again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;#8217;t make her go to harriers, it&amp;#8217;s her choice &amp;#8212; what she wants to do &amp;#8212; but the club insists its members compete. It&amp;#8217;s not about keeping fit. One of the novice girls had lost a shoe, it stuck in the mud at the start, and she&amp;#8217;d run up the hill wearing one shoe and carrying the other, had her footwear refitted, and gone on to finish, gaining points for her team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family had gone now. Two and a half hours until my race. I was wearing several layers of clothing and all of them were damp. The rain had stopped but the wind was tugging more clouds our way. My fingers and toes were cold. I walked the route. Downhill, the ground was waterlogged. The map showed the route fording something described as a spring, and what I&amp;#8217;d pictured as clear running water turned out to be a trench overflowing with viscous mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped to talk with a couple of marshals who stood dressed like fishermen in the middle of the park. They explained the route to me in some detail. There&amp;#8217;d been a fault with the original version of the map, the one I&amp;#8217;d seen online. It said the senior men would run three medium loops and one full one but we&amp;#8217;d actually be running one medium loop and three full ones. The course could have been simplified, they thought, joining points together and eliminating whole sections. They could have overlapped events and had more than one group out at once. The U15 girls race had started now, and the marshals trudged into position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the start line I queued for a cup of tea from the Licensed to Grill van. It wasn&amp;#8217;t hot enough or strong enough but it warmed my fingers. I ate a banana and one of the welsh cakes I&amp;#8217;d packed. A mobile shoe shop had set itself up near the start line. My feet are short and wide. They had a good selection of of cross country spikes and the Adidas ones fitted perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/cross-country-spikes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cross country spikes&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran a short warm up with a couple of others then got changed. I wondered if Ifan was coming? At last the race started. I ran eagerly along the top section then let gravity lengthen my stride downhill. Oh, there he was, just in front. I checked myself slightly. Plenty of time to accelerate later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spikes feel different to the trail shoes I&amp;#8217;m used to: lighter, less stable. Faster? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try and find firmer ground. Take muddy corners wide. Run closer to foliage &amp;#8212; being shorter, I can duck under the tagged branches. Up and downhill I do better. I could improve on the flat and through mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Fulcher came past at speed on the final lap but I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow him. I was locked into my pace and my group and there I stayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to congratulate Ifan who&amp;#8217;d finished 22nd. I was happy with 45th. They were filming him for some Vets 24/7 program which BBC Wales will screen next year. I did hear them ask, if he was a veteran runner and a veteranarian, did that make him a vet vet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I returned to the tent and ate another welsh cake pulling layers of clothing back on. My lined cycling gloves are a real struggle to put on when damp. Rain hammered down. Cars queued to leave Bishop Gore car park. One which had parked on the field spun its wheels in the mud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-12-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011</link>
<category>Cross country</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>West Wales cross country championships, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6349344373/&quot; title=&quot;Race number 6 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6112/6349344373_a530c3c561.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; alt=&quot;Race number 6&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned up early enough to register Isobel too &amp;#8212; she&amp;#8217;d compete in the first event of the day, the U13 girls, and I&amp;#8217;d run the final event, the senior mens &amp;#8212; and collected race number 6, not to be confused with 9. We were at the Swansea University playing fields, Fairwood, for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html&quot;&gt;second race in the West Glamorgan cross country league&lt;/a&gt;, incorporating the West Wales championships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was sunny and fresh. Recent rainfall had soaked the ground. Perfect cross country conditions. Gail, Alex and my parents arrived in time to see Isobel start, but only just: they&amp;#8217;d been watching Alex play rugby at Penclawdd, where the referee had extended the game because the home team were about to score a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls were strung along the far side of the field, the front runners striding out. Pembrokeshire Harriers had the first two places. We intercepted the route to cheer Isobel along the first and second fields &amp;#8212; the up and down bit of the course &amp;#8212; then climbed the bank to the finish line, by the observatory. She did well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An hour to go before the men&amp;#8217;s race. My family found a place to sit and Gail sorted them out with hot drinks and snacks. I got myself ready. I knew a few people from the Saturday morning runs: Ifan, the animal beast monster; Ross, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowertriathlon.com/results.asp&quot; title=&quot;Ross Simpson, winner of the Gower olympic distance triathlon&quot;&gt;race-winning triathlete&lt;/a&gt;, who&amp;#8217;d competed in another event yesterday and been training on the bike this morning; Raul, who couldn&amp;#8217;t believe I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be doing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-coast-half-marathon.html&quot; title=&quot;My report on the Gower coast half marathon, 2010&quot;&gt;Gower coastal half marathon&lt;/a&gt; next weekend; and Simon who asked if I was running, and then said, shame, he wouldn&amp;#8217;t win. I laced my shoes tightly and double-knotted them: at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011.html&quot;&gt;Bridgend&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#8217;d almost left one stuck in the mud. I recognised a few more athletes from Bridgend and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html&quot; title=&quot;Welsh castles relay, 2011&quot;&gt;Brecon&lt;/a&gt;. Many have the look &amp;#8212; skinny, long-limbed, elastic &amp;#8212; but by no means all, and, even at the age of 47, I&amp;#8217;m far from being the oldest: these guys never give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tail-enders in the women&amp;#8217;s race were finishing. Not long now. I jogged across the pitch and back, keeping warm. Go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people complain about running laps rather than a single extended circuit, but, as someone new to the course, it suits me. I gave it more than at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011.html&quot;&gt;Bridgend&lt;/a&gt;, striding out on the downhills, digging in on the climbs. Ross came alongside me on the second lap. He runs so smoothly. Go on, Thomas! That was Gail. Mrs Smith, Isobel&amp;#8217;s ironman science teacher, had finished the women&amp;#8217;s race in time to take up a position on the second field and encourage everyone. Appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up my pace on the final lap. Amazingly, Ross fell back. I&amp;#8217;d dropped him. One last push to the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2F&amp;set_id=72157628136270030&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2F&amp;set_id=72157628136270030&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clickonwales.org/2011/06/sport-sponsored-by-sport-wales/&quot; title=&quot;Dr David Hedydd Davies, MBE&quot;&gt;Dr Hedydd Davies&lt;/a&gt; handed me a letter as I crossed the line: an invitation to run for West Wales in the inter-regional championships in Builth Wells! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6350090562/&quot; title=&quot;letter by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6051/6350090562_5c5a44f002.jpg&quot; width=&quot;333&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m accepting, of course, but have two questions: what size vest? and should I get spikes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Chris Fulcher for allowing me to use his wonderful photos. More of &lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/102718880405756419943/WestGlamLeagueFairwood2011&quot;&gt;his photos of the event can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-11-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011</link>
<category>Cross country</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Gwent cross country league, Bridgend, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6234349086/&quot; title=&quot;Newbridge fields, Bridgend, cross country course by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6224/6234349086_3d3a5cec9c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;391&quot; alt=&quot;Newbridge fields, Bridgend, cross country course&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drove from Swansea along the M4, the car buffeted by gusting winds, windscreen wipers swiping away the rain. We parked at Bridgend recreation centre and walked along a concrete-lined service road and past a wet playground. There was the race HQ &amp;#8212; Bridgend Athletics club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isobel was nervous. What time is it? There should be a tent. Stay close to me. Is that Andrew? What time is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were lots of tents and lots of tall track-suited men who could have been Andrew. Striped tape stretched between plastic posts, marking out the route. There was the finish line. The PA system chattered away. 7 minutes till the novice boys&amp;#8217; race, the first event of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found the Swansea Harriers tent and reported in. &amp;#163;1 for the under 13 event, &amp;#163;4 for seniors. Isobel fell in with some friends and was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked over the bridge and onto the fields, heading for the start. The novice boys were on the course now, stretched in a line between the river and the rugby pitch. Spectators struggled to control umbrellas. Dogs tugged at leads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isobel found me again, wanting to hand over her clothes. Half an hour, I said. Keep warm. Do you need the loo? Are you thirsty? I&amp;#8217;d keep those on, really, don&amp;#8217;t get cold. But she wanted to be ready. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novice girls swung round towards the bridge. The first runner passed, straight-faced, serious. She wouldn&amp;#8217;t be caught. More lone front runners, then clumps. Go on! Well run! Towards the back, tears, girls walking, being urged to push on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6230068047/&quot; title=&quot;U13 U13 Boys cross country race, Newbridge Fields, Bridgend by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6230068047_653525fc23.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;288&quot; alt=&quot;U13 U13 Boys cross country race, Newbridge Fields, Bridgend&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The under 13 boys&amp;#8217; race now. They shivered and twitched then set off at a sprint. Isobel was with her team getting final words of advice. The under 13 boys were on their way back. The leaders hadn&amp;#8217;t slowed down at all. The girls lined up. Over a hundred of them, I should think. Aberdare, Aberystwyth, Barry, Bath, Bridgend, Bristol, Caerleon, Cardiff, Carmarthen, Chepstow, Gorseinon, Griffithstown, Llanelli, Lliswerry, Neath, Newport, Pembrokeshire, Penarth, Pontypridd, Port Talbot, Porthcawl, Rhondda, Stroud, Swansea, Taunton, Wells, Westbury, Weston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She ran well, at a steady pace. I cut across the course to cheer her on at different points: by the river, at the bridge, near the woods, and I was there waiting at the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;56th. I hugged her. Well done! I need spikes, dad. So muddy, I mean it is soooo muddy! I&amp;#8217;m really pleased, are you pleased? I didn&amp;#8217;t stop and walk. You did really well, I&amp;#8217;m proud of you. Really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your turn now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, my turn. I got Isobel&amp;#8217;s kit, made sure she put it on, gave her money for a snack. No surprise to see Ifan Lloyd. I&amp;#8217;m guessing you know this course, I said. You could say that, yes. Yes, you could say. I knew I wouldn&amp;#8217;t see much of him during the race though. And there was Gary Irving, captain of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html&quot;&gt;Welsh Castles Relay&lt;/a&gt; team, taller and thinner than ever. Was I over 50? No. Shame! We&amp;#8217;d have had a useful M50 team. Younger seniors crouched in the tent, swigging drinks, selecting footwear, unpeeling tights, rubbing muscles. I had stopped following the races now but was aware of the different age groups out on the course tracing different circuits different numbers of times, crossing and re-crossing. Some of the route posts had fallen over and loose tapes got trampled into the wet grass. The first senior women had finished, muddy and flushed. I got changed. Had a drink. Checked my laces. Queued for the toilet, then needed to go again. Jogged around the field. Now I was walking across the bridge to the start line. 5 minutes till off. And now we were off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fell into position in the middle of the pack. We passed the stone circle which marks the place where the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eisteddfod.org.uk/english/content.php?nID=55&quot;&gt;Eisteddfod&lt;/a&gt; was held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on daddy! There was Isobel with a friend. Come on Swansea!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6237143908/&quot; title=&quot;Gwent League, Bridgend 2011, by Chris and Maxine Fulcher by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6036/6237143908_9902e8bdc4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;332&quot; alt=&quot;Gwent League, Bridgend 2011, by Chris and Maxine Fulcher&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran through mud churned by previous runners. I clung to the edges where the grass gave more traction. Downhill, I followed the slope, not the route. I slowed into corners, took them wide, then pushed on when we hit gravel and harder ground. Bang, man down! A sniper got him. Uphill in chopped strides, looking for footholds. Isobel appeared again. I waved, feeling good. The lead runners swerved ahead, rattling round far corners of the course. On the second lap I started moving up the field. The heel of my right shoe was too loose and stuck in the mud. Lace up more tightly next time. Field, field, woods, bridge, field. 3rd and final lap. I had something left. I charged for the line and funneled in, collecting a cardboard position token to be handed to my team manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasoned runners bring two bottles of water. One for drinking, one for washing. A sign at the recreation centre said cross country runners were &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to use the facilities but we did anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2011/res111.htm&quot;&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; came through, and an email from Kevin Corcoran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an outstanding day for the Senior Men with wins for Dewi Griffiths (Senior Men &amp;amp; Under 23), Mark Roberts (V40) and Ifan Lloyd (V50).  Dewi led our men to team victory over Cardiff and we also won the B Team Division in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Chris and Maxine Fulcher for allowing me to take a copy of their fine &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6237143908&quot;&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt;. More of &lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/102718880405756419943/GwentLeagueBridgend2011#&quot;&gt;their photos of the event can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011</link>
<category>Cross country</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
