<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/20871409082/in/dateposted-friend/" title="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5776/20871409082_524894d533_z.jpg" width="451" height="640" alt="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in June I went to the launch of Paul Jones&amp;#8217; book &amp;#8220;A Corinthian Endeavour &amp;#8212; The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great talk and it&amp;#8217;s a great book. Here in the UK, we don&amp;#8217;t have Alpine cols or Pyrennean passes. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs"&gt;We have hills&lt;/a&gt;. Hills with erratic gradients and twisted names &amp;#8212; Nick-o-Pendle, Mow Cop, Pea Royd Lane &amp;#8212; hills which, at the end of the cycling season, draw nascent professionals and amateur specialists to battle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/18495855150/in/dateposted-public/" title="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/458/18495855150_4d6165f574_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones has the credentials to tell the tale: an unashamed fan and a talented writer, he is himself a tidy competitor. The book begins with him interviewing Vic Clarke, the man who finished second in the inaugural national hill climb championships in 1944 and who would go on to win the event three times. Also present is Lyn Hamel, a current competitor and multiple champion herself. When Jones offers biscuits (Marks and Spencers Belgian chocolate selection!) both champions decline: for climbers, gravity&amp;#8217;s pull is the enemy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gravity isn&amp;#8217;t the only enemy. Competitors don&amp;#8217;t race head to head. The courses are too short, the roads too narrow. Instead they square up to the clock. The fastest time wins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the book continues Jones deftly weaves the history of the championships around more stories from and interviews with their protagonists. There&amp;#8217;s Chris Boardman, who set and still holds several records. There are other less familiar names: Wilson, Sydney, Armitage, Dobbin, Pettinger.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/anti-gravity-specialists/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cyclinguphill.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Screen-Shot-2015-06-24-at-10.00.13.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered Paul Jones via his &lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/"&gt;Traumfahrrad&lt;/a&gt; cycling blog, a forum where he allows himself more freedom to poke fun and sound off. His blog describes the joy and pain of early morning training rides. He chortles at triathletes who get their socks wrong. You&amp;#8217;ll also find the details of his own assaults on the hill climbs: despite his self-effacement he&amp;#8217;s clearly a feared and respected rider. In the book, though, he reins himself in and logs the facts. The who, what, how and when are painstakingingly researched and recorded. Gear inches matter more to the author than, apparently, to Chris Boardman, who can barely remember if he took part in the races he won, let alone the number of teeth on his sprocket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, though, Jones takes a step back from the details. In one chapter he asks: &amp;#8220;When is a Hill not a Hill?&amp;#8221; A good championship course:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;#8230; should be run on closed roads [&amp;#8230;] Riders should be digging out their hill climb bikes and making &lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/marginal-gains-hill-climb-bike" title=""Tejvan Pettinger strips down his bike"&gt;absurd modifications&lt;/a&gt; for no real gain [&amp;#8230;] each competitor needs to be left flailing on a grass bank like a dying goldfish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contrast this to the 2011 championship on Long Hill:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/2015/08/24/below-the-line/"&gt;&lt;img style="width:500px" src="https://scontent-lhr3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xft1/v/t1.0-9/11796216_10207229514877458_7189614863695398022_n.jpg?oh=a2544be1e9e0a4883cd4531b8946519b&amp;oe=5671E221"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the last, Jones claims hill climbers are ascetics in search of transcendence who tilt their caps backwards. By battling time and human frailty paradoxically they escape it and themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first thing&lt;/br&gt;I have understood:&lt;/br&gt;Time is the echo of an axe&lt;/br&gt;Within a wood.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-08-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Uphill downhill</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Two of my favourite cycling videos. The first chases a solo rider downhill on the ride of his life, his flamboyant skills matched only by the increasingly hysterical commentary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//www.youtube.com/embed/EqYgAX6D43Q?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second catalogues the participants in this year&amp;#8217;s national hill climb championships, ticking off a series of skinny introverts who battle elements and inclines.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//www.youtube.com/embed/MiNfJ-slbIg?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replay!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-11-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/uphill-downhill</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/uphill-downhill</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bargain!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a member so I had to fork out a 50% premium to enter. For &amp;pound;6 I got:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     a cup of tea
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a toasted tea-cake (help yourself to butter and jam)
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a route description
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a protective cover for the route description
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a brevet card
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     two cups of squash
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a chocolate flapjack
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     &lt;a href="http://www.aukweb.net/events/detail/13-408/#more"&gt;100km of cycling&lt;/a&gt;, to include 2400m of climbing and some of the finest scenery in south Wales
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     another cup of tea
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     a ham roll (help yourself to salad)
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9713256358/" title="Carreg Cennen by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5330/9713256358_5d3a60a6b6_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Carreg Cennen"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-09-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bargain</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bargain</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Punctures</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Oh no, not &lt;strong&gt;another&lt;/strong&gt; puncture!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-09-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/punctures</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/punctures</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol, Cycling City?</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6544368391/" title="BETT... by
Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img
src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7165/6544368391_abd9703d60_m.jpg" width="230"
height="240" alt="BETT..."&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6544368593/" title="ER BY BIKE
by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img
src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7018/6544368593_f8ab7f7ba5_m.jpg" width="205"
height="240" alt="ER BY BIKE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2008 Greater Bristol was chosen as England&amp;#8217;s first Cycling City and received &amp;pound;11m from the Department for Transport to transform cycling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helped bring about a strong cycling renaissance in the city. New dedicated on-road cycle lanes, new traffic-free routes, 3400 new cycle parking spaces, as well as cycling training and lots of other &amp;#8216;softer measures&amp;#8217; projects encouraged thousands of people to saddle up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/cycling"&gt;http://www.bristol.gov.uk/page/cycling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and I got a mug out of it, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/philmciver/2299981707/" title="Bristol: Queen Square by Phil McIver, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3062/2299981707_b94952f0ec.jpg" width="500" height="351" alt="Bristol: Queen Square"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, though, I cycled from &lt;a href="http://www.screwfix.com/jsp/tradeCounter/tradeCounterDetailsPage.jsp?id=66"&gt;Screwfix in Bedminster&lt;/a&gt; to my office in Clifton. How pleasant to cycle through the middle of Queen Square on a track which, less than 20 years ago, was a dual carriageway. And how enjoyable to continue on across Broad Quay and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Centre_(Bristol)#1998_remodelling"&gt;the centre&lt;/a&gt;, which used to be one great roundabout. Pedestrians and cyclists get the best routes and the best views and that&amp;#8217;s how it should be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6550510109/" title="The Queen Square of the Future by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7013/6550510109_e4f31684ba.jpg" width="500" height="243" alt="The Queen Square of the Future"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle parking area where I work is secure, free (in marked contrast to the car parking spaces), and recently doubled in size. It fills up, every day, even now winter has set in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree: there &lt;strong&gt;has&lt;/strong&gt; been a cycling renaissance but I think it&amp;#8217;s down to a number of factors. Primarily, it&amp;#8217;s lower incomes and the rising price of motoring which is getting people on their bikes. A secondary effect adds momentum: the more cyclists there are, the more people accept cycling, and the more cyclists there will be. The fantastic success of British cycling may have something to do with it, judging by the number of swish road bikes which spin round the Downs every evening. The &lt;a href="http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/TravelAndTransport/Cycling/DG_190101"&gt;government cycle to work scheme&lt;/a&gt; is a fine deal, though I suspect the main beneficiaries are people like me who&amp;#8217;ve always cycled to work. And technological improvements, like &lt;a href="http://traumradfahren.wordpress.com/2011/12/07/commuter-bicycle-race/"&gt;electrically assisted bikes&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; I see plenty of cyclists who wouldn&amp;#8217;t be cycling without these.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling city? &amp;pound;11m! Transformation!?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It annoys me that &amp;#8220;special&amp;#8221; funding should be needed to provide for cyclists. Cycle parking spaces should be built anyway. Any transport planning should naturally prioritise pedestrians and cyclists. I don&amp;#8217;t think &amp;pound;11m paid for the reworking of Queen Square and Broad Quay, yet these schemes have benefited cyclists far more than a new bike route from the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JG7Lv1Ipfz8" title="worth watching for the muzak and subtitles alone"&gt;Farm pub to B&amp;amp;Q&lt;/a&gt;. I would like bike theft to be eliminated. I would like to see car-free approaches to secondary schools in the mornings and afternoons. Get kids used to commuting on foot and by bike and they&amp;#8217;ll continue as adults.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cycling City money wasn&amp;#8217;t wasted but I&amp;#8217;d say the initiative contributed little to the increase in cycling and it&amp;#8217;s foolish to claim or think otherwise. Yes, there are more cyclists on the roads but there need to be far, far more. How can we maintain the momentum? The little things help, let&amp;#8217;s keep doing them, but really it&amp;#8217;s down to government policy, personal responsibility and intelligent transport planning.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-11-16</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-cycling-city</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-cycling-city</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Following the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As ever, I&amp;#8217;m watching the Tour de France &amp;#8212; or maybe I should say I&amp;#8217;m &lt;strong&gt;following&lt;/strong&gt; the tour, since I get much of my fix online, direct from &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/geraintthomas86" title="Geraint Thomas"&gt;riders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://inrng.com" title="The Inner Ring"&gt;commentators&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com" title="Cycling News"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I like the mountain stages. The scenery, the history, the combat. Winners and losers. The Pyrenees have disappointed with the favourites marking each other and no one prepared to make a sustained attack. We had this in 2010, and we still don&amp;#8217;t know who won that race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll on the Alps. As &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/inrng" title="The Inner Ring, on Twitter"&gt;@inrng&lt;/a&gt; points out, the &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage19" title="Inner Ring analysis of stage 19"&gt;Alpe d&amp;#8217;Huez stage is just under 110km&lt;/a&gt;, a sprint. Andy Schleck: don&amp;#8217;t look back!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2011/jul/09/team-sky-bradley-wiggins"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2011/7/9/1310205980831/Team-Skys-Bradley-Wiggins-007.jpg" alt="Bradley Wiggins, crashed out on stage 7"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrible to see Bradley Wiggins collapsed on the tarmac nursing a broken collarbone and knowing his race was over. What if? He&amp;#8217;d shed so much weight in preparation for the mountains there wasn&amp;#8217;t much left of him but what remained &amp;#8212; self-belief, humour, quality &amp;#8212; well, the climbers wouldn&amp;#8217;t have dropped him and he&amp;#8217;d have smashed them in the final time trial. There may yet be positives. Geraint Thomas is off the leash and riding with flair and abandon. He&amp;#8217;s no threat in the GC and could well grab a breakaway stage. Team Sky will build and regroup and throw everything at the Vuelta where Wiggo could yet become the first Briton to win a Grand Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the flatter stages have provided better racing. Cavendish has been a great winner. He also lost well, to Greipel, just the once. For the fourth consecutive year, he&amp;#8217;s fastest. Victory margins haven&amp;#8217;t been massive but to end up in green you have to run a marathon and a sprint, repeatedly. Is all about conserving energy. He can do it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Liggett and Paul Sherwen are putting in a solid performance. Ned Boulting too. Chris Boardman sounds dull, especially when voicing the sponsors&amp;#8217; messages which bookend the ad breaks:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve often wondered, why do they have second and third place on the podium? &amp;#8230; Yellow isn&amp;#8217;t a colour, it&amp;#8217;s a state of mind &amp;#8230; When my team had to lift me off my bike at the end of a stage, I knew I&amp;#8217;d done enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take (some of) it back about Chris Boardman: his analysis of &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage16"&gt;stage 16&lt;/a&gt;, the one which finished with a treacherous descent into Gap, was spot on. There&amp;#8217;s Andy Schleck moaning people don&amp;#8217;t want to see a race won downhill, yet he hasn&amp;#8217;t raced uphill either, not really. Or as CB described it: throwing the toys out of his pram.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Headwinds</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The wind has been picking up over the last few weeks. Last Thursday it was gusty and fresh &amp;#8212; riding my bike felt like wading through waves. Tonight the wind was more forceful. Out of Swansea city suburbs and on the exposed Gower Road, I dropped into a low gear and dug in, tunneling for home. In places I had to stand on the pedals and wrench the handlbars just to stay in control. Debris flew past in the darkness. It took me well over an hour to get from Swansea station to Reynoldston, a personal worst by some margin. On Saturday I&amp;#8217;m running the &lt;a href="http://www.endurancelife.com/event.asp?series=36&amp;amp;location=98"&gt;Gower coastal half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. If the weather&amp;#8217;s like this Rhossili Down will be brutal.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-11-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/headwinds</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/headwinds</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>100 Greatest Cycling Climbs</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/100-Greatest-Cycling-Climbs-Cyclists/dp/0711231206"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/100-greatest-cycling-climbs.jpg" alt="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing in the rain on Constitution Hill, Swansea, waiting for the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010.html"&gt;Tour of Britain&lt;/a&gt; to arrive, I watched a lanky chap striding up the cobbles. He carried a road sign over his shoulder &amp;#8212; a red triangle, a warning. The triangle contained a picture of a slope and the number 100.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign carrier was Simon Warren, author of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/100-Greatest-Cycling-Climbs-Cyclists/dp/0711231206"&gt;100 Greatest Cycling Climbs&lt;/a&gt;, seizing the chance to advertise his book on what turned out to be the decisive climb of this year&amp;#8217;s tour. Later that evening I visited the Tour of Britain website and entered a competition to win the book. Now, a few weeks later, I&amp;#8217;m holding a copy in my hands.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a shamelessly straight-up book. 100 climbs: arranged, graded, defeated. Constitution Hill, for example, rates 4/10.  Remember though, on this scale, 1/10 means pretty damn tough, and 10/10 means lung-bustingly-knee-wrenchingly-ball-breakingly tough. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle.html"&gt;Porlock Hill&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; the toughest I&amp;#8217;ve ever taken on &amp;#8212; weighs in at 9/10. There are harder climbs, oh yes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maps are useless, the route descriptions redundant (basically: the road goes up). The pictures are spoiled by the garish triangles slapped across them. It&amp;#8217;s not the kind of book you&amp;#8217;d imagine enjoying.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5103981499/" title="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4108/5103981499_9c290fb50a.jpg" width="500" height="377" alt="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved it. I read it from cover to cover, climb upon climb, savouring its remorseless rhythm. It&amp;#8217;s a celebration of Britain&amp;#8217;s hills: &amp;#8220;the cyclists&amp;#8217; theaters, our stadia&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s a monomaniac&amp;#8217;s catalogue, the diary of an obsessive. In the author&amp;#8217;s own words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The super-smooth road heads up straight and steep, first at 20%, then for a short while 25% before easing back into 20% and bending gently to the right. Near the summit comes the hardest section, a left-hand bend ushering in 30 metres of leg-breaking 25% before finally levelling as you enter woods and rumble, stars in your eyes, across a cattle grid to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-10-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Wesley May Super Grimpeur</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I set off at sunrise this morning. Cold mist wafted up from the Loughor estuary. A sheep stood to watch me pass, exposing a warm damp patch where it had been resting in the otherwise frosty field.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5026380019/" title="Sheep in a frosty field by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4088/5026380019_4cc198f85d_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Sheep in a frosty field" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;#8217;s challenge, the &lt;a href="http://www.aukweb.net/cal/calsolo.php?Ride=10-408"&gt;Wesley May Memorial Super Grimpeur&lt;/a&gt;, 2931m of climbing in 100km of riding. I&amp;#8217;ve been wanting to find my way up into the Brecon Beacons. This seemed the perfect opportunity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard bit wasn&amp;#8217;t Black Mountain itself &amp;#8212; that&amp;#8217;s a steady, shallow climb on well-surfaced roads &amp;#8212; it was the rolling hills before and after. Rolling isn&amp;#8217;t the right word, though. These hills crash into you, steep and sudden. On the way down, the sunlight slashes through the trees, attacking with bright light and black shade. The roads are strewn with nuggets of granite, tree branches, potholes and decomposing badgers. Even after a few dry days, water streams across them. You swallow insects and cling to your brakes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5026401841/" title="Me on Black Mountain by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4089/5026401841_b89a86a44a_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Me on Black Mountain" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is all quite staggeringly beautiful. Ten minutes from leaving an industrial estate in Llanelli, and you&amp;#8217;re here, on top of the world, the chimneys of Port Talbot smoking on the horizon. There was an uphill time-trial, the national championships, I think, on the north face of Black Mountain. The real specialists ride a fixed wheel. I saw a large hawk with swept back wings and an arrow shaped tail. My cycling companion couldn&amp;#8217;t help but laugh at the way I mispronounced Cwmllynfell. Many thanks to Dai Harris, &lt;a href="http://www.byneacc.co.uk/"&gt;Bynea cycling club&lt;/a&gt;, for organising such a great ride.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5026992012/" title="Cwmllynfell by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4132/5026992012_c3f120a9d7_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Cwmllynfell" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-09-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wesley-may-super-grimpeur</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wesley-may-super-grimpeur</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tour of Britain 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2009.html"&gt;I watched the start&lt;/a&gt; of a Tour of Britain stage. This year I caught the end of a stage, joining the crowds gathered on Constitution Hill, a vicious little cobbled climb near the centre of Swansea.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked slowly up the road. A sea mist obscured the view back over Swansea Bay. I stopped about &amp;frac34; of the way up. I waited. The riders were late &amp;#8212; headwinds and rain had slowed their progress over the Black Mountains. I called Dan. He said he was about &amp;#8531; of the way up the hill, with a couple of friends. I walked back down to meet them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car came past. A convoy of police riders. Then nothing. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&amp;#8217;s Brad Wiggins? someone next to me asked. What colour is he wearing? Black with a green band, I said. He rides for Team Sky. I don&amp;#8217;t know where he is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A police 4x4 stormed up the hill, flattening the spectators back against the sides of the road. And now the leading riders were here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4987111756/" title="Heavy going by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4112/4987111756_f22f4fa392_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Heavy going" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d been assuming the pros would demolish the hill. Not so. They made it look hard going, hauling round mighty gears, their spindly bikes buckling beneath them. It&amp;#8217;s true, you get close enough to touch them. Some of these guys are way too big and solid to ride up hills.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-09-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Constitution Hill</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.tourofbritain.co.uk/_ns_race/default.asp?section=stage3_route"&gt;Welsh stage&lt;/a&gt; of the Tour of Britain finishes in Swansea. Soon after 1pm the leading riders hurtle through the city centre along Kingsway, which is where the race will also finish, but not before they&amp;#8217;ve taken on a couple of steep climbs. First Bryn-y-M&amp;ocirc;r, near where Dan lives, then Constitution Hill, which is where I plan to be watching.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; the leading riders will face a last few metres of flat before the road veers upwards and onto over 300 metres of steep cobbles that lead them up onto the Swansea skyline. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hills + cobbles? Ouch!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/w2CURwHjJiw?#t=9s&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/w2CURwHjJiw?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=Constitution+Hill,+Swansea"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; indicated that Constitution Hill featured in the Keith Allen&amp;#8217;s sensitive, wry evocation of a Swansea youth, &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120394/" title="Twin Town, imdb"&gt;Twin Town&lt;/a&gt;. The road is now closed to traffic after too many idiots copied the Lewis twins&amp;#8217; driving stunt (seconds 7 to 17 of the YouTube montage above).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4941877207/" title="At the foot of Constitution Hill by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4140/4941877207_45790f4563.jpg" width="408" height="500" alt="At the foot of Constitution Hill" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode up Constitution Hill on Thursday, on my way back home from Swansea station. The train was 45 minutes late, spoiling my plans to meet the family at Parc Abertawe in time for Toy Story 3. I needed to do something to vent my frustration. It&amp;#8217;s a tough little climb, tougher than it looks from the bottom, especially if you&amp;#8217;re carrying a rucksack with a 15&amp;#8221; laptop in it, but the view from the top over Swansea bay is stunning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4941878625/" title="At the top of Constitution Hill by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4097/4941878625_6ef34d810b.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="At the top of Constitution Hill" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-08-30</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/constitution-hill</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/constitution-hill</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 15, fear and respect</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees.html"&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about the failures and disappointments which made the opening week of this year&amp;#8217;s tour so compelling, and complained that the action had dropped when it should have peaked, in the mountains. Having shaken off the field, Contador and Schleck seemed unable to get to grips with each other. That all changed on stage 15, though again failure and disappointment underpinned the racing. Schleck sprang away from the elite climbers on the Port de Bal&amp;egrave;s, with Contador in hot pursuit. Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain came off but the momentum of his attack continued &amp;#8212; now carried by Contador and a few other elite riders.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve already seen Schleck doesn&amp;#8217;t have the team support Contador does; but he looked cruelly exposed on that mountain road, struggling to re-fit his chain. It took a couple of goes. He had to fend off a motorbike. He needed help from a couple of spectators to shove him back on course. By then, the leader on the road was Contador.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last we were treated to the sight of Schleck racing uphill. He tore up the road. He nearly caught Contador, but the Spaniard was lucky to be in the perfect group for a super-fast descent. At the end of that descent, the end of the stage, Contador had the yellow jersey.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleck was furious. He &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; furious. I think he&amp;#8217;s also wiped out, physically and emotionally. Anger fuelled his final climb up the Bal&amp;egrave;s but a tankful of anger won&amp;#8217;t get take over the Tourmalet. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview afterwards Contador was asked if he was afraid of Schleck. Fear? No, he said. Respect, yes. Contador lost a lot of respect for attacking when the race leader suffered a mechanical failure. Maybe even self-respect. He was jeered on the podium. He &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/news/contador-defends-his-attack-on-the-bales"&gt;toughed it out with the press&lt;/a&gt;, claiming he hadn&amp;#8217;t known about Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain falling off. Later on, from his hotel room, he posted a public apology on &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XdOJLuePexs"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain hadn&amp;#8217;t come off? I think Contador would have caught him. Schleck was already looking back to see who was where. He needed to face forwards and give it everything. I also thought Contador would attack on the final Pyrenean stage. He&amp;#8217;s been holding something back. I thought that he was too classy to accept winning the Tour by beating the clock in a time trial. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m not so sure he would have attacked, when defence and a decent time-trial would have sufficed. He will attack, if only to regain some respect. Sadly, I doubt Schleck has enough left.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 14, Pyrenees</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The first week of the Tour is normally a prelude to the real action &amp;#8212; someone unexpected wears yellow, sprinters stretch their legs, commentators and journalists clock up a few words, everyone looks forward to the real race. This year has seen a first week like no other. Looking back, amazingly, it&amp;#8217;s the failures and disappointments which stand out:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     Cav&amp;#8217;s failure to contest the opening sprints
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Armstrong&amp;#8217;s poor luck and subsequent inability to follow the leaders (and now look how far he has fallen!)
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Frank Schleck&amp;#8217;s broken shoulder, meaning he won&amp;#8217;t be there for his brother
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     yellow jersey Cancellara cancelling the sprint finish at the end of stage 2. How could he do that?
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on. If this opening week offered so much drama, what would we get when the route hit the mountains?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story unfolds. Unimaginably, Andy Schleck beat Contador in the first Alpine stage, and in the next stage the two of them &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers.html"&gt;toyed with each other&lt;/a&gt; briefly then teamed up to demolish any wannabes. Now we&amp;#8217;re in the Pyrenees, where the tour should be decided. Yesterday Contador and Schleck reached stalemate, again, like a joke with no punchline. Come on guys, this race deserves better!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On the subject of Armstrong, has he really cracked, or is he trying to drop so far down the GC that he&amp;#8217;ll be allowed a break-away stage win?)
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 11, sprint battle</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What battle? Understandably lost in the controversy is the fact that Mark Cavendish has roared back into the form he had last year. He leapt away from the pack and took the stage comfortably. No, the real battle was 500m from the line, fought between Cav&amp;#8217;s lead-out man, Mark Renshaw from HTC Columbia, and Julian Dean from Garmin-Transitions. You could see it coming &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;d been barging and shoving on very a fast run-in. Everyone was wound up tight. Dean cut across Renshaw. Either Renshaw had to back down, or he had to force Dean away, or there&amp;#8217;d be an almighty pile-up. Renshaw was furious. He lost his head. He used his head, butting Dean three times with it. Then &amp;#8212; and this did not look good &amp;#8212; he cut in front of Tyler Farrar, the Garmin-Transitions sprinter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this happened in a couple of seconds, at high speed. It did look brutal. At least no one got hurt, but the judges came down hard. Mark Renshaw has been eliminated from the Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sprint finish is all about the individual who gets to the line first, but it&amp;#8217;s also all about the team. Cavendish always stresses his wins are team victories: the HTC Columbia train sets him up, he just has to finish the job. HTC Columbia had already lost one rider, Adam Hansen, on stage 2, evidently without too many adverse effects, but can they do without the world&amp;#8217;s best lead-out man, Mark Renshaw? More importantly, how will Cav respond? He&amp;#8217;s hot-headed and impetuous. I hope he doesn&amp;#8217;t do something stupid.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-11-sprint-battle</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-11-sprint-battle</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 9, dancing climbers</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The best climbers seem to dance up the slopes and today, on the Madeleine, two of the very best performed a wonderful pas de deux. Schleck flashed, Contador darted. The elastic between them pinged and sang. Might their rivals not take advantage of this energy-sapping flirtation? What rivals! A gruelling stage had already unravelled them. Contador and Schleck stopped playing and chased home. The race is between them now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If I attacked one more time I would have dropped myself,&amp;#8221; said Andy Schleck afterwards, but he looked as if he&amp;#8217;d just stepped out of the shower after a good night&amp;#8217;s sleep, rather than completed a mountain stage of the world&amp;#8217;s toughest race. Bring on the Pyrenees. Contador is too classy a rider to win the tour in a time trial. He&amp;#8217;s getting stronger. Watch him attack!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Week One</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, a rest day today, after a week of quite literal thrills and spills. Yesterday provided a fitting finale.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember last year, that final mountain stage on Mont Ventoux? It was meant to decide the general classification but by then Contador, already in yellow, had enough of a lead to ride defensively and cover the attacks. Andy Schleck couldn&amp;#8217;t shake him off. The stage was effectively neutralised. Yesterday, on the first Alpine stage, it looked like Schleck hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped at the summit of Ventoux at all. There he was, still poised on Contador&amp;#8217;s shoulder, a fresh-faced skinny executioner kitted out in white. This time Contador didn&amp;#8217;t look so clever. Schleck may not have taken much time out of his rival but he beat him convincingly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/races/97th-tour-de-france-gt/stage-8/results"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com//2010/07/11/2/bettiniphoto_0056537_1_full_600.jpg" alt="Schleck the skinny executioner"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Stages 0 and 1</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Chapeau, &lt;a href="http://www.itv.com/sport/tourdefrance/"&gt;ITV4&lt;/a&gt;, for the live coverage, even if I can&amp;#8217;t see myself getting to watch much of it. The prologue stage has definitely whetted the appetite. I&amp;#8217;m pleased Cancellara won. &amp;#8220;My body worked at 100% for exactly ten minutes,&amp;#8221; he said. It&amp;#8217;s almost unthinkable that another expert clock-racer, Brad Wiggins, could drop almost a minute over such a short course, but he did. I&amp;#8217;ve read Wiggo&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Pursuit-Glory-Autobiography-Bradley-Wiggins/dp/0752884034"&gt;In Pursuit of Glory: The Autobiography&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; one for the fans, I think, but one thing I did take from it was how accurately Wiggo can calibrate his form on the track. He knows how long it takes for him to ride a kilometre in a covered velodrome to within a second. A wet road in Rotterdam is less predictable, and Wiggo wanted to avoid trouble. Cancellara has more panache and his bike-handling skills are sans pareil. So he won. Can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him attack the &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;cobbled roads&lt;/a&gt; in stage 3.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com/2010/04/09/2/img_0669_600.jpg" alt="Going. To. Be. Carnage"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hardened campaigner got going when the going got tough. Armstrong took a chunk out of Wiggins and other GC rivals in the &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr/2010/TDF/LIVE/us/0/classement/index.html"&gt;prologue&lt;/a&gt;. He also got the first strike in against Contador (let&amp;#8217;s not forget that he lost 22 seconds to the Spaniard over the same stage last year). I&amp;#8217;ll bet he rattles Contador some more on the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/17414049508"&gt;cobbles&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking forwards to the highlights of Stage One this evening, especially when it became obvious it would end with a bunch sprint. About time to see Cavendish stretch his legs. Except it didn&amp;#8217;t happen like that. Cav has had a rotten run-in to the Tour this year. Always volatile and unpredictable, he&amp;#8217;s turning into very a loose cannon. He tumbled on the final bend taking out rival Oscar Freire. Last year no one got close to Cav. And this year other riders would do well to stay away from him. With Cav down the other riders had to improvise the final kilometre and they made a spectacular mess of it, staging a mass pile up instead of a mass sprint. Quelle horreur!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Owl spotting by bike</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mattburns.co.uk"&gt;Matt Burns&lt;/a&gt; spotted a &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/floater81/4742388490/"&gt;barn owl&lt;/a&gt; on a bike ride earlier today &amp;#8212; the first wild owl he&amp;#8217;s ever seen. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="400" height="300" data="http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="intl_lang=en-us&amp;photo_secret=d58646bae4&amp;photo_id=4742388490"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="bgcolor" value="#000000"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377" bgcolor="#000000" allowfullscreen="true" flashvars="intl_lang=en-us&amp;photo_secret=d58646bae4&amp;photo_id=4742388490" height="300" width="400"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barn owls hunt by stealth rather than speed. They fly silently. A well oiled bicycle moves quietly too, making it a fine mobile vantage point for wildlife spotting. Some years ago, I spent a short while working at a serviced office in &lt;a href="http://www.harthampark.com"&gt;Hartham Park&lt;/a&gt; and my daily commute included a bike ride from Chippenham railway station. Sometimes I took the Bath Road (passing the place on Rowden Hill where &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eddie_Cochran#Death"&gt;Eddie Cochran died in a traffic accident&lt;/a&gt;) but usually I took the more rural Chippenham Lane. We were only in that office a year, I think &amp;#8212; it wasn&amp;#8217;t a great location &amp;#8212; but in that short time I saw a family of tawny owls learning to fly. There must have been five or six of them, arranged on branches at various levels of that tree. I saw them several days in a row, and then they were gone, flown the nest. Thanks to google street view I&amp;#8217;ve made that journey again and I&amp;#8217;d say this is the tree. There was less ivy on it back then.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;iframe width="562" height="314" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=hartham+park&amp;amp;sll=53.800651,-4.064941&amp;amp;sspn=20.088699,38.100586&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Biddestone,+Hartham+Park+(N-bound)&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=51.461224,-2.16612&amp;amp;panoid=AwIf4CsdRnZ2RlaSaQp41Q&amp;amp;cbp=13,259.07,,0,5&amp;amp;ll=51.447957,-2.200962&amp;amp;spn=0,0.048237&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;output=svembed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=hartham+park&amp;amp;sll=53.800651,-4.064941&amp;amp;sspn=20.088699,38.100586&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Biddestone,+Hartham+Park+(N-bound)&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=51.461224,-2.16612&amp;amp;panoid=AwIf4CsdRnZ2RlaSaQp41Q&amp;amp;cbp=13,259.07,,0,5&amp;amp;ll=51.447957,-2.200962&amp;amp;spn=0,0.048237&amp;amp;z=14" style="color:#0000FF;text-align:left"&gt;View Larger Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mad March hares raced and tussled in the surrounding fields.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-28</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owl-spotting-by-bike</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owl-spotting-by-bike</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Rider, Kilometer 61-67</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Rider-Tim-Krabbe/dp/0747559414"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/the-rider-krabbe.jpg" alt="The Rider, book cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Rider-Tim-Krabbe/dp/0747559414" title="The Rider, Amazon.co.uk"&gt;The Rider&lt;/a&gt; is Tim Krabb&amp;eacute;&amp;#8217;s account of the fictional Tour de Mont Aigoual, &amp;#8220;the sweetest, toughest race of the season&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s a short book weighing in at around a page for each of the race&amp;#8217;s 137 kilometres. I&amp;#8217;m reading it as slowly as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central character is a rider named Krabb&amp;eacute;. The other characters make up a fictional peleton &amp;#8212; Barth&amp;eacute;lemy, Kl&amp;eacute;ber, Reilhan, etc. &amp;#8212; and their interrelationships build with the rhythm of the stage, overtaking, falling back, regrouping. Lebusque punctures at 55km, but I&amp;#8217;m sure he&amp;#8217;ll be back. At 61km the first descent starts. Krabb&amp;eacute; reflects on the downhill specialists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 1977 Tour de France, the Frenchman Rouxel was the best downhill man. During a descent of the Tourmalet that year, he bridged a gap of four and a half minutes &amp;#8212; in terms of distance, more than five kilometres!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rouxel says: &amp;#8220;I love going downhill. It&amp;#8217;s like skiing. You have to stay loose the whole time, never lock your knees &amp;#8212; they&amp;#8217;re your shock absorbers. You have to stay down on your bike, to keep your centre of gravity as low as possible. Sure, sometimes when I&amp;#8217;m doing ninety and both wheeels leave the ground, it gives me goose bumps too.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Lebusque and the rest, &lt;a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Rouxel"&gt;Charles Rouxel&lt;/a&gt; is as real as the Tour de France. Certainly he rode the 1977 Tour, though apparently he was eliminated on stage 17 for failing to make the cut-off time. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Col_du_Tourmalet" title="Col du Tourmalet, Wikipedia"&gt;The Tourmalet&lt;/a&gt; featured in the second stage of the race which ran from Auch to Pau. Rouxel may well have made up time on the descent but Lucien van Impe went on to take the stage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/charles-rouxel.jpg" alt="Charles Rouxel"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand what Rouxel has to say about technique, and I too love to go fast, but I&amp;#8217;m no descender. There&amp;#8217;s something terrifying about hurtling towards a bend you can&amp;#8217;t see around. Krabb&amp;eacute; puts it better:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have that kind of looseness. I take the curves like a wooden puppet, afraid that my centre of gravity is going to wind up in the ravine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-04-23</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rider-kilometer-6167</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rider-kilometer-6167</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chris Hutt, cycling activist, mischievous plumber</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terrible news. Chris Hutt has been found dead at his home &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/chrishutt"&gt;@chrishutt&lt;/a&gt;. Bristol and cycling has lost such a special man.
   &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CllrJonRogers/status/10814984695"&gt;@CllrJonRogers&lt;/a&gt;, 1:57 AM Mar 21st
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terrible news indeed. I&amp;#8217;m shocked and saddened.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never met Chris myself, but I subscribe to his &lt;a href="http://greenbristolblog.blogspot.com/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and follow him on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/chrishutt"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#8217;ve exchanged emails and tweets.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris styled himself as a &amp;#8220;grumpy old man about town&amp;#8221;, but in reality he contributed much more than moaning. At the start of the year, when the city was gripped by winter, when others complained about the council&amp;#8217;s failure to clear the pavements of ice, he and the indomitable Jon Rogers were out &lt;a href="http://greenbristolblog.blogspot.com/2010/01/ice-man-cometh.html"&gt;shovelling&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bristol-Bath cycle path, the foundation of Sustrans, and ultimately the nomination of Bristol 2010 as Britain&amp;#8217;s first cycling city &amp;#8212; he had a part in all these things, and we will remember him with thanks for this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;#8217;t realise is that Chris Hutt was also:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; the best plumber in the west. He plumbed in the four fountains on the [Bristol-Bath cycle] route and when the fountain on Castle Green was first installed he plumbed it so red wine came out of one side and orange out of another.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.kingswoodpeople.co.uk/news/Tributes-Bristol-cycling-campaigner-dead-home/article-1931446-detail/article.html"&gt;John Grimshaw&lt;/a&gt;, Sustrans.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a photo of that fountain. Isobel and Alex are pretending to be the fish which decorate the frieze on its sides.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/209291883/" title="2005 014 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/86/209291883_1a44d8a556.jpg" width="500" height="374" alt="2005 014" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-03-21</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/chris-hutt</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/chris-hutt</link>
<category>Cycling</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
