<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Rourke, wrestler, barfly, Bukowksi</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=" http://www.bafta.org/awards/film/film-nominations-in-2009,657,BA.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/mickey-rourke-bafta.jpg" alt="Mickey Rourke at the BAFTAs"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mickey Rourke shambles on stage, hunches over the mike, cusses a bit, thanks his best mates for sticking by him, shambles off again. Actors: you never know when they&amp;#8217;re acting and when they&amp;#8217;re not, and I&amp;#8217;m not convinced they do either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rourke&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.bafta.org/awards/film/film-nominations-in-2009,657,BA.html"&gt;best actor gong&lt;/a&gt; comes for his portrayal of Randy &amp;#8220;The Ram&amp;#8221; Robinson in &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1125849/"&gt;The Wrester&lt;/a&gt;, a film I watched with my brother a couple of weeks ago. It&amp;#8217;s a terrific film but makes for uncomfortable viewing: the wheezy soundtrack and out of focus imagery take us directly into Randy&amp;#8217;s world, a world where the wrestling matches may be staged, but the blood, scars and pain are all too real.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/mickey-rourke-the-wrestler.jpg" alt="Randy The Ram Robinson"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface it&amp;#8217;s about a faded wrestler who defies health problems for one last comeback bout; but it&amp;#8217;s tempting to see it as Rourke&amp;#8217;s own story. In The Ram&amp;#8217;s words.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just want to say to you all tonight I&amp;#8217;m very grateful to be here. A lot of people told me that I&amp;#8217;d never wrestle again and that&amp;#8217;s all I do. You know, if you live hard and play hard and you burn the candle at both ends, you pay the price for it. You know in this life you can lose everything you love, everything that loves you. Now I don&amp;#8217;t hear as good as I used to and I forget stuff and I aint as pretty as I used to be but god damn it I&amp;#8217;m still standing here and I&amp;#8217;m The Ram. As times goes by, as times goes by, they say &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s washed up&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s finished&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s a loser&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s all through&amp;#8221;. You know what? The only one that&amp;#8217;s going to tell me when I&amp;#8217;m through doing my thing is you people here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bukowski"&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/e2/Charles_Bukowski_smoking.jpg" alt="Charles Bukowksi" style="float:right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1987, at the peak of his success, Mickey Rourke chose to play writer &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bukowski"&gt;Charles Bukowski&lt;/a&gt; in the film &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092618/"&gt;Barfly&lt;/a&gt;. Bukowski is best known for his books about Henry Chinaski, a womanizing, gambling drunk who lurches from one dead-end job to the next. To what extent are these books autobiographical? I&amp;#8217;m not sure, but I do know Bukowski was sober enough to write a lot of great material. I particularly recommend his first novel, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0061177571?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;Post Office&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0061177571?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/postoffice.gif" alt="Post Office"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rourke shed his pretty boy looks and gained several kilos to play Bukowski in &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092618/"&gt;Barfly&lt;/a&gt;, a film which was also scripted by Bukowski, but now botched plastic sugery and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mickey_Rourke#From_actor_to_boxer"&gt;one bout too many in a boxing ring&lt;/a&gt; have spoiled his looks for real. He remains charismatic, a fine actor, but what other roles can there be for him? Henry Chinaski, fictional post office worker?
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-02-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/rourke-wrestler-barfly-bukowksi.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/rourke-wrestler-barfly-bukowksi.html</link>
<category>Film</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Say no to noisy popcorn!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2008/aug/10/foodanddrink1"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in today&amp;#8217;s Observer says:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;The End&amp;#8217; for popcorn at the movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A growing number of cinemas are barring the snack because it is too downmarket and messy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can cope with downmarket and I&amp;#8217;m tolerant of mess &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s the &lt;strong&gt;noise&lt;/strong&gt; which bugs me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2008/aug/10/foodanddrink1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.mcps.org/sms/popcorn.gif" alt="Bag of popcorn" style="float:right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On holiday last week, on one of those days when the rain didn&amp;#8217;t stop, we went to see what was on at the &lt;a href="http://www.merlincinemas.co.uk/"&gt;Savoy Cinema&lt;/a&gt; in Penzance. They were showing &lt;a href="http://disney.go.com/disneypictures/wall-e/"&gt;WALL-E&lt;/a&gt;, a film I&amp;#8217;d not heard of and which, on the face of it, I would happily have avoided, but one Alex seemed to know all about. He was keen. We paid up and traipsed in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed it. For a big budget film, it was suprisingly radical. For the first hour or so there wasn&amp;#8217;t a single spoken word; the story unfolded through images and sounds (bleeps, squeaks, taps, snatches of music, the sound of a computer booting up, etc.) alone. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the family behind us were scoffing popcorn served up in large and crinkly paper bags. The noise distracted me. But it&amp;#8217;s hard asking people to finish their snack before watching a film when the snack is served in the cinema foyer specifically to be taken in to accompany the show.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-08-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/say-no-to-noisy-popcorn.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/say-no-to-noisy-popcorn.html</link>
<category>Film</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bond, James (cough cough) Bond</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With two young children, Gail and I don&amp;#8217;t get to see as many films as
   we&amp;#8217;d like, but recently we&amp;#8217;ve been lucky enough to catch two.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Babel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first, &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0449467"&gt;Babel&lt;/a&gt;, was showing at the &lt;a href="http://www.watershed.co.uk"&gt;Watershed&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a superb film,
   but what also struck me was that the &lt;a href="http://www.watershed.co.uk"&gt;Watershed&lt;/a&gt; is now an entirely
   non-smoking venue &amp;#8212; and not before time. After too many evenings in
   too many smoky venues I can&amp;#8217;t wait for the new anti-smoking legislation.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second, &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0381061/"&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/a&gt;, was also excellent, and so true in
   spirit to what I recall of the book that I decided to re-visit the
   original. The book has fewer locations, fights and chases, but
   otherwise is indeed quite similar to the film. One difference which
   struck me was the change in Bond&amp;#8217;s smoking habits. It&amp;#8217;s hard to
   imagine the &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0185819/"&gt;Daniel Craig&lt;/a&gt;
   incarnation of Bond smoking &amp;#8212;- I don&amp;#8217;t think he&amp;#8217;d manage to sprint up
   the side of a crane so nimbly.  Yet the original Bond lights up all
   the time. About five pages in, on returning to his hotel room:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; he lit his seventieth cigarette of the day
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;and later, when he&amp;#8217;s setting off for the casino to bankrupt Le Chiffre:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;#8230; he filled a flat, light gunmetal box with fifty of the Morland
   cigarettes with the triple gold band
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think
   &lt;a href="http://www.sonypictures.com/movies/casinoroyale/site/"&gt;Sony&lt;/a&gt; would
   have been quite so keen on placing their products in the movie
   if new Bond had been faithful to this particular habit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend &lt;a href="http://richardbeard.info/html/x20.html"&gt;X20&lt;/a&gt; by Richard Beard.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2007-01-27</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bond-james-cough-cough-bond.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bond-james-cough-cough-bond.html</link>
<category>Film</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
