<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Gower coast half marathon</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I ran the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.endurancelife.com/event.asp?series=36&amp;amp;location=98&quot;&gt;Gower coast half marathon&lt;/a&gt; today. It&amp;#8217;s a cracking route, heading past Fall Bay, round Worms Head, over the top of Rhossili Down, through Hillend, around Broughton Burrows, over Llanmadoc Hill, down to Llangennith, back along the soggy side of Rhossili Down to Mewslade, and then up and down the coast path to the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wind had dropped and the sun was out. It was wet and muddy underfoot after all the recent rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly I found myself up with the leaders coming over Rhossili Down. Slowing up would probably be a good idea but running along Llangennith beach in the sunshine felt wonderful. The sand was firm and the waves were high and white. By Llanmadoc Hill I even had a small lead but by now my legs felt leaden. Running through the marshland below Rhossili Down was nasty. I wanted it to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I ran a half marathon (2007) it took 1 hour and 22 minutes. Although the Gower course was a mile or two longer, and despite the challenging terrain, I reckoned I&amp;#8217;d be able to finish it in 1:40. Just keep going until 1:40, I told myself. I kept checking my watch. 1:40 passed. I slipped and stumbled along one of those rocky rural lanes which becomes a stream at this time of year. 1:45. I was on the coast path above Mewslade, my favourite beach. 1:50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually finished with a time of 1:52:51. That&amp;#8217;s about twice as long as any of my training runs. I failed to spot the very last route marker and ended up going a few extra metres along a lane to the finish line rather than directly through a field &amp;#8212; which sadly meant Gail, Isobel and Alex didn&amp;#8217;t get to see me running. They did see me awarded my prize, though. A medal and some tokens to future Endurance Life events. Yes, I won!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the tokens, and thanks too for organising such a great event, but I think I shall retire unbeaten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-11-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-coast-half-marathon</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-coast-half-marathon</link>
<category>Gower</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hunting razor shells at Oxwich</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t bother hunting razor shells unless high tide is over 39 feet, David says. Today the tide flowed up to 42 feet, about as high as it gets, and when it dropped, in the middle of the afternoon, the sun shone and the wind was down: conditions were perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5068285982/&quot; title=&quot;Huntsman and quarry by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4128/5068285982_461a59d67c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;447&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Huntsman and quarry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gail brought salt, a 3kg bag. David supplied his trusty squeezy bottles and a couple of buckets. He showed us how. You walk backwards, disturbing the sand with your feet. Sometimes the razor shells flick water at you. Otherwise, you&amp;#8217;re looking for their breathing holes, which are supposed to be keyhole-shaped. Aim the squeezy bottle into the hole. Squirt in salty water. The razor shell coughs and froths then slides out, gasping. Grab a hold of it. Watch it kick its muscular foot, in and out. Into the bucket it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5067678939/&quot; title=&quot;Cooking them up by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4084/5067678939_31dcc38d6d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; alt=&quot;Cooking them up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collected some cockles too. A Chinese family were digging for clams. Higher up the beach, they&amp;#8217;d collected a barrel full of winkles. We ate our catch at the top of the beach, burying the remains in the sand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-10-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/hunting-razor-shells-at-oxwich</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/hunting-razor-shells-at-oxwich</link>
<category>Gower</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Gower Triathlon, 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foor.co.uk&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/foor-quantum.png&quot; alt=&quot;Foor quantum&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wetsuit is designed for warmth and durability. Getting it on and off is a struggle, and any extended swim turns into a battle with wet neoprene. Contrast this with a triathlon wetsuit, which is flexible, taut and sleek, the sort of thing a porpoise would look good in. I had no intention of spending money on a triathlon wetsuit, though. What&amp;#8217;s the point in forking out when I might not even like triathlons? Besides, not having a proper wetsuit was a good excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael ruined that strategy. He turned up last night with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foor.co.uk&quot;&gt;Foor Quantum F3&lt;/a&gt; racing wetsuit. It&amp;#8217;s too small for me, it might fit you, give it a try in the bath, he said. Caveat emptor and all that. Good luck tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It fitted. When, at last, I marched into Port Eynon bay alongside 326 similarly clad athletes, a shade after 7 o&amp;#8217;clock this morning, it felt good. I tried a few strokes. Oh, it was good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I wasn&amp;#8217;t. Despite the suit, I found myself flailing and out of breath. No one warned me about triathlon being a contact sport. Swimmers barged, kicked and gouged. The orange buoys marking the route had seemed so close together from the shore. At sea-level I could barely make them out on the foamy horizon. And then I was trying to cut a racing line around one at the same time as a hundred others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the swim about half way down the field. I felt pretty dejected coming back up the beach. Thank goodness some people were cheering me on. I felt much better once I&amp;#8217;d got on my bike. The rolling course suited me. I know these roads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding near the centre line coming up Cefn Bryn, overtaking.  A van coming down the hill. A sheep leapt from the bracken and dashed through a cluster of cyclists. The van slammed on its brakes. The sheep stopped abruptly, all four legs rigid, eyes goggling, then sprang back into the verge. It sprinted alongside the race for another couple of hundred metres before finally veering across the road and safely away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain came. My shoes filled with water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4830108778/&quot; title=&quot;End of the cycle leg by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4078/4830108778_13fc408798_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;541&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;End of the cycle leg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;#8217;d been told about training for a triathlon: try running immediately after cycling, otherwise you won&amp;#8217;t know what it feels like. Good advice! Shame I ignored it, choosing instead to find out on race day. At least I didn&amp;#8217;t fall over. I stumbled into the transition area, racked my bike, swigged some water. Then off on the run, the best bit of which was finishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/Final.xls&quot;&gt;results&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My entry reads: 357, Thomas Guest, MV, M, 13:19, 3:16, 45:28, 20:52, 1:22:53, 30, 8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;357 was my race number. MV means Male Veteran. M means Male. The agony of the swim lasted barely 13 minutes. I then spent over 3 minutes getting ready for the cycling. 45 and a half minutes on the bike was good, my best stage, and just under 21 minutes for the run and second transition isn&amp;#8217;t too bad. I came 30th overall, and 8th out of around 100 male veterans, amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I do another one? I like sports which involve getting from A to B. For me, the feeling you get when you can cover ground efficiently, in control, you can&amp;#8217;t beat it. Now if I could get that feeling when swimming &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my dad and Fynn for coming along to support me, to everyone else who cheered me on &amp;#8212; you made a big difference, thanks &amp;#8212; to Michael for lending me the wetsuit, and to the organisers and marshals who ran everything with efficiency and good humour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-triathlon-2010</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-triathlon-2010</link>
<category>Gower</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Potholes, Ponies and other cycling hazards</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t even see it. My bike has carbon fibre forks which are meant to absorb shocks but the impact traveled up through my arms and shoulders and shook my teeth. I heard something clatter on the road. The pump! Thrown clean off the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4401185333/&quot; title=&quot;Evil pothole by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4049/4401185333_87efcf04f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Evil pothole&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/talking_point/8510907.stm&quot;&gt;pothole&lt;/a&gt; square on and at speed. If I&amp;#8217;d caught its edge, it could well have been me on the road. I collected the pump and rode off slowly, feeling for damage. Handlebars need tilting back down. Front wheel, usable, but judders when the brakes are applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened on the final unlit stretch of my regular Tuesday morning commute from Reynoldston to Swansea railway station, where I catch the 06:28 on to Bristol. A clear sky, the full moon hanging low. I&amp;#8217;d just passed the Three Crosses turning. In a few hundred metres I&amp;#8217;d ride over the cattle grid which marks the end of the common. I&amp;#8217;m all too aware this section of the North Gower road has a lunar surface. My usual tactic is to ride close to the centre line, which avoids the worst of the craters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of last year, making the same journey, I was hurtling down the road which goes over Cefn Bryn. My colleague Chris, who grew up in Carmarthen, knows this road as &amp;#8220;the wobbly road&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s straight but not level. In a car, with a clear run, you can pretend you&amp;#8217;re on a roller-coaster; on a bike, in the dark, the troughs and crests limit your vision. Something large and pale loomed in the middle of the road. I slammed on both brakes. In front of me a white horse stood quite still. Unperturbed by my presence, it leant forward, stretching its legs, and breathed out a cloud. I wheeled slowly round it. Next time I&amp;#8217;ll be more careful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-03-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/potholes-and-ponies</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/potholes-and-ponies</link>
<category>Gower</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
