<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>A Corinthian Endeavour: The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/20871409082/in/dateposted-friend/" title="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5776/20871409082_524894d533_z.jpg" width="451" height="640" alt="A Corinthian Endeavour"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in June I went to the launch of Paul Jones&amp;#8217; book &amp;#8220;A Corinthian Endeavour &amp;#8212; The Story of the National Hill Climb Championships&amp;#8221;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great talk and it&amp;#8217;s a great book. Here in the UK, we don&amp;#8217;t have Alpine cols or Pyrennean passes. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs"&gt;We have hills&lt;/a&gt;. Hills with erratic gradients and peculiar names &amp;#8212; Nick-o-Pendle, Mow Cop, Pea Royd Lane &amp;#8212; hills which, at the end of the cycling season, draw nascent professionals and amateur specialists to battle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-header="false" data-footer="false" data-context="false"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/18495855150/in/dateposted-public/" title="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/458/18495855150_4d6165f574_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="PJ wraps up with Larkin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones has the credentials to tell the tale: an unashamed fan and a talented writer, he is himself a tidy competitor. The book begins with him interviewing Vic Clarke, the man who finished second in the inaugural national hill climb championships in 1944 and who would go on to win the event three times. Also present is Lyn Hamel, a current competitor and multiple champion herself. When Jones offers biscuits (Marks and Spencers Belgian chocolate selection!) both champions decline: for climbers, gravity is the enemy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gravity isn&amp;#8217;t the only enemy. Competitors don&amp;#8217;t race head to head. The courses are too short and the roads too narrow. Instead they face off against the clock. The fastest time wins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the book continues Jones deftly weaves the history of the championships around more interviews with their protagonists. There&amp;#8217;s Chris Boardman, who set and still holds several records. There are other less familiar names: Wilson, Sydney, Armitage, Dobbin, Pettinger.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/anti-gravity-specialists/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cyclinguphill.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Screen-Shot-2015-06-24-at-10.00.13.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered Paul Jones via his &lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/"&gt;Traumfahrrad&lt;/a&gt; cycling blog, a forum where he allows himself more freedom to poke fun and sound off. His blog describes the joy and pain of early morning training rides. He chortles at triathletes who get their socks wrong. You&amp;#8217;ll also find the details of his own assaults on the hill climbs: despite his self-effacement he&amp;#8217;s clearly a feared and respected rider. In the book, though, he reins himself in and logs the facts. The who, what, how and when are painstakingingly researched and recorded. Gear inches matter more to the author than, apparently, to Chris Boardman, who can barely remember if he took part in a race which he won, let alone the number of teeth on his sprocket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, though, Jones takes a step back from the details. In one chapter he asks: &amp;#8220;When is a Hill not a Hill?&amp;#8221; A good championship course:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;#8230; should be run on closed roads [&amp;#8230;] Riders should be digging out their hill climb bikes and making &lt;a href="http://cyclinguphill.com/marginal-gains-hill-climb-bike" title=""Tejvan Pettinger strips down his bike"&gt;absurd modifications&lt;/a&gt; for no real gain [&amp;#8230;] each competitor needs to be left flailing on a grass bank like a dying goldfish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contrast this to the 2011 championship on Long Hill:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://traumfahrrad.com/2015/08/24/below-the-line/"&gt;&lt;img style="width:500px" src="https://scontent-lhr3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xft1/v/t1.0-9/11796216_10207229514877458_7189614863695398022_n.jpg?oh=a2544be1e9e0a4883cd4531b8946519b&amp;oe=5671E221"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the last, Jones claims hill climbers are ascetics in search of transcendence who tilt their caps backwards. By battling time and human frailty paradoxically they escape it and themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first thing&lt;/br&gt;I have understood:&lt;/br&gt;Time is the echo of an axe&lt;/br&gt;Within a wood.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-08-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-story-of-the-national-hill-climb-championships</link>
<category>Hill</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>100 Greatest Cycling Climbs</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/100-Greatest-Cycling-Climbs-Cyclists/dp/0711231206"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/100-greatest-cycling-climbs.jpg" alt="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing in the rain on Constitution Hill, Swansea, waiting for the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010.html"&gt;Tour of Britain&lt;/a&gt; to arrive, I watched a lanky chap striding up the cobbles. He carried a road sign over his shoulder &amp;#8212; a red triangle, a warning. The triangle contained a picture of a slope and the number 100.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign carrier was Simon Warren, author of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/100-Greatest-Cycling-Climbs-Cyclists/dp/0711231206"&gt;100 Greatest Cycling Climbs&lt;/a&gt;, seizing the chance to advertise his book on what turned out to be the decisive climb of this year&amp;#8217;s tour. Later that evening I visited the Tour of Britain website and entered a competition to win the book. Now, a few weeks later, I&amp;#8217;m holding a copy in my hands.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a shamelessly straight-up book. 100 climbs: arranged, graded, defeated. Constitution Hill, for example, rates 4/10.  Remember though, on this scale, 1/10 means pretty damn tough, and 10/10 means lung-bustingly-knee-wrenchingly-ball-breakingly tough. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle.html"&gt;Porlock Hill&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; the toughest I&amp;#8217;ve ever taken on &amp;#8212; weighs in at 9/10. There are harder climbs, oh yes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maps are useless, the route descriptions redundant (basically: the road goes up). The pictures are spoiled by the garish triangles slapped across them. It&amp;#8217;s not the kind of book you&amp;#8217;d imagine enjoying.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5103981499/" title="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4108/5103981499_9c290fb50a.jpg" width="500" height="377" alt="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved it. I read it from cover to cover, climb upon climb, savouring its remorseless rhythm. It&amp;#8217;s a celebration of Britain&amp;#8217;s hills: &amp;#8220;the cyclists&amp;#8217; theaters, our stadia&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s a monomaniac&amp;#8217;s catalogue, the diary of an obsessive. In the author&amp;#8217;s own words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The super-smooth road heads up straight and steep, first at 20%, then for a short while 25% before easing back into 20% and bending gently to the right. Near the summit comes the hardest section, a left-hand bend ushering in 30 metres of leg-breaking 25% before finally levelling as you enter woods and rumble, stars in your eyes, across a cattle grid to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-10-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs</link>
<category>Hill</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Porlock Hill on a bicycle</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The road signs warn you early about Porlock Hill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3789309966/" title="Early warning by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2642/3789309966_f8b3eb8720.jpg" width="390" height="500" alt="Early warning" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you snub the alternative route and reach the base of the hill you&amp;#8217;ll be offered the option of the scenic woodland Toll Road.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3789305024/" title="Decisions by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2537/3789305024_d59fcc0ff7.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Decisions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s true, the air here is acrid with the smell of burned out brakes and clutches &amp;#8212; maybe that&amp;#8217;s why the house is for sale &amp;#8212; and you&amp;#8217;ll see a line of cars parked hard against roadside while pale-faced drivers recover.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.activeexmoor.com/site/cycling/exmoor-cycle-route/map"&gt;Exmoor cycle route&lt;/a&gt;, signed in the picture, follows the toll road too. That&amp;#8217;ll be a pound please!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went straight up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road climbs approximately 400 m (1,300 ft) in less than 2 miles (3.2 km) up onto Exmoor: a very steep hill with gradients of up to 1 in 4 and hairpin bends. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A39_road#Porlock_Hill"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My normal tactic when cycling uphill is not to use the lowest gear: keep it in reserve in case the going gets &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; tough. Porlock Hill blew that strategy apart on the first switchback. For the rest of the climb I was in bottom gear, out of the pedals, sweating and yawing like a porpoise
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I reached the top of the steep bit my legs were jelly. The road continued to climb, albeit more gently, for some way. A few miles on, the A39 from Lynmouth to Lynton is equally steep, but for a mercifully short section.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the return journey this morning from Combe Martin to Taunton, taking the B3558 across the top of Exmoor. It&amp;#8217;s a rolling route but nowhere near as severe as the coast road. This time my enemy was filthy weather. It felt like riding through a sodden sponge. Rain bounced up from the road and the wind shook great gobs of water from the trees as I passed beneath. Does Alberto Contador ever stop to wring out his socks, I wondered?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     Soaking in Simonsbath.
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Drenched at Exford.
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Wet through by Wheddon Cross.
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bag of &lt;a href="http://www.rolysfudge.co.uk/"&gt;Roly&amp;#8217;s lemon and stem ginger fudge&lt;/a&gt; dispelled the gloom and sped me on my way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rolysfudge.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.rolysfudge.co.uk/images/serve.jpg" alt="Roly's fudge"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-08-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle</link>
<category>Hill</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
