<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>The Secret Blackbird</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What a treat, to be &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow.html"&gt;back&lt;/a&gt; at the zoo education centre for the launch of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/secret-blackbird.html"&gt;The Secret Blackbird &amp;mdash; the alarming case of the missing birds&lt;/a&gt;! The book investigates the summer-time absence of garden birds, but before considering this central mystery Geraldine posed some other puzzles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do herons fly overhead when a ground mist covers the downs?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do more long-tailed tits fly out of a bush than flew into it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do pied wagtails run in circles round lamp posts?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never counted birds in and out of bushes but I reckon I know the answer to the second one: by the time you notice a tit fly into a bush there&amp;#8217;s probably a few others in there already; and you watch them all fly out. Geraldine suggests the discrepancy is always one &amp;#8212; the lone anchor bird which discreetly reconnoitres the bush before giving the others the OK to proceed. So you see, the mystery is all about point of view.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for herons. When the downs are covered in mist Geraldine looks up more. Have you noticed, she added, the way wood-pigeons dive in and out of the mist, like a dolphin? Why do they do that? Lubrication, to stop their wings creaking!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5752121266/" title="Crowded nest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2365/5752121266_4af54dcacc_n.jpg" width="320" height="267" alt="Crowded nest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pied wagtails in our garden do run in circles but not around things and not right now, they&amp;#8217;re too busy feeding five hungry fledglings. I&amp;#8217;d assumed it was a courtship display. Geraldine had no definitive answer either. By now, the audience was involved: where do swifts sleep, and what happens to swallows in winter? The swifts fly up high in the evening and wake lower down in the morning, still on the wing. The swallows conglobulate together, by flying round and round, and then all in a heap throw themselves under water, and lye in the bed of a river.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dru read a haiku. Deborah Harvey read two poems from &lt;a href="http://www.indigodreamsbookshop.com/#/deborah-harvey/4552913959"&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The birds, it turns out, aren&amp;#8217;t missing, they&amp;#8217;re moulting. Low on energy after the nesting season and barely able to fly due to lack of feathers, they lie low, avoiding predators. In the summer of 2010 Geraldine watched a blackbird &amp;#8212; the secret blackbird &amp;#8212; go through this process, and now she retold the story, reading from her book. Dru signalled the part of the bird using a set of semaphore flags.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fbelvedere%2Fsets%2F72157628893181051%2F&amp;set_id=72157628893181051&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more poems, the final one acted out with a soft toy and a star.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a very fine book indeed. Dru has surpassed herself with the illustrations, which mix avian character studies and cartoons.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-05-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-secret-blackbird</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Owls, trains, turkeys and other friends of the RWA</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803013211/" title="Wild Turkey by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7141/6803013211_5e35ca7ed2_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Wild Turkey"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bird stands in judgement outside the main gallery at the &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/" title="Royal West of England Academy"&gt;Royal West of England Academy&lt;/a&gt;. The glass on the bar once contained bourbon whiskey &amp;#8212; look closely and you can see an empty Wild Turkey miniature.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turkey&amp;#8217;s by &lt;a href="http://filthyluker.org/"&gt;filthy luker&lt;/a&gt;. He works with pigeons too &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://filthyluker.org"&gt;&lt;img src="http://filthyluker.org/wp-content/gallery/manifestations/08pigeon_english_by_filthy_luker_UK.jpg" alt="Urban birds" width="600px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; and monsters!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3364983737/" title="Kraken invades RWA by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3574/3364983737_cd574805b1.jpg" width="500" height="399" alt="Kraken invades RWA"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now filthy luker is &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/whats-on/exhibitions/2012/01/exhibitions-filthy-luker/"&gt;artist in residence&lt;/a&gt; at the RWA. Also in residence at the RWA &amp;#8212; just outside, on the balcony, where those tentacles were &amp;#8212; is Damien Hirst&amp;#8217;s outsize collection box, Charity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803014231/" title="Charity by Damien by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7024/6803014231_6b6b6665a3.jpg" width="500" height="323" alt="Charity by Damien"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean to say: the RWA is Bristol&amp;#8217;s finest exhibition space and it puts on Bristol&amp;#8217;s finest exhibitions. The juxtaposition of classical architecture and &lt;a href="http://www.crimesofpassion.info/"&gt;urban art&lt;/a&gt; works well. Classical paintings fit in superbly too: last year&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz.html"&gt;Robert Lenkiewicz&lt;/a&gt; retrospective was stunning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It costs to get in though. It cost &amp;pound;4 last year and now it costs &amp;pound;5. That&amp;#8217;s quite a lot for a show you&amp;#8217;re not sure you&amp;#8217;ll like. Often the shows you&amp;#8217;re not sure you&amp;#8217;ll like are the ones worth seeing, and seeing again. That&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;m a &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/support-us/friends-patrons/"&gt;Friend&lt;/a&gt;. I work around the corner and can head over whenever the computer screen makes me dizzy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6800313715/" title="Friend of the RWA by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7013/6800313715_c6755919bf.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Friend of the RWA"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Lane made the bird on the card from scrap metal. I&amp;#8217;m not sure &lt;a href="http://is.gd/fNQRas"&gt;what type of bird&lt;/a&gt; it is. An archetypal mix of hornbill/stork/flamingo maybe? In the gallery behind the turkey are more birds, owls, by Ivor Abrahams, along with his interesting 2&amp;#189; dimensional sculptures and some tiresome garden things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6803013435/" title="One of Ivor Abrahams' owls by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7009/6803013435_0ba8e39b05.jpg" width="461" height="500" alt="One of Ivor Abrahams' owls"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quite liked the show until I read what he had to say on the &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/local/views/uploads/documents/1327919367_20120130102927_17542851114f2671071a0fd6_93619033_592086275_8114811666.pdf"&gt;&amp;#8220;interpretation panel&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sculptures, collages, prints and drawings of Ivor Abrahams occupy a very particular place in British 20th Century art. No other artist has attempted to do what he has done &amp;#8212; to create an entirely new kind of polychrome sculpture which operates effectively between painting and sculpture &amp;#8212; and achieved such a catalogue of notable successes in the process. Essentially subversive, Abrahams has also gained a reputation for a wicked wit and a generally argumentative demeanour. Nothing is sacred, particularly the established names of the past. As he has admitted: &amp;#8220;I always enjoyed the pomposity of academic sculpture, the grandiosity and rhetoric. The edifying or inspirational nature of the art has always led me to treat it with the greatest of disrespect.&amp;#8221; That irreverence has fuelled his career, and helped him make of the sum of destructions a newly-constructed vision of his own work. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidshepherd.com"&gt;&lt;img width="600px" src="http://www.davidshepherd.com/davidshepherd-elephantsatamboseli.jpg" alt="Elephants at Amboseli, David Shepherd" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside, and by contrast, are a number of paintings and prints by David Shepherd. They aren&amp;#8217;t to my taste but they most certainly were when I was younger (the animal ones, not the trains and planes). I can&amp;#8217;t argue with &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/whats-on/exhibitions/2012/02/exhibitions-david-shepherd/"&gt;his attitude&lt;/a&gt; either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Shepherd paints every day of his life. Now aged eighty, the famed wildlife, aviation and steam train artist describes his life as &amp;#8216;a series of disasters&amp;#8217; &amp;#8212; David Shepherd&amp;#8217;s career has been shaped by serendipity. Rejected by the Slade School of Art, David planned to train as a bus driver. A chance encounter with artist Robin Goodwin resulted in a three-year apprenticeship &amp;#8212; a first for Goodwin, who revelled in the challenge, and a life-changing opportunity for Shepherd.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodwin taught Shepherd commercially as well as artistically. &amp;#8220;Throwing paint at the wall and &amp;#8216;expressing yourself&amp;#8217; doesn&amp;#8217;t pay the bills&amp;#8221;, taught Robin. &amp;#8220;Artists, like everyone else, have to work eight hours and more a day, seven days a week, to meet their responsibilities.&amp;#8221; These words have informed Shepherd&amp;#8217;s work, and he is now one of the UK&amp;#8217;s most financially rewarded artists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidshepherd.com"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.davidshepherd.com/davidshepherd-overtheforth.jpg" width="600px" alt="Over the Forth, David Shepherd"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-02-01</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owls-trains-turkeys-and-other-friends-of-the-rwa</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/owls-trains-turkeys-and-other-friends-of-the-rwa</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Still Lives, Lenkiewicz, summarised</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5781189874/" title="Shrouded by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3033/5781189874_51379c43ec.jpg" width="500" height="452" alt="Shrouded"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bumped into Nick in the RWA gallery at lunch time. He happened to be there because he wanted to see the damage done to the David Backhouse sculpture at the front of the building, and then he&amp;#8217;d realised there was an exhibition on, and entry was free. So why not?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told Nick he was lucky, this was the final day of the Lenkiewicz exhibition. It seemed ironic that the publicity resulting from an act of vandalism should draw someone into a show which should have been more than capable of generating its own buzz.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve visited the show a number of times and I want to record my response now it&amp;#8217;s over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite stunning. It has been a privilege to enjoy the work of one person displayed with the space and scale it deserves. Lenkiewicz&amp;#8217;s skill as a painter is breathtaking. He paints people, fabrics, ghosts, lemons, interiors, mirrors, memento mori. He does colour. He arranges. He goes large. He paints details.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/image-gallery/miscellaneous/1994-retrospective-birmingham-nec/mr-earl-funeral-director-and-family-co"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/files/images/15ROL_P75S.jpg" width="500px" alt="Mr Earl, funeral director, and family, in coffin warehouse"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The huge canvases in the main halls which arrange vagrants, the elderly, the disabled, in classical tableaux; these were my favourites at first. I especially like the burial of John Kynance and the funeral director&amp;#8217;s family group portrait posed in the coffin warehouse. I tend to skip through the next room, the one where the artist paints himself with naked women draped around him. Increasingly I dwell in the final room, the one with the solo portraits. Here characters like Albert Ernest Fisher, known as &amp;#8220;The Bishop&amp;#8221;, who appear in various roles elsewhere in the exhibition, figure simply as themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/image-gallery/themed-projects/project-20-addictive-behaviour/robbie"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/files/images/20ROL_Robbie.jpg" width="500px" alt="Robbie, by Robert Lenkiewicz"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-05-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-lenkiewicz-summarised</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-lenkiewicz-summarised</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.robertlenkiewicz.org/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/the-burial-of-john-kynance.jpg" alt="The Burial of John Kynance"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Pike; Death; Doc; Terence P. D. Stott aka &amp;#8216;Blue&amp;#8217;; James Foster aka &amp;#8216;Harmonica Jim&amp;#8217;; Taff; Barney; Victor Jonson/alias/James Howard aka &amp;#8216;Cockney Jim&amp;#8217;; Cyril Hocking aka &amp;#8216;Mephistopheles&amp;#8217;; Wee John; Ghost of Diogenes; and Edwin MacKenzie, aka Diogenes, attend the Burial of John Kynance in a painting by Robert Lenkiewicz currently on display in an &lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/currexh.htm" title="Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz, RWA Bristol"&gt;exhibition&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the Royal West of England Academy, Bristol.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene is viewed from the coffin of the recently deceased John Kynance. Diogenes features twice, once as his ghost and once as himself. You&amp;#8217;ll find him elsewhere in the exhibition too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rwa.org.uk/currexh.htm" title="Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz, RWA Bristol"&gt;Still Lives, by Robert Lenkiewicz&lt;/a&gt;, is a stunning exhibition. The RWA galleries are spacious, light and elegant &amp;#8212; well suited to displaying Lenkiewicz&amp;#8217;s masterful paintings. I will revisit this show many times over the next few weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/still-lives-by-robert-lenkiewicz</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Curious crow, cantankerous goose, life saving Puffin</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to be at the zoo education centre last night for the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolzoo.org.uk/avon-gorge-and-downs-events" title="Bristol Zoo event listings"&gt;launch&lt;/a&gt; of Geraldine Taylor and Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s new book, &lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt;. The evening included readings from the book, mince pies, soft toys, photography, clippings from the Bristol Evening Post, poetry, tea, dramatic reconstructions, slide shows, damson vodka. Yes, you had to be there.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;The Case of the Curious Crow&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful book, beautifully observed and exquisitely illustrated. For example, here&amp;#8217;s Dru Marland&amp;#8217;s picture of the fox which Geraldine Taylor saw on Zoo Banks, head back, catching hailstones in its mouth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beingdrusilla.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-case-of-the-curious-crow/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2718/4293238314_17bce23898.jpg" alt="Fox and hailstones"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geraldine Taylor produced a stuffed goose, prompting us to remember &lt;a href="http://www.thisisbristol.co.uk/news/Goose-terrorised-drinkers-remembered/article-2554802-detail/article.html"&gt;Sylvester, Bristol harbour&amp;#8217;s most famous resident&lt;/a&gt;. When Sylvester died on the final day of this year&amp;#8217;s harbour festival the news made the front page of the Bristol Evening Post. Mr Rankin, who runs Number Seven Boat Trips, paid this handsome tribute:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;He lived a full and eventful life attacking people outside various pubs &amp;#8230; We all loved him dearly but he had a big personality and pecked me in all sorts of places. We&amp;#8217;re going to make a coffin and he is going to be buried with full military honours.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sylvester did indeed get a maritime send off. He was ferried from the swan feeding station at Welsh Back down to the Ostrich pub, where he was buried.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a break for refreshments Keith Taylor presented a slide show about pioneering wildlife photographers, the Kearton brothers. I think that&amp;#8217;s Richard Kearton supporting Cherry Kearton for a hedge nest shot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam349.jpg" alt="How to photograph a nest in a hedge"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There they are again, up a tree.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1103.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam343.jpg" alt="Photographing a nest in a tree"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick web search found the complete text of their book &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/index.html" title="With Nature and a Camera"&gt;With Nature and a Camera&lt;/a&gt; online at the Glasgow Digital Library. Like everything I encountered last night it&amp;#8217;s packed with character. The photos of birds nesting on the cliffs of St Kilda are stunning, all the more so when you see the lengths they took to get them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0213.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam091.jpg" alt="Gannet and young" style="align:top"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam1102.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam336.jpg" alt="Method of descending a cliff" style="align:top"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about this for a &lt;a href="http://gdl.cdlr.strath.ac.uk/keacam/keacam0312.htm"&gt;bird-related escape&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years ago a girl, whilst watching the men collect eggs on the Doon, had her petticoats ballooned by a sudden squall of wind, and was lifted clean over the cliff. She fell one hundred and eighty feet without a break, and alighted on a ledge which was covered with earth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cragsmen descended to pick up what they very naturally supposed to be the dead body of the poor child, but were surprised to find that she was still alive. Her head had entered a large Puffin burrow, and the force of the blow been expended upon her shoulders. This undoubtedly saved her, and although she hung a whole week between life and death in an unconscious condition, she ultimately made a complete recovery, and was a fine buxom lassie at the time of our visit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-12-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/curious-crow</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>100 Greatest Cycling Climbs</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.franceslincoln.co.uk/en/C/0/Book/1890/100_Greatest_Cycling_Climbs.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.franceslincoln.co.uk/content/45/5645" alt="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs" style="float:left"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing in the rain on Constitution Hill, Swansea, waiting for the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010.html"&gt;Tour of Britain&lt;/a&gt; to arrive, I watched a lanky chap striding up the cobbles. He carried a road sign over his shoulder &amp;#8212; a red triangle, a warning. The triangle contained a picture of a slope and the number 100.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sign carrier was Simon Warren, author of &lt;a href="http://www.franceslincoln.co.uk/en/C/0/Book/1890/100_Greatest_Cycling_Climbs.html"&gt;100 Greatest Cycling Climbs&lt;/a&gt;, seizing the chance to advertise his book on what turned out to be the decisive climb of this year&amp;#8217;s tour. Later that evening I visited the Tour of Britain website and entered a competition to win the book. Now, a few weeks later, I&amp;#8217;m holding a copy in my hands.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a shamelessly straight-up book. 100 climbs: arranged, graded, defeated. Constitution Hill, for example, rates 4/10.  Remember though, on this scale, 1/10 means pretty damn tough, and 10/10 means lung-bustingly-knee-wrenchingly-ball-breakingly tough. &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle.html"&gt;Porlock Hill&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; the toughest I&amp;#8217;ve ever taken on &amp;#8212; weighs in at 9/10. There are harder climbs, oh yes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maps are useless, the route descriptions redundant (basically: the road goes up). The pictures are spoiled by the garish triangles slapped across them. It&amp;#8217;s not the kind of book you&amp;#8217;d imagine enjoying.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5103981499/" title="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4108/5103981499_9c290fb50a.jpg" width="500" height="377" alt="100 Greatest Cycling Climbs" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved it. I read it from cover to cover, climb upon climb, savouring its remorseless rhythm. It&amp;#8217;s a celebration of Britain&amp;#8217;s hills: &amp;#8220;the cyclists&amp;#8217; theaters, our stadia&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s a monomaniac&amp;#8217;s catalogue, the diary of an obsessive. In the author&amp;#8217;s own words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The super-smooth road heads up straight and steep, first at 20%, then for a short while 25% before easing back into 20% and bending gently to the right. Near the summit comes the hardest section, a left-hand bend ushering in 30 metres of leg-breaking 25% before finally levelling as you enter woods and rumble, stars in your eyes, across a cattle grid to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-10-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/100-greatest-cycling-climbs</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Rider, Kilometer 61-67</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Rider-Tim-Krabbe/dp/0747559414"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/the-rider-krabbe.jpg" alt="The Rider, book cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Rider-Tim-Krabbe/dp/0747559414" title="The Rider, Amazon.co.uk"&gt;The Rider&lt;/a&gt; is Tim Krabb&amp;eacute;&amp;#8217;s account of the fictional Tour de Mont Aigoual, &amp;#8220;the sweetest, toughest race of the season&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s a short book weighing in at around a page for each of the race&amp;#8217;s 137 kilometres. I&amp;#8217;m reading it as slowly as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central character is a rider named Krabb&amp;eacute;. The other characters make up a fictional peleton &amp;#8212; Barth&amp;eacute;lemy, Kl&amp;eacute;ber, Reilhan, etc. &amp;#8212; and their interrelationships build with the rhythm of the stage, overtaking, falling back, regrouping. Lebusque punctures at 55km, but I&amp;#8217;m sure he&amp;#8217;ll be back. At 61km the first descent starts. Krabb&amp;eacute; reflects on the downhill specialists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 1977 Tour de France, the Frenchman Rouxel was the best downhill man. During a descent of the Tourmalet that year, he bridged a gap of four and a half minutes &amp;#8212; in terms of distance, more than five kilometres!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rouxel says: &amp;#8220;I love going downhill. It&amp;#8217;s like skiing. You have to stay loose the whole time, never lock your knees &amp;#8212; they&amp;#8217;re your shock absorbers. You have to stay down on your bike, to keep your centre of gravity as low as possible. Sure, sometimes when I&amp;#8217;m doing ninety and both wheeels leave the ground, it gives me goose bumps too.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Lebusque and the rest, &lt;a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Rouxel"&gt;Charles Rouxel&lt;/a&gt; is as real as the Tour de France. Certainly he rode the 1977 Tour, though apparently he was eliminated on stage 17 for failing to make the cut-off time. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Col_du_Tourmalet" title="Col du Tourmalet, Wikipedia"&gt;The Tourmalet&lt;/a&gt; featured in the second stage of the race which ran from Auch to Pau. Rouxel may well have made up time on the descent but Lucien van Impe went on to take the stage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/charles-rouxel.jpg" alt="Charles Rouxel"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand what Rouxel has to say about technique, and I too love to go fast, but I&amp;#8217;m no descender. There&amp;#8217;s something terrifying about hurtling towards a bend you can&amp;#8217;t see around. Krabb&amp;eacute; puts it better:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have that kind of looseness. I take the curves like a wooden puppet, afraid that my centre of gravity is going to wind up in the ravine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-04-23</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rider-kilometer-6167</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rider-kilometer-6167</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>In Search of Robert Millar</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strangely, the cyclists who seem to cope least well when the curtain falls on their careers are the climbers. I mean the &lt;em&gt;pure&lt;/em&gt; climbers &amp;#8212; the very few who, when the road soars upwards, are able to take flight, as if they are fleeing those whom Millar nick-named the &amp;#8220;animals&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; all-rounders like Hinault, LeMond, Indurain, Armstrong. Necessarily, the climbing specialists are small, fragile, birdlike in build, power-to-weight ratio being all important in the mountains. And perhaps, in some cases, a rider&amp;#8217;s physical build is not so easily separated from his psychological make-up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Richard Moore, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X"&gt;&amp;#8220;In Search of Robert Millar&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/in-search-of-robert-millar.jpg" alt="Book cover. In Search of Robert Millar"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Moore_%28journalist%29"&gt;Richard Moore&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s superb book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X"&gt;&amp;#8220;In Search of Robert Millar&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, has provided me with the perfect come down after the thrills of this year&amp;#8217;s Tour de France.  Any talk of Bradley Wiggins being &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/384420/tour-comment-is-bradley-wiggins-the-best-ever-brit.html"&gt;the best ever British tour rider&lt;/a&gt; is premature: no one can seriously dispute the book&amp;#8217;s tagline, &amp;#8220;Unravelling the mystery surrounding Britain&amp;#8217;s most successful  Tour de France cyclist&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; unless, that is, they want to remove any qualification of Millar&amp;#8217;s achievements and nominate him simply as Britain&amp;#8217;s most successful road cyclist.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millar&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Millar#Palmares"&gt;palmares&lt;/a&gt; includes king of the mountains in the Giro and the Tour, a 4th place finish in the 1984 Tour, 2nd places in the Vuelta and the Giro, and victory in the Dauphin&amp;eacute; Lib&amp;eacute;r&amp;eacute;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is no hagiography. Millar is revealed as a complex and contradictory character; a man who defies any attempt to get close to him. He comes across as awkward, shy, and abrasive. Many people fail to get his sense of humour. Moore believes Millar had the ability and drive to win a grand tour but lacked the personality. Winning such a race requires the respect of your team and indeed of the peleton, political skills which Millar lacks; and Moore identifies this weakness as the main cause of the conspiracy which tricked him out of victory in the 1985 Vuelta. Millar eventually seemed happier as a super-domestique, a professional who would work for the team, but who remained capable of stealing stages.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millar refuses to play the media game. He has often been rude to commentators and journalists. Yet he has also proved himself to be an &lt;a href="http://www.rouleur.cc/recent-features/240-previewissue13"&gt;articulate thinker and writer&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since retiring from the sport Millar has again taken flight. Where is he now? What is he up to? Few people know. Email is the only way of reaching him, and in the book&amp;#8217;s epilogue Moore does at last make contact with Millar. He reprints their brief email exchange, ending his book with Millar&amp;#8217;s own words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;No more questions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a satisfying, thoroughly researched, well written book. Certainly it asks and investigates difficult questions, but the answers aren&amp;#8217;t always forthcoming. The story continues &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:gold;font-size:400%;"&gt;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-08-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/in-search-of-robert-millar</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/in-search-of-robert-millar</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Review: Becoming Drusilla</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/becoming-drusilla.jpg" alt="Becoming Drusilla cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s hard for me to be objective about &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;Becoming Drusilla&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info" title="Richard Beard's home page"&gt;friend of mine&lt;/a&gt; wrote it and I&amp;#8217;ve met its subject, Dru, a few times &amp;#8212; though she spelled her name &amp;#8220;Drew&amp;#8221; then, short for Andrew, and very male she appeared too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book centres on a journey which starts in Bristol then heads out of Chepstow on foot along &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Offa%27s_Dyke"&gt;Offa&amp;#8217;s Dyke&lt;/a&gt;. As the two of them walk, Richard mulls over his relationship with Dru, past and present, and tries to work out how it all happened. Dru identifies wildlife and knows all the words to some arcane songs. They squabble over directions. Mid-way, they abandon the Dyke, instead heading for St Davids, Pembrokeshire.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a cracking book, if something of a conundrum for book-sellers. On which shelf do you put a travel book which is also a biography and indeed an autobiography, which covers gender issues with wit and intelligence? Oh, and it also includes some rather good haiku and illustrations. &lt;strong&gt;So pile it high near the front, then!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.com/"&gt;&lt;img style="float:left;" src="http://www.facebook.com/profile/pic.php?uid=AAAAAQAQW2Pbi8-IS-Gq5OCcRAGQQwAAAAkNWQzqa9aqZz9B1znkyFAp" alt="Dru Marland, self-portrait"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;Becoming Drusilla&lt;/a&gt; has just been relaunched in paperback. Richard and Dru will be &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=85841341768" title="Becoming Drusilla, Bristol Launch. A Facebook group"&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt; from the book in the Green Room at the Tobacco Factory, Bristol, on Friday 8th May, 7:45 pm.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to meeting Dru again. It must be almost a decade since we last met in person. Now, of course, I&amp;#8217;ve read her biography. I&amp;#8217;m also her friend on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/people/Dru-Marland"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; which doesn&amp;#8217;t mean much since I barely use Facebook. She has a &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.com/"&gt;fine blog&lt;/a&gt; and her Flickr &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/belvedere/"&gt;photostream&lt;/a&gt; includes some beautiful photographs and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/belvedere/sets/72157594410663343/"&gt;illustrations&lt;/a&gt;. See you on Friday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: looks like Richard is unwell and won&amp;#8217;t be able to make it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-05-06</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-becoming-drusilla</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-becoming-drusilla</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Hobbit</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t think of many books which feature a burglar as a hero, but then Bilbo Baggins makes a rather reluctant hero &amp;#8212; for much of the story he finds himself wondering why everyone makes such a fuss about adventures, and wishing he were back at home in his comfortable hobbit hole with its well-stocked pantries.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tolkienbooks.net/html/the_hobbit.htm"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" src="http://www.tolkienbooks.net/images/thumbs/hobbit-1961-th.jpg" alt="The Hobbit cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The Hobbit&amp;#8221; is a book I was read, as a child. I can clearly remember my parents&amp;#8217; edition of the book, with its dark cover and yellowing pages. My mother tells me that was when I started to read for myself: one evening I just couldn&amp;#8217;t wait to hear what happened next, so I didn&amp;#8217;t.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hobbit"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.tolkienbooks.net/images/other/hobbit-binding.gif" alt="Cover of first edition of The Hobbit"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I&amp;#8217;ve just finished reading it to my own children. With its riddles, songs and last-gasp escapes, it reads aloud beautifully. We&amp;#8217;ve all thoroughly enjoyed it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-03-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-hobbit</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-hobbit</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rourke, wrestler, barfly, Bukowksi</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=" http://www.bafta.org/awards/film/film-nominations-in-2009,657,BA.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/mickey-rourke-bafta.jpg" alt="Mickey Rourke at the BAFTAs"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mickey Rourke shambles on stage, hunches over the mike, cusses a bit, thanks his best mates for sticking by him, shambles off again. Actors: you never know when they&amp;#8217;re acting and when they&amp;#8217;re not, and I&amp;#8217;m not convinced they do either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rourke&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.bafta.org/awards/film/film-nominations-in-2009,657,BA.html"&gt;best actor gong&lt;/a&gt; comes for his portrayal of Randy &amp;#8220;The Ram&amp;#8221; Robinson in &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1125849/"&gt;The Wrester&lt;/a&gt;, a film I watched with my brother a couple of weeks ago. It&amp;#8217;s a terrific film but makes for uncomfortable viewing: the wheezy soundtrack and out of focus imagery take us directly into Randy&amp;#8217;s world, a world where the wrestling matches may be staged, but the blood, scars and pain are all too real.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/mickey-rourke-the-wrestler.jpg" alt="Randy The Ram Robinson"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface it&amp;#8217;s about a faded wrestler who defies health problems for one last comeback bout; but it&amp;#8217;s tempting to see it as Rourke&amp;#8217;s own story. In The Ram&amp;#8217;s words.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just want to say to you all tonight I&amp;#8217;m very grateful to be here. A lot of people told me that I&amp;#8217;d never wrestle again and that&amp;#8217;s all I do. You know, if you live hard and play hard and you burn the candle at both ends, you pay the price for it. You know in this life you can lose everything you love, everything that loves you. Now I don&amp;#8217;t hear as good as I used to and I forget stuff and I aint as pretty as I used to be but god damn it I&amp;#8217;m still standing here and I&amp;#8217;m The Ram. As times goes by, as times goes by, they say &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s washed up&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s finished&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s a loser&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;s all through&amp;#8221;. You know what? The only one that&amp;#8217;s going to tell me when I&amp;#8217;m through doing my thing is you people here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bukowski"&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/e2/Charles_Bukowski_smoking.jpg" alt="Charles Bukowksi" style="float:right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1987, at the peak of his success, Mickey Rourke chose to play writer &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Bukowski"&gt;Charles Bukowski&lt;/a&gt; in the film &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092618/"&gt;Barfly&lt;/a&gt;. Bukowski is best known for his books about Henry Chinaski, a womanizing, gambling drunk who lurches from one dead-end job to the next. To what extent are these books autobiographical? I&amp;#8217;m not sure, but I do know Bukowski was sober enough to write a lot of great material. I particularly recommend his first novel, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0061177571?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;Post Office&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0061177571?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/postoffice.gif" alt="Post Office"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rourke shed his pretty boy looks and gained several kilos to play Bukowski in &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092618/"&gt;Barfly&lt;/a&gt;, a film which was also scripted by Bukowski, but now botched plastic sugery and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mickey_Rourke#From_actor_to_boxer"&gt;one bout too many in a boxing ring&lt;/a&gt; have spoiled his looks for real. He remains charismatic, a fine actor, but what other roles can there be for him? Henry Chinaski, fictional post office worker?
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-02-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/rourke-wrestler-barfly-bukowksi</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/rourke-wrestler-barfly-bukowksi</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Great books, 2008</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I enjoy reading a book I make a mental note to review it here, but somehow I haven&amp;#8217;t got round to writing all those reviews. The truth is, I find it very hard to put in words exactly why I like a book. So here are three books I read last year which I really must recommend.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Stuart, A Life Backwards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0007241771?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/stuart-a-life-backwards.jpg" alt="Stuart: A Life Backwards (cover)"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Masters&amp;#8217; book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0007241771?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;Stuart, A Life Backwards&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; starts with the death of its anti-hero, Stuart, a &amp;#8220;chaotic&amp;#8221; homeless person from Cambridge, then proceeds to tell his life story in reverse order. (Here the term &amp;#8220;chaotic&amp;#8221; is used to describe someone whose life is completely out of control: offender, chronic drug abuser, alcoholic). On the surface, this is a plainly written biography &amp;#8212; Stuart Shorter&amp;#8217;s true story written down directly by hostel worker Alexander Masters &amp;#8212; but you&amp;#8217;ll come to appreciate it as a cleverly constructed and well written novel. The reversed narrative works brilliantly: from the start we know what happens, but as the story unfolds we find out how and why (as much as there can ever be a how and why in such a sad story).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;English Passengers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/038549744X?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/english-passengers.jpg" alt="English Passengers"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Kneale&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/038549744X?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;English Passengers&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; is a rollicking adventure and historical novel which travels round the world, involving the brutal extermination of Tasmanian aboriginals, Victorian science, religion, and Manx smugglers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Life, A User&amp;#8217;s Manual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one niggle with &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/038549744X?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;English Passengers&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;: for me, it didn&amp;#8217;t particularly improve as I worked my way through it. For big books telling big stories, with multiple storylines and narrators, it&amp;#8217;s important that the story should gather momentum and pull you along to the ending.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0002719991?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://wordaligned.org/images/books/life-a-users-manual.jpg" alt="Life A User's Manual"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third book &amp;#8212; my book of 2008 &amp;#8212; doesn&amp;#8217;t just get better as you read through it, it gets better each time you read it. Georges Perec&amp;#8217;s masterpiece &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0002719991?tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;Life, A User&amp;#8217;s Manual&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; is a big book which tells many stories. Utterly different from any other book I&amp;#8217;ve read, yet very accessible, it makes great reading out of both the quotidian and the fantastical. It&amp;#8217;s a compelling and moving story about human failure.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-01-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/great-books-2008</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/great-books-2008</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Me and my Strida</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3002377244/" title="unfolded by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3181/3002377244_040063a9bb_m.jpg" width="213" height="240" alt="unfolded" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3001540717/" title="folded by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3184/3001540717_b91a82588f_m.jpg" width="162" height="240" alt="folded" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Gadget Show reviews folding bikes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rebeccaromero.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.rebeccaromero.co.uk/images/morph3.gif" style="float:left;" alt="Rebecca Romero medalled in rowing and cycling"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the &lt;a href="http://fwd.five.tv/gadget-show"&gt;Gadget Show&lt;/a&gt; on 5 last night because I was interested in hearing what cycling gold &lt;a href="http://www.rebeccaromero.co.uk/"&gt;Rebecca Romero&lt;/a&gt; would have to say about folding bikes. What interested me most, in fact, was that she said she hadn&amp;#8217;t ridden a bike since winning the 3km individual pursuit in Beijing. I guess that&amp;#8217;s the difference between using a bike to get around on and doing what it takes to win a gold medal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do cycle for leisure and fitness; but for me cycling is primarily a means of transport and I ride a bicycle on most days. I&amp;#8217;ve always hankered after a folding bicycle but never could quite justify the purchase: after all, I already had a touring bike and a &amp;#8220;mountain bike&amp;#8221; (in quotes since it never went near any mountains; rather I used it as a sturdy bike to which a child seat could be fitted).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My children have their own bikes now and the mountain bike has long gone. A couple of years ago I decided to finally buy a foldie. I regularly visit my employer&amp;#8217;s London office, and a folding bike gets me to either of the Bristol mainline stations (Temple Meads and Parkway), and between Paddington and Farringdon at the other end of the journey. Also, I can fold up the bike and sling it in the back of the car &amp;#8212; very handy when driving somewhere to cycle with the family.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rebecca Romero hates Stridas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.strida.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://www.strida.nl/en/images/strida5/strida5-bike.jpg" alt="Strida 5"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided on a &lt;a href="http://www.strida.co.uk"&gt;Strida&lt;/a&gt;. A Strida 3, in fact. I&amp;#8217;ve been generally happy with it. I used it this morning when I dropped the car off at the garage for its MOT.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Romero reviewed the latest Strida, a Strida 5, last night. It&amp;#8217;s half as expensive again as the model I bought, and looks to be the same distinctive design but with several components tuned and improved. She found it an uncomfortable ride and couldn&amp;#8217;t wait to get off, resulting in a final verdict of just one out of five stars.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I give mine three out of five&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ottawafilmreview.blogspot.com/2008/07/nostalgia-of-france-in-1947.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img5.allocine.fr/acmedia/medias/nmedia/18/36/02/36/18445934.jpg" alt="Jacques Tati on his bike"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience with the Strida has been very different. I enjoy riding mine. I wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to go a long way on it. It has just one gear, and while the upright riding position makes for fun &amp;#8212; you feel a bit like cycling postman Jacques Tati in the picture above &amp;#8212; it certainly isn&amp;#8217;t the most efficient. Who cares? I&amp;#8217;ve got a road bike for long distances. The Strida is for nipping to and from stations, or across town. For such use it&amp;#8217;s great.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/google-maps-for-the-humanpowered.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/walking-directions.png" alt="Muddled map"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, I managed to cycle mine up Bristol&amp;#8217;s notorious &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/google-maps-for-the-humanpowered.html"&gt;Mont D&amp;#8217;Arbres Neuf&lt;/a&gt;, a hors cat&amp;eacute;gorie climb so savage Google maps refuse to offer directions up it, though I did have to tack from side to side of the road.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Strida is light. It&amp;#8217;s a doddle to assemble. The brakes are positive. Just getting on it makes me smile. I get smiles when I ride it too. It&amp;#8217;s pretty much zero maintenance. The chain is kevlar and nothing needs oiling &amp;#8212; very nice for a bike you might want to park indoors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m marking it down because:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     it doesn&amp;#8217;t fold as small as some other bikes
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     it&amp;#8217;s not the most robust. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to hop on and off pavements on it, and I&amp;#8217;m careful to avoid pot-holes
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     the kevlar chain can slip if you apply too much force on a wet day.
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I think I made a good choice. Nowadays I wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to be without a foldie.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Folding up a Trek Pilot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2883059364/" title="Bicycle dismantled by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3161/2883059364_a6ccfaf69a.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Bicycle dismantled" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-11-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/me-and-my-strida</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/me-and-my-strida</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Brighton Rock</title>
<description>&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142437972?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/brighton-rock.png" alt="Brighton Rock"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back from holiday in Portugal, the cold and dark making us shiver, on checking the garden we discover the one pumpkin the slugs failed to destroy has also failed to ripen so Gail heads for the shops returning later with diabolical costumes for the children and I&amp;#8217;m reminded of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142437972?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;Graham Greene&amp;#8217;s Brighton Rock&lt;/a&gt;, a book I read whilst away, a book I&amp;#8217;ve read several times but which never fails to terrify, whose main character, Pinkie, is cruel and innocent and evil.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-10-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/brighton-rock</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/brighton-rock</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>We Need to Talk About Kevin</title>
<description>&lt;div class="amazon"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/006112429X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/we-need-to-talk-about-kevin.jpg" alt="We Need to Talk About Kevin"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read Lionel Shriver&amp;#8217;s powerful novel, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/006112429X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wordalig-20"&gt;&amp;#8220;We Need to Talk About Kevin&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, over the summer. The story centres on a school massacre and is narrated by Eva Khatchadourian, a mother who, in a series of letters to her estranged husband Franklin, comes to terms with the horrific murders committed by her son, Kevin. Even before he was born Eva had trouble with Kevin. She hated carrying him, never wanted him, resents him for spoiling her career, her marriage, her life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s just a story but school massacres are very real. At first I thought the novel might be an attempt to analyse a serious subject through fiction, in which case I&amp;#8217;d probably not have got to the end of it. In fact it&amp;#8217;s a thriller, a page-turner. From the outset we know &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; is going to happen but not &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;. Kevin doesn&amp;#8217;t want to be any old school murderer, he wants to do it with style, he wants to be the best. Details of the massacre he enacts are saved until last. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A horrible disturbing book. Recommended.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-09-29</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/we-need-to-talk-about-kevin</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/we-need-to-talk-about-kevin</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Say no to noisy popcorn!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2008/aug/10/foodanddrink1"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in today&amp;#8217;s Observer says:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;The End&amp;#8217; for popcorn at the movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A growing number of cinemas are barring the snack because it is too downmarket and messy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can cope with downmarket and I&amp;#8217;m tolerant of mess &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s the &lt;strong&gt;noise&lt;/strong&gt; which bugs me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2008/aug/10/foodanddrink1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.mcps.org/sms/popcorn.gif" alt="Bag of popcorn" style="float:right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On holiday last week, on one of those days when the rain didn&amp;#8217;t stop, we went to see what was on at the &lt;a href="http://www.merlincinemas.co.uk/"&gt;Savoy Cinema&lt;/a&gt; in Penzance. They were showing &lt;a href="http://disney.go.com/disneypictures/wall-e/"&gt;WALL-E&lt;/a&gt;, a film I&amp;#8217;d not heard of and which, on the face of it, I would happily have avoided, but one Alex seemed to know all about. He was keen. We paid up and traipsed in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed it. For a big budget film, it was suprisingly radical. For the first hour or so there wasn&amp;#8217;t a single spoken word; the story unfolded through images and sounds (bleeps, squeaks, taps, snatches of music, the sound of a computer booting up, etc.) alone. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the family behind us were scoffing popcorn served up in large and crinkly paper bags. The noise distracted me. But it&amp;#8217;s hard asking people to finish their snack before watching a film when the snack is served in the cinema foyer specifically to be taken in to accompany the show.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-08-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/say-no-to-noisy-popcorn</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/say-no-to-noisy-popcorn</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Run Away</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2744090734/" title="The Run Away front cover"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3291/2744090734_4fc4c79120_m.jpg" width="169" height="240" alt="The Run Away front cover" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2744090798/" title="The Run Away blurb"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3272/2744090798_3d75c16364_o.png" width="522" height="285" alt="The Run Away blurb" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-08-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-run-away</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-run-away</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Pete T Day-Journay</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://londonreviewofbreakfasts.blogspot.com/2005/08/reviews-by-contributor.html"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" src="http://wordaligned.org/images/cooked-breakfast.jpg" alt="Full English"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to submit a review to the &lt;a href="http://londonreviewofbreakfasts.blogspot.com"&gt;London Review of Breakfasts&lt;/a&gt;, if only to see my pseudonym up there with the other &lt;a href="http://londonreviewofbreakfasts.blogspot.com/2005/08/reviews-by-contributor.html"&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatives:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     Frieda Bredd
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Blake Pudding
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Erin Juice
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Boyle d&amp;#8217;Egg
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any more?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(My thanks to Simon Brunning for the &lt;a href="http://www.brunningonline.net/simon/blog/archives/002254.html"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/pete-t-dayjournay</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/pete-t-dayjournay</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>A Short History of Tractor Fishing in the Yemen</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Short-History-Tractors-Ukrainian/dp/0141020520/ref=pd_bbs_1/026-2389784-2367637?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1189585741&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;A Short History of Tractors in Ukrainian&lt;/a&gt; was one of my favourite books from last year, a fact which, funnily enough, put me off the similarly titled &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Salmon-Fishing-Yemen-Paul-Torday/dp/0753821788/ref=sr_1_1/026-2389784-2367637?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1189585930&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Salmon Fishing in the Yemen&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; I assumed the yemen-salmon book would be a flimsy me-too book, pushed out by publishers on the back of the ukrainian-tractor&amp;#8217;s success.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://ec1.images-amazon.com/images/I/51sLQq1kRLL._AA240_.jpg" alt="salmon book cover"/&gt;
   &lt;img src="http://ec1.images-amazon.com/images/I/51WRNVtcnOL._BO2,204,203,200_PIsitb-dp-500-arrow,TopRight,45,-64_OU02_AA240_SH20_.jpg" alt="tractor book cover"/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so. I greatly enjoyed the salmon book. Unlike the tractor book, salmon and salmon fishing are central to the the plot: Dr Alfred Jones, a government scientist, is roped into a crazy scheme to introduce salmon to the Yemen. It turns he&amp;#8217;s actually being manipulated by the Prime Minister and his director of communications, Alistair Campbell, oops Peter Maxwell I mean, who are desperate for a feel-good story in the Middle-East, though as the story continues, Jones falls increasingly under the influence of an inspirational sheik and his attractive assistant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a deftly-written satire. My only complaint is that, as a satire, it loses its bite as it continues: the best satires (The History Man, for example) should start with you laughing and end with you crying. This one left me laughing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://news.bbc.co.uk/olmedia/1040000/images/_1044800_historymanbbc300.jpg" alt="The History Man"/&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2007-09-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-short-history-of-tractor-fishing-in-the-yemen</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/a-short-history-of-tractor-fishing-in-the-yemen</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Review of Bob Dylan&#8217;s Theme Time Radio Hour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio2/shows/dylan/"&gt;Ace!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2007-02-07</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-of-bob-dylans-theme-time-radio-hour</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-of-bob-dylans-theme-time-radio-hour</link>
<category>Review</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
