<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>The last ever Pomphrey 5K</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On a warm summer evening I cycled out of Bristol on the railway path. The verges were overgrown, the air dense with insects. Coming through Staple Hill the path enters a tunnel, water falling from the arching roof and onto the tarmac.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I count the Pomphrey Sports 5K as unfinished business. Last time I ran it &amp;#8212; the only time I&amp;#8217;d run it, in fact, the only timed 5K I&amp;#8217;d ever run &amp;#8212; on a dark, blustery winter&amp;#8217;s evening it took me &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=70510&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Jan-13"&gt;18 minutes and 44 seconds&lt;/a&gt; to get round. Today, I had to do better. I wanted to test my speed ahead of the &lt;a href="http://www.swanseahalfmarathon.co.uk/"&gt;Swansea half&lt;/a&gt;. An email from race director, Chris Elson, warned me I wouldn&amp;#8217;t get another chance:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;This race incorporates the Avon AA mob match with the winning team (20 to count) being awarded the Andrew Rawnsley Memorial Trophy. We hope there will be lots of Avon Clubs with teams! &lt;b&gt;This race will be the last, after some 15 years&lt;/b&gt;, to be held on the course but plans are at an advanced stage to move the race to a flat fast course using the mile circuit at Aztec West.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short warm up around Pomphrey Hill playing fields, I joined the other runners at the start of the course. Fewer than I expected &amp;#8212; maybe a couple of hundred of us, and only seven from &lt;a href="http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk/"&gt;SRC&lt;/a&gt;. There was Sam Stone, a work colleague, running for &lt;a href="http://www.emersonsgreenrunningclub.co.uk/"&gt;Emersons Green&lt;/a&gt;. We gathered on the cycle track under the B4465 bridge over the ringroad. After a brief announcement, we were off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, 5K is a tough distance. It feels like I&amp;#8217;m running flat out the whole way. The track veers through a subway under the ringroad. At 1K, my watch showed 3:30. Now we skirted the new roundabout exit, trainers hitting plywood boards laid over fresh tarmac. Crossing the ringroad now on a pedestrian bridge. I hit 2K around 7 minutes in and realised my target, 18 minutes, was very much on. Matt was just ahead. Around us, red and white vests, Bristol and West. The track takes a left at the next roundabout and then at exactly 2.5K out doubles back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/157862063/embed/5f0a94ffb444a1ce7f5bffd483e08cd8159dbe32'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My legs felt tired in the final kilometre. Somehow sensing my weakness Matt opened a gap which 5 Bristol and West runners smartly filled. I checked my watch. A PB for sure. 18 minutes, definitely, but having got into this position how hard would I push for the finish? Did I really want to set a best time which would be out of reach in future? My legs felt ragged.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I crossed the line under the bridge over the ringroad and stopped my watch. 17:48, it said. 17:50, officially.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the presentation, Roger, one of the race directors, took the opportunity to talk about the history of the race which originated some 20 years ago to finance Bristol and West AC sending competitors all round the country, paying for petrol and entry fees. There was no roundabout, no ring road, no cycle track. The sports pavilion we sat in hadn&amp;#8217;t been built and so the Bridge Inn hosted the event which was run on dirt tracks around the former quarry.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first MV50 to finish, in 22nd place with an official time of 17:50, I picked up a &amp;pound;5 Easy Running voucher. Without me being aware of it the next two runners, just 4 and 13 seconds behind me, were also MV50&amp;#8217;s. Some race!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
1      15.23   John Ashcroft   Bristol University      SM
2      15.34   Matt Whitfield  Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
3      16.21   James Denne     Exeter Harriers         SM
4      16.33   Jarlath McKenna Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
5      16.35   Matthew Krelle  Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
6      16.48   Mark Edwards    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
7      17.06   Iain Stuart     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
8      17.08   Olly Sheppard   Team Bath AC            SM
9      17.09   Sam Hedley      Team Bath AC            SM
10     17.14   Jenny Jagger    Bristol &amp; West AC       SW
11     17.24   Anthony Hall    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
12     17.26   Torran Elson    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
13     17.34   Jacob Hayes     Bitton Road Runners    M40
14     17.35   Matt Burns      Southville              SM
15     17.37   Chris Palmer    Westbury Harriers       SM
16     17.38   Peter Gandon    Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
17     17.40   Alexander Whittaker  Bristol &amp; West AC  SM
18     17.41   Helen Sharpe    Bristol &amp; West AC       SW
19     17.42   Phil Lucker     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
20     17.44   Jason Barry     Stroud &amp; District      M40
21     17.46   Ben Farrell     Bristol &amp; West AC       SM
&lt;b&gt;22     17.50   Thomas Guest    Southville             M50&lt;/b&gt;
23     17.54   Gary Hughes     Team Bath AC           M50
24     18.03   Phil Westlake   Bitton Road Runners    M50
25     18.04   Julian Bailey-Gard Westbury Harriers    SM
26     18.06   C McQuade       Unattached              SM
27     18.08   Andrew Malloy   Bristol &amp; West AC      M40
...
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling back along the track which was once a railway I thought about Bristol traffic, transport and history. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-06-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-last-ever-pomphrey-5k</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Wrington Woodland Tyntesfield 10</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At the start of the month I attempted the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Wrington Woodland&lt;/a&gt; run. Conditions were warm and damp. The race starts with a gradual climb from Goblin Coombe. I was tracking the leaders at this stage. The rocky track became a river of viscous clay. A Frome runner slipped and slithered, his &lt;a href="http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/running_mens.htm"&gt;five fingers&lt;/a&gt; affording little traction. I moved past into second place.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=http://www.theracephotographer.com/2014/WWR/Set_A/large/image_a0007.jpg alt="WWR, theracephotographer.com/2014" width=640px /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own shoes &amp;#8212; my normally trusty Adidas swoop trail shoes &amp;#8212; skidded on the fast tarmac descent to Wrington. I slowed down then pushed on, determined to hold my position. On the second climb, the steep one up Bullhouse Lane, my right calf went. I limped, then walked, then tried to run through the injury, then walked again. I was in some pain. Runners passed me. I&amp;#8217;m fine, I said, it&amp;#8217;s cramp. The woods on top of Wrington Hill were packed with bluebells. A kindly marshal gave me a lift back to the HQ once the race had passed. My first ever DNF. I felt lousy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, three weeks later, I showed up for the &lt;a href="http://nailsearunningclub.org.uk/club-races/"&gt;Tyntesfield 10&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; a favourite event from last year. My calf still isn&amp;#8217;t 100% but I needed to get round the course to put Wrington behind me. I could surely do that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started easily on the first meadow circuit. We looped back to the house, swerving round the croquet lawn and flowerbeds, then back to the meadow again. My legs felt good. I pushed on towards the woods, passing runners as the track rose. Watch out for tree roots! Go on Southville! The track twists and swerves, hurdling fallen trees, ducking under branches. I was glad to be clear and able to pick my own route. Andy Malloy cruised past. I drafted him, pulling me into contention with a couple of other runners.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the woods and into long grass, nettles, thistles, rape. At this stage last year I&amp;#8217;d been wiped out. Today, a more cautious start had earned me something in reserve. To my surprise, Annabel Granger was in range, plus another couple of runners I didn&amp;#8217;t know. At last we reached the long descent bringing the route back home. I passed one runner. I passed two more, only for them to nip ahead when I misinterpreted a marshal&amp;#8217;s signal and turned the wrong way. Down the steps and on to the tarmac. I dug in on the final short climb, regaining my earlier position. On the finishing straight, for the first time in the race, I looked behind me. My position was safe. I crossed the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training mate Neil Williams was so close behind I didn&amp;#8217;t see him finish. I cheered in another friend, Steve Swan, drank the water and ate the minuscule cereal bar in the goodie bag.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14056237608" title="Tyntesfield 10k by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/14056237608_9b09156c0c_z.jpg" width="640" height="428" alt="Tyntesfield 10k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was 7th to finish and 1st in my category. My time, &lt;a href="https://www.fullonsport.co.uk/fos/index.php?module=results&amp;amp;eventId=4350&amp;amp;action=results" title="Race results"&gt;40:39&lt;/a&gt;, was 22 seconds faster than at the same event last year. Next up: the Welsh Castles Relay.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rich Kenington, &lt;a href="http://www.theracephotographer.com"&gt;theracephotographer.com&lt;/a&gt;, and Sally Johnson for the excellent action shots used on this page.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-05-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-tyntesfield-10</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/wrington-woodland-tyntesfield-10</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>110th Welsh Cross Country championships, Llandeilo</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Blame the wind, which started before Christmas and still hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped. Or the rain, which had been similarly persistent, flooding roads, train lines, villages and fields. I guess even the toughest
   runners may have thought twice about showing up for another mudfest, even if this one was the Welsh championships.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, you can only compete against those who turn up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked up, as instructed, on the outskirts of the Dinefwr estate, and caught the shuttle bus to the event. A massive tree, toppled by the recent storms, lay on the grass, its roots pointing upwards. The racing had already started: junior runners picked their way through the mud. I collected my number from the race HQ in front of Newton House.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Davis, the commentator said, was hot favourite for the U13 boys&amp;#8217; event. You can tell it&amp;#8217;s Luke Davies, he said, because of his socks: one pink, one green. If Luke Davies felt the pressure of expectation, he responded well to it, taking an early lead and extending it all the way to the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain held off. The wind was strong but no gale. The senior event would be four times round a rolling, heavy, lovely course. I ran one as a warm up with Kneath, Eamonn, Raul and Martin. Dewi Griffiths, defending champion, was here, and although I&amp;#8217;d be on his team, I didn&amp;#8217;t want him lapping me!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some great &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=582349755166585&amp;amp;set=a.582349438499950.1073741898.100001746967305"&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt;, taken by Gwynfor James.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great day for Swansea Harriers! Here&amp;#8217;s a snippet from the &lt;a href="http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk/content/results-round-usa-llandeilo-cardiff-birmingham-brecon"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on the club&amp;#8217;s website.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&amp;#8230;] arguably the main highlight of the day showing the talent and strength in depth of the senior mens team, saw the B team win team SILVER, just, by a point! The SILVER winning team were Eamon Kirk (14th), Lewys Hobbs (16th), &lt;strong&gt;Thomas Guest&lt;/strong&gt; (21st) Matthew Richards (22nd), Raul Reismann (30th) and Kneath Philippart (35th).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/12566784253" title="Swansea harriers, Welsh cross country champions! by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3789/12566784253_843bb33ed4_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Swansea harriers, Welsh cross country champions!"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-02-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/110th-welsh-cross-country-championships-llandeilo</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/110th-welsh-cross-country-championships-llandeilo</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh Inter-Regional &amp; Masters XC Champs, 2013</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The cross country course at Builth Wells ticks all the boxes:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     hills &amp;#10003;
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     mud &amp;#10003;
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     scenery &amp;#10003;
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They even threw in a log jump (&amp;#10003;) this year!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;ve adjusted the course since I last ran it. If anything, it&amp;#8217;s better. What used to be a steady climb has been reversed, becoming a fast and treacherous descent, which you&amp;#8217;ll have to undertake on wobbly legs after a woodland ascent through ditches and streams.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day, as a representative of West Wales in the inter-regional championships, I was running in a red and black vest. Since the race included the Welsh Masters cross country championships, I was also running for Swansea Harriers, and &amp;#8212; for the first time ever &amp;#8212; running in the V50 category.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rare combination gave me several chances so I struck out at a sharp pace, stretching my legs on the rolling prelude, and &amp;#8212; to my surprise &amp;#8212; found myself just behind Peter Coles, last year&amp;#8217;s V50 winner, on the first downhill. I passed him at speed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/11455697276/" title="2013 Welsh Inter-Regional Cross Country championships, Builth Wells by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2821/11455697276_658bec0be9_c.jpg" width="530" height="800" alt="2013 Welsh Inter-Regional Cross Country championships, Builth Wells"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe if I&amp;#8217;d paced myself better I could have finished in the top 10. Maybe not. In the end &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/files/welsh-interregional-xc-2013.pdf"&gt;I came 12th&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/11407194815/" title="Welsh masters cross country by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7296/11407194815_afb2369075_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Welsh masters cross country"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won a bronze medal in the masters V50 category, coming around minute behind V50 winner Ifan Lloyd and just 20 seconds behind Peter Coles. West Wales were the winning V50 team and Swansea Harriers were the winning V50 club.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-12-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-interregional-amp-masters-xc-champs-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-interregional-amp-masters-xc-champs-2013</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Blaise Blazer, from A to T, August 2013</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle estate, another great location for a multi-terrain race. I was looking forward to running in the third and last of Westbury Harriers&amp;#8217; &lt;a href="http://www.westburyharriers.co.uk/promotions.html"&gt;Blaise Blazer 2013 races&lt;/a&gt; for a couple of reasons: first, my knowledge of the estate&amp;#8217;s winding paths and trails could only be to my advantage; and second, I&amp;#8217;d be running for Southville Running Club, who I train with on Tuesday evenings, and who would be defending the Blazer Challenge Cup they won in 2012.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time, I&amp;#8217;d try not to arrive so early. It took a while to register everyone. Eventually, over 120 runners toed a wide starting line on the field looking down towards the mansion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/10859993384/" title="blaise-blazer by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7353/10859993384_334b3ce734_z.jpg" width="640" height="570" alt="blaise-blazer"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We charged across the grass to A hitting the path at B. I must have been about 20th at C, the foot of the first climb, and picked up a few places by H, where we switched from a well-surfaced path to a woodland trail. Matt, Mike, Mark and Tim &amp;#8212; all Southville runners &amp;#8212; were ahead, but not too far ahead. Climbing I, J, K, a treacherous uphill track, I passed Tim. I took the muddy descent from O to P carefully. Mike pulled away on the flat, Q, and somehow I was pulling away from Mark and staying in contact with Matt. Maybe I could have done more on the final climb to the castle, R, S, T, but maybe I didn&amp;#8217;t know the paths quite as well as I thought.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I was glad to finish and cheer in the remaining runners.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half an hour later we were back at the Westbury Harriers club house and half an hour after that the results had been logged and checked. Southville retained the Challenge Cup, hooray! I finished 10th, the first MV40, in a time of 24:17.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/10859883155/" title="Southville Running Club, Blazer challenge cup holders 2013 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3755/10859883155_890e326008_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Southville Running Club, Blazer challenge cup holders 2013"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-09-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2013</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The TACH ticks talk</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Happily I recovered from flu in time to line up for the start of the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Wrington Woodland&lt;/a&gt; run. 100 or so of us queued on the footpath just outside Cleeve listening to a well rehearsed pre-race briefing: this is going to take 5 minutes so don&amp;#8217;t stare at me, I won&amp;#8217;t go any faster, a special announcement, Jim and Alfredo are running &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/10kX365"&gt;10km a day every day this year&lt;/a&gt; so like them on Facebook and when you shower check yourself for ticks, you&amp;#8217;re unlikely to have any and they&amp;#8217;re unlikely to be carrying Lyme disease, which can usually be treated, but if you do and they are and you aren&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8230; conditions &lt;strong&gt;downhill&lt;/strong&gt; are fine but uphill watch out for tree roots, loose stones etc. Honk! We were off!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The path climbed steadily up Cleeve Hill. Matt hung behind the leaders then eased away hitting a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow. Andy passed me when the path levelled off. A tall runner from Weston AC bounded downhill on elastic legs. Hey, maybe I was still the first veteran runner on the course? If I was, I wasn&amp;#8217;t for long. I felt weary on the climb up Wrington Hill; Andrew Malloy (V40) and  Adrian Noble (V50) overtook. At last the track levelled and zigzagged downhill back to Cleeve. I clattered over a narrow wooden bridge and cleared a stile and ran on wobbly legs across one last field to the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done Matt for winning! Jim and Alfredo ran on through the finish, the route being a few metres short of 10k. Prize-giving was held in the Lord Nelson skittle alley. How we cheered!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9381867241/" title="About a mile into the Burrington Blaster by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3734/9381867241_da0013242e_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="About a mile into the Burrington Blaster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second race, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Burrington Blaster&lt;/a&gt;, found me in better form, which is just as well: the route took us from the Burrington Inn right up to the top of the Mendips in one long climb. The view at the summit was spectacular and although the urge to stop and admire it was strong I pushed on through gusting winds and boggy footing. 4th place was mine if I could negotiate the treacherous descent. I couldn&amp;#8217;t, falling a short way from the finish when my feet slid on loose stones. Nothing damaged, but physical and mental momentum destroyed. A couple of red and white vests &amp;#8212; Bristol and West &amp;#8212; passed. I held on for 6th.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fancied my chances in the third race, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Purdown Pursuit&lt;/a&gt;, my former training ground. When I lived in Cobourg Road, on Sunday mornings I&amp;#8217;d head out along Boiling Wells Lane and past the telecoms tower, attacking a selection of Purdown&amp;#8217;s short sharp hills before passing the UWE campus to head under the M32 and back through Frenchay and Snuff Mills. How could they fit 10k into Purdown, I wondered? The answer turned out to be a double loop; the first short circuit had me wondering how I&amp;#8217;d hang on for the second longer loop, this one covering the full length of the down, Stoke Lane to Muller Road and back again. Hold on I did, passing a pony-tailed Nailsea runner who took a wrong turn through the woods, and losing a place to Andrew Malloy (again!) on the final downhill swoop. I collapsed at the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9381881853/" title="Purdown pursuit by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5327/9381881853_858db6ec4d_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Purdown pursuit"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something different! Race four, closing the series, the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Dundry Thunder&lt;/a&gt; run, started at the top of the hill. A prolonged spell of hot weather had broken into storms during the week and I wondered if the thunder would be more literal than alliterative, but the evening turned out just fine, clear, not too hot, as we gathered on the downs at foot of the radio masts. You could see all of Bristol, city and suburbs, the Clifton bridge, and beyond to the Severn estuary spanned by another suspension bridge and the angular second crossing. I warmed up, running the wrong way along the finishing straight, skipping over thistles and cowpats. The start was delayed whilst a local resident trimmed his hedge, destroying some route markings in the process.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race was a double loop: starting with a jostling descent down Littleton Lane towards Winford. Determined to hold something back for the second loop, I watched the leaders stride away from me. Behind a hedge, the sound of gunshots. We turned off the lane and looped back through fields up the hill to Dundry, negotiating uneven ground, gates and stiles. Skittish cattle stampeded across the course. I pulled back a couple of places on the climb and sped up when we reached the level section along Crabtree Lane, vaulting a gate at the same time as a Weston AC runner tried to open it. We waded through a field of oilseed rape, the heavy pods slapping our legs, then past another radio mast. The second extended downhill cut a diagonal through a barley field. More gates, stiles, streams. Now we were back on Littleton Lane for a final drag uphill to the finish. I was tired but the runners around me were too, maybe more so. The tall runner from Weston AC was walking. I went past. Further on, I passed Matt. Briefly I nosed ahead of Andrew Malloy but that spurred him to up his pace and pull away again. One last momentum-sapping stop-start through a gate and I could see the line. Was Matt on my heels or 50m away? Now would not be a good time to look back. I blundered through thistles and cowpats and crossed the line exhausted but in control. The 5th place I thought I&amp;#8217;d got turned out to be 4th. Result!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary: in the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;WW, BB, PP and DT&lt;/a&gt; races I came 9th 6th 5th 4th with times of 39:45, 37:11, 42:52 and 42:32.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the TACH team for organising such a great series of races with good humour and efficiency. I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to next year already. Four pubs did well to serve drinks to all those thirsty runners but I guess they did well out of it too. Thanks to Matt for transporting the Swansea Harriers team. Thanks also to Rachel Foyle and Emma Postlethwaite for allowing me to use their fine photos here. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-07-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-tach-ticks-talk</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh castles relay 2013, the Drovers Armsless leg</title>
<description>&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/wcr-stage14-profile.png" alt="WCR stage 14 profile"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard Matt Burns would represent Southville Running Club on the &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/stage-14/"&gt;Drovers Arms leg&lt;/a&gt; of the Welsh Castles Relay, the race&amp;#8217;s queen stage, I had to ask Gary, the Swansea Harriers team manager, if I could run it too. He warned me:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stage 14 is a nightmare, the road zigzags up the mountain, not for the fainthearted!!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zigzags and mountains don&amp;#8217;t scare me. What does scare me is bright sunshine and that&amp;#8217;s what we had on Sunday. I slathered on sunscreen and lurked in the shadows in sunglasses waiting for the stage to start.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confusion at the briefing.  An illegal rave at the top of the mountain: police had closed the road. We&amp;#8217;ll finish the stage a mile early, the race official said. We&amp;#8217;ll see what we can do. We&amp;#8217;ll try and get you through. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, there&amp;#8217;d been talk of a vintage car rally coming down the mountain at the same time as we we ran up it. No rally, apparently; instead, a rave. I guess anyone holding a 20 stage road race over a summer weekend has to think on their feet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off. I settled into a steady pace. There&amp;#8217;d be plenty of opportunity to burn energy later. The rolling route left Builth Wells on the A483 heading west, hills rising ominously to the south. Supporters offered wet sponges and water. Thanks!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Garth we turned and ducked under the railway line and then the climb started. I was passing runners now. For the first time I could see Matt, not so far ahead of me. At the side of the road a sun-burned and dreadlocked girl huddled against the crash barrier.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary had warned me about the false summit. You get to the top and then you&amp;#8217;ve another couple of miles to go. Except today we hadn&amp;#8217;t and there, at the top of the first climb, suddenly, was the finish line. Oh.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9020573242/" title="WCR 2013 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2834/9020573242_1fd3662ee2_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="WCR 2013"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The views were spectacular. I felt uncomfortably fresh, especially considering I&amp;#8217;d just run the best part of nine miles the last two which had been uphill. We set off to follow the next two stages of the race. Rob had the top of his BMW down. It took a few tense minutes to negotiate the road past the Drovers, reduced to a single lane by vehicles on the verges. Team vans were trying to head in both directions as the music throbbed and pulsed and ravers staggered around in the sunshone. Down the hill the police were methodically pulling over and questioning people.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a period of several minutes on the run into Brecon we overtook the stage 15 runners. Mark Roberts, one of Swansea&amp;#8217;s finest, was near the front; ahead of him some seriously good athletes from Altringham, Port Talbot, Les Croupiers, Hare and Hounds tore up the road. On the way out of Brecon we passed by stage 16, the mountain stage &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html"&gt;I&amp;#8217;d run in filthy weather two years earlier&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="480" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/n6-3dYvcEeE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swansea Harriers were 11th overall, 2nd in the vets category just 16 minutes behind &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/storage/wcr-2013/team%20bath%20newsletter.pdf" title="The Bath Plug - a great read"&gt;Bath&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s the fastest time we&amp;#8217;ve completed the route in for some years. Thanks to Rob Falconer for providing a lift, the photo, and for putting in &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6-3dYvcEeE"&gt;a storming run on stage 13&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks again to Gary Irving: as manager of a veterans&amp;#8217; team I think he accepts and expects a few injuries will upset his plans, but four people pulling out in the final week, that&amp;#8217;s tough!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-06-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2013</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>2012-2013 Cross Country season and some</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I recorded some of my race results since the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012.html"&gt;WCR, 2012&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next race was the &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk"&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt; opener at Newbridge Fields, Bridgend. I ran this same course the year before on a cold, blustery day, sheets of rain swirling. This time, the weather turned out unseasonably warm. I came &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm121i.htm"&gt;78th with a time of 38:22&lt;/a&gt;, an improvement of 26 places and 3 minutes over my previous outing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4531393735/" title="Whiteford Sands lighthouse by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2772/4531393735_eba09f0864.jpg" width="500" height="371" alt="Whiteford Sands lighthouse"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after I ran closer to home in the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;West Glamorgan League at Llanmadoc&lt;/a&gt;. Although the rain held off on the day, it hadn&amp;#8217;t over the past weeks and the track out to the lighthouse comprised a series of ponds linked by mud. I made a mistake lining up for the start some way from the front of the field and ended up jostled and sodden by the time the race stretched out and settled in. After, I hooked up with Ifan for a warm down; we ran the full route a second time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://westglamleague.co.uk/resources/_wsb_417x374_West+Glam+League+at+Llanmadoc.jpg" alt="puddles"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle, Bristol, for the 3rd fixture in the Gwent League. Isobel and Alex ran too. I tried to keep up with Eamon but he pulled away on the second lap. In the closing stages I looked over my shoulder to see Raul storming towards me. I had enough left, or he timed his surge for the line too late; either way I &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm123i.htm"&gt;finished ahead of him&lt;/a&gt;, but I can&amp;#8217;t see that happening next time we race together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was it, my cross country season over. I was supposed to run the Welsh regional cross country championships but didn&amp;#8217;t make it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of January this year I ran the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolandwestac.org/bridge-inn-5k"&gt;Bridge Inn 5K&lt;/a&gt; on a very windy night and did well to finish &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0BzIFRjtRS2vBVkE3b1dWV0RrUUU/edit"&gt;a few seconds&lt;/a&gt; before Matt Burns.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I ran the first of four alliterative &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;TACH races&lt;/a&gt;, the Wrington Woodland run, which I thoroughly enjoyed. The &lt;a href="http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/v2/181608257/218757"&gt;course&lt;/a&gt; started in Cleeve with a long but gradual climb up a woodland track. After a few dry weeks the surface was rocky and rutted. Matt (who I beat in the 5K, remember?) strode ahead a few minutes in, clocking a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow; and, as it turned out, noone else could either. As we crested the top of the climb Andy overtook me. On the descent to Wrington another runner bounded past. I wasn&amp;#8217;t feeling too fresh by Bullnose Lane, the second uphill section, and settled on trying to hold my place rather than catch anyone. Even that proved optimistic and a couple of runners pegged me back before the final descent back to Cleeve.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased with &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=wrington_result13.inc"&gt;9th place&lt;/a&gt;. Congratulations to Matt on his well deserved win! A diet of interval training and competitive racing have honed his form and after a series of top ten placings in recent events it came down to when not if.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.srcbristol.hostoi.com/images/sidebar/bristol_running_club_matt.jpg" alt="Burnsy" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh castles relay 2012, 14 seconds and 30 years apart</title>
<description>&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/wcr-stage19-profile.png" alt="WCR stage 19 profile"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html"&gt;I ran a mountain stage&lt;/a&gt; through heavy rain and into the wind. This year I ran a flat stage, well, flat for Wales, and &amp;#8212; despite news reports of flooding and dams bursting &amp;#8212; the weather was just fine: overcast, a light wind, not too hot. We gathered in Navigation Park, Abercynon, just off the A470. For &amp;#8220;park&amp;#8221; read &amp;#8220;industrial estate&amp;#8221;. After waiting a few minutes after the scheduled start time of 14:25 for the Turner Broadcasting runner to (not) appear, we were off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/7371400078/" title="Stage 19 of 2012 Welsh castles relay by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5453/7371400078_d53029aa40_o.jpg" width="500" height="331" alt="Stage 19 of 2012 Welsh castles relay"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route climbed over the A470 and curved around to point south. After the usual initial shakeout the race settled down and I could see 7 runners ahead of me; within distance, but ahead. After a brief diversion through the Rhydfelin Housing estate we hit the Taff Trail. I&amp;#8217;d been here before, &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cycling-the-celtic-trail.html"&gt;on a bike&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a disused railway line, straight, level and shaded by trees. Cow parsley and nettles towered in the muddy verges. Insects hovered in the humid air. I was running alongside a Sarn Helen runner and could see two runners ahead. Then one pulled up. Over the course of a couple of steady miles we hauled in and passed the other. I looked back &amp;#8212; mistake &amp;#8212; and saw a Vale Royal AC runner approaching fast.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the Taff Trail we doubled back on to the Old Nantgarw road, a country lane heading sharply upwards. Ifan had warned me about this and now the marshalls at the bottom of the climb warned me again. About a mile uphill, it does get easier, look out for cars.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="562" height="400" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=Nantgarw+Road,+Caerphilly,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;aq=0&amp;amp;oq=nantga&amp;amp;sll=51.587465,-4.195722&amp;amp;sspn=0.021118,0.036864&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Nantgarw+Rd,+Caerphilly,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=51.56495,-3.263349&amp;amp;panoid=_hWpHiBOqTf0Gzom22AVqg&amp;amp;cbp=13,0,,0,0&amp;amp;ll=51.558823,-3.263369&amp;amp;spn=0.021345,0.048237&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;output=svembed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my chance. I&amp;#8217;d lost sight of the runner ahead of me but I used the slope to push ahead of Sarn Helen and Vale Royal. Dig in, don&amp;#8217;t look back. Hills suit my legs. A couple of off-road motorbikes bowled down the hill. More marshalls stood at the turn on to Groeswen Road. I&amp;#8217;d drunk enough water but grabbed a sponge and wrung it over my head.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The climb sets the stage finish up, that&amp;#8217;s how Ifan had described it, and he should know: he won this stage last year. It&amp;#8217;s all downhill, lots of turns, all the way to Caerphilly. As the road swerved and tilted I saw the castle, a crumbled pile of stones, far away, further than I&amp;#8217;d hoped. Now I looked back &amp;#8212; no sign of anyone. I lengthened my stride, letting gravity swing my tired legs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swansea Harriers were marshalling the finish of the stage so I got some welcome support on the run in. You&amp;#8217;re going well, said Gary. How far now? I asked Kevin. About a mile.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mile! As good as a miss. Vale Royal had me in sight, blue and yellow squares. Luckily it was a short mile. I turned a corner and suddenly there were flags and people. Is that the finish? I sprinted for the line. My time was &lt;a href="http://www.welshcastlesrelay.org.uk/results/2012/s19p_2012.html" title="Stage 19 - Navigation Park to Caerphilly Castle"&gt;01:12:08&lt;/a&gt;, 4:09 behind the stage winner. 12 seconds later Vale Royal appeared and another 27 seconds behind him, Sarn Helen. I came 5th, the first runner from a veterans team, but the runners ahead of me were veterans running in the open category. Anyone over 35 counts as a veteran, which makes no sense in endurance events: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haile_Gebrselassie"&gt;Haile Gebrselassie&lt;/a&gt; knocked 27 seconds off his own world marathon record at the age of 35.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t hang around in Caerphilly. I wanted to catch the finish of the next stage &amp;#8212; leg 20, the final stage &amp;#8212; which was scheduled to arrive in Cardiff at 16:00. The car was where Ifan had said it would be. I put my foot down. Djokovic and Nadal slugged it out on the radio. But a car is no match for a runner approachng the capital and by the time I&amp;#8217;d negotiated roundabouts, traffic lights and ticket machines the race was done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studying the results later I discovered the first two home were separated by 14 seconds and 30 years! With Paul Hammond&amp;#8217;s permission, here&amp;#8217;s the culmination of 20+ hours of racing over 20 stages and two days. Andrew Greenleaf pips the veteran &amp;#8212; who, at twice the younger runner&amp;#8217;s age, truly &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; a veteran &amp;#8212; Andrew Greenleaf in black pips Martin Rees in white to the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="667" height="500"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2F&amp;set_id=72157630125808318&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2F&amp;set_id=72157630125808318&amp;jump_to=" width="667" height="500"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The castles relay offers lots of prizes in lots of categories. The grounds of Cardiff castle are a fine venue for an extended awards ceremony. I drank sweet tea from a thermos flask and munched garibaldis and shook my legs to stop them seizing up. My team, Swansea Harriers veterans, came second in their category, some way behind the Les Croupiers vets. We were monarchs of the mountains, collected first veterans team in a couple of mountain stages, and &lt;a href="http://www.thepowerof10.info/athletes/profile.aspx?athleteid=8208"&gt;Matthew Gurmin&lt;/a&gt; won &lt;a href="http://www.welshcastlesrelay.org.uk/results/2012/s17p_2012.html"&gt;stage 17&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Paul Hammond for allowing me to reproduce here some of his superb photos of the event. The versions here are low resolution copies. The originals are on &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hammy8241"&gt;Paul Hammond&amp;#8217;s Flickr site&lt;/a&gt;. I also want to thank Gary Irving for his immense effort getting the team organised.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-06-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cross country catch up</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I posted these old race reports &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Inter-Regional &amp;amp; Masters Championships, Builth Wells, December 10th 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did say, at the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011.html"&gt;Fairwood race&lt;/a&gt;, I was invited to represent West Wales in the &lt;a href="http://www.welshathletics.org/competitions/events/cross-country/2011/12-dec/welsh-inter-regional-cross-country-championships.aspx"&gt;inter-regional championships&lt;/a&gt;? Well, the day had come, a chill December morning. White frost coated the meadow at Parkmill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ifan took the scenic route through Llandeilo and LLandovery &amp;#8230; I sank back into the passenger seat and watched the hills roll by. We parked outside the showground and crunched across ice and gravel to the race HQ where the tarpaulin they&amp;#8217;d laid down on the floor was already rucked and muddy. Red and white tapes zig-zagged up the hill, marking out the course.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collected my West Wales vest. When you get a heavy course, like today, one which includes sections of concrete and tarmac, Ifan said, use longer spikes here and shorter ones here, under the ball of the foot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just over an hour to go we jogged a warm-up lap, starting with an extended climb through the woods. You can push on here, he said, as we emerged from the trees and passed a static caravan, still climbing, it&amp;#8217;s downhill for a while after this. At the summit stood an enormous speaker, part of the showground&amp;#8217;s PA system. I could see the Builth Wells showground now &amp;#8212; the timber-clad buildings, the neat field, the high boundary fence &amp;#8212; like a stage in the centre of the immense ampitheatre formed by the surrounding hills.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunlight poked through the clouds as we lined up at the start, shivering, edgy. One short lap and two long ones. I found my place and settled in. On the first climb my way was blocked by a tall runner. I moved left to overtake. He moved left. I moved right. He moved right. I passed him by the caravan and extended my lead downhill. Briefly, our route intersected the U15 girls&amp;#8217; race and I was dodging elbows, legs, pony-tails. On the long flat section round the playing fields the tall runner pegged me back. I let him go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching the climb for the second time, the ground had softened. I went past a couple of runners who&amp;#8217;d gone out too fast. I dug in as the path steepened, skeetering wide through tree roots, leaf mould and brambles to pass him. I was clear now but there were two more in front to aim at. I remembered Ifan&amp;#8217;s advice and stumbled over the top on empty, relying on gravity to recharge my legs on the descent. I bounded down a final rocky path, arms flailing, and held on till the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6955236875/" title="13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7202/6955236875_2d6a00c8d9.jpg" width="500" height="335" alt="13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;West Glamorgan League, Margam, January 8th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/4.html"&gt;Margam&lt;/a&gt; at eleven in time to see the race start without me. Lesson being, the West Glamorgan races are organised differently. The sight of all those humans on the move had animated the park&amp;#8217;s deer herd. I watched them hurtle round their own short course. I ran the route anyway, slowly, and very boggy it was too. Next time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cardiff Cross Challenge, January 15th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://cardiffxchallenge.wordpress.com/the-event/"&gt;McCain Cardiff cross challenge&lt;/a&gt;, held just north of the city centre in Blackweir Fields, is &amp;#8220;one of the most prestigious Cross Country events in the UK&amp;#8221;. Isobel was running. Last time she&amp;#8217;d run, in the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011.html"&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt;, around a foul course in filthy weather, she&amp;#8217;d failed to finish, so it was a crucial event for her. We arrived in good time and registered. She&amp;#8217;d be wearing her Afan-Nedd-Tawe vest. I&amp;#8217;d be running for Swansea Harriers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the going looked fine. The sun was out, the wind was down. The course was flat, dry, sheltered. Isobel had a solid run, finishing strongly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, they&amp;#8217;d fine-tuned the schedule, overlapping races, closing and opening routes through the parkland, somehow without any runners getting trampled, confused or impeded, and so it was that the senior men&amp;#8217;s event, the last of the day, would be starting just an hour after Isobel had finished. With 5 minutes to go I made my way to the starting pen. Where was everyone? Suddenly the elite runners appeared, peeling off thermals, shaking long, elastic legs. We&amp;#8217;d be running four times round. I realised I was in danger of getting lapped.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/IwVLNiAQYps?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily I avoided any such ignominy. The course seemed tame &amp;#8212; where were the hills, swamps, trenches, wild animals? Isobel injected some welcome variety, appearing at random positions to cheer me on, and her encouragement helped me maintain my pace and place. I did pass one runner on the final lap and pushed hard to close the gap on the next, a tall lad in a black vest, but, closing in on the finish, he kicked away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Cross Country Championships, St Fagans, February 18th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6910503621/" title="Start and finished by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7053/6910503621_5807ae1e07.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Start and finished"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Torrential rain and wind during the morning made for very difficult conditions on an already tough course for the 108th running of the Welsh Cross Country Championships. While the junior races were run in these treacherous conditions, the rain had stopped by the time the senior athletes were on the starting line; the damage to the course, however, was already done. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.welshathletics.org/news--media/news/cross-country/2012/02-feb/jones-and-griffiths-clinch-cross-country-welsh-titles.aspx"&gt;Welsh Athletics race report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hats off to Isobel for getting round this one. She lasted longer than the inflatable start and finish markers, which were swiftly deflated and packed away before the wind ripped them up. After, she went with Gail and Alex to visit the &lt;a href="http://www.museumwales.ac.uk/en/stfagans/"&gt;National History Museum&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain had indeed stopped by the time the men&amp;#8217;s race started but the course was brutal. I slogged my way round one, two, three, four laps, and was glad when it ended. I pulled my bag from the mud and squelched back through the field to the road-side, texting Gail to collect me.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-06-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cross country, Singleton Park 2011</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday 4th December was the 3rd of 5 league cross county fixtures at home in Singleton Park where all the ideal cross country ingredients were available, rain, hail, long steep hills and thick muddy bogs, very many congratulations to everyone who competed on one of the toughest cross country courses around.
   &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk"&gt;http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6435309037/" title="Gwent League cross country, December 2011, Singleton Park Swansea by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7167/6435309037_fe064f27e6.jpg" width="500" height="387" alt="Gwent League cross country, December 2011, Singleton Park Swansea"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many &lt;a href="http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk/" title="Swansea harriers website"&gt;Swansea Harriers&lt;/a&gt; had turned out for the previous Gwent League event, held a month ago in Bath, and team manager Kevin Corcoran expected a good showing for today&amp;#8217;s event &amp;#8212; a home fixtur in Singleton Park. The going will be heavy, his email said, bring spikes!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly we&amp;#8217;d help boost the numbers. Alex would be racing his first race for the club, the novice boys at 12:06, to be followed immediately by Isobel in the U13 girls at 12:15. The Senior men&amp;#8217;s race &amp;#8212; me! &amp;#8212; wouldn&amp;#8217;t start until 14:50. Because of the time gaps and the wintry weather Gail decided to drive the kids, getting there in time to register and then head back with them as soon as they&amp;#8217;d run. I&amp;#8217;d travel independently by bike: a good way to warm up and cool down, I reckoned.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rain spat as I started my journey. A fresh wind pushed clouds across the sky. Half an hour later I pedalled through the crowded car park at Bishop Gore school, locked my bike to the railings, then made my way to the club tent.  Take it slowly to start with, I told Alex, save something for the finish. He doesn&amp;#8217;t have running spikes and I had suggested he wore his rugby boots, but he wanted to wear his trainers. He doesn&amp;#8217;t have a club vest either and was wearing a &lt;a href="http://www.skins.net"&gt;thermal top&lt;/a&gt;. There he stood, black top, black shorts, anxious, ready to go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route starts with a climb then loops around the park back to the start and climbs again to the finish. He was going well. Dan turned up with Fynn, Cai and Schnorbie. We cheered, Alex responded, passing four people at speed on the final muddy climb. Rain slashed down in a sudden squall. He crossed the line, exhausted, breathless, on the verge of tears. I wanted to get to him and get him warm and dry but he had to follow the finish-line protocol: waiting in line to collect his token, waiting again to hand it over to the team manager.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bundled Alex into the tent and pulled dry clothes over the top of his wet  muddy kit. It had been a tough race for him. Isobel&amp;#8217;s race had already started &amp;#8212; two laps for her. She was in trouble on the first climb, looking to us, shaking her head. She&amp;#8217;s pulled out, Gail said. What? Never! Isobel&amp;#8217;s already an experienced runner: she knows how to pace herself. But it was true, she was walking back, in tears.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#8217;t breathe, she said. You&amp;#8217;re not cross with me?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course not. I hugged her.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made our way back to the car. I reassured Isobel. It happened. Now you know, and you&amp;#8217;ll know what to do next time. It won&amp;#8217;t happen again. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;#8217;t make her go to harriers, it&amp;#8217;s her choice &amp;#8212; what she wants to do &amp;#8212; but the club insists its members compete. It&amp;#8217;s not about keeping fit. One of the novice girls had lost a shoe, it stuck in the mud at the start, and she&amp;#8217;d run up the hill wearing one shoe and carrying the other, had her footwear refitted, and gone on to finish, gaining points for her team.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family had gone now. Two and a half hours until my race. I was wearing several layers of clothing and all of them were damp. The rain had stopped but the wind was tugging more clouds our way. My fingers and toes were cold. I walked the route. Downhill, the ground was waterlogged. The map showed the route fording something described as a spring, and what I&amp;#8217;d pictured as clear running water turned out to be a trench overflowing with viscous mud.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped to talk with a couple of marshals who stood dressed like fishermen in the middle of the park. They explained the route to me in some detail. There&amp;#8217;d been a fault with the original version of the map, the one I&amp;#8217;d seen online. It said the senior men would run three medium loops and one full one but we&amp;#8217;d actually be running one medium loop and three full ones. The course could have been simplified, they thought, joining points together and eliminating whole sections. They could have overlapped events and had more than one group out at once. The U15 girls race had started now, and the marshals trudged into position.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the start line I queued for a cup of tea from the Licensed to Grill van. It wasn&amp;#8217;t hot enough or strong enough but it warmed my fingers. I ate a banana and one of the welsh cakes I&amp;#8217;d packed. A mobile shoe shop had set itself up near the start line. My feet are short and wide. They had a good selection of of cross country spikes and the Adidas ones fitted perfectly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/cross-country-spikes.jpg" alt="cross country spikes"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran a short warm up with a couple of others then got changed. I wondered if Ifan was coming? At last the race started. I ran eagerly along the top section then let gravity lengthen my stride downhill. Oh, there he was, just in front. I checked myself slightly. Plenty of time to accelerate later.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spikes feel different to the trail shoes I&amp;#8217;m used to: lighter, less stable. Faster? Maybe.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try and find firmer ground. Take muddy corners wide. Run closer to foliage &amp;#8212; being shorter, I can duck under the tagged branches. Up and downhill I do better. I could improve on the flat and through mud.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Fulcher came past at speed on the final lap but I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow him. I was locked into my pace and my group and there I stayed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to congratulate Ifan who&amp;#8217;d finished 22nd. I was happy with 45th. They were filming him for some Vets 24/7 program which BBC Wales will screen next year. I did hear them ask, if he was a veteran runner and a veteranarian, did that make him a vet vet?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I returned to the tent and ate another welsh cake pulling layers of clothing back on. My lined cycling gloves are a real struggle to put on when damp. Rain hammered down. Cars queued to leave Bishop Gore car park. One which had parked on the field spun its wheels in the mud.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-12-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>West Wales cross country championships, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6349344373/" title="Race number 6 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6112/6349344373_a530c3c561.jpg" width="500" height="389" alt="Race number 6"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned up early enough to register Isobel too &amp;#8212; she&amp;#8217;d compete in the first event of the day, the U13 girls, and I&amp;#8217;d run the final event, the senior mens &amp;#8212; and collected race number 6, not to be confused with 9. We were at the Swansea University playing fields, Fairwood, for the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html"&gt;second race in the West Glamorgan cross country league&lt;/a&gt;, incorporating the West Wales championships.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was sunny and fresh. Recent rainfall had soaked the ground. Perfect cross country conditions. Gail, Alex and my parents arrived in time to see Isobel start, but only just: they&amp;#8217;d been watching Alex play rugby at Penclawdd, where the referee had extended the game because the home team were about to score a try.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls were strung along the far side of the field, the front runners striding out. Pembrokeshire Harriers had the first two places. We intercepted the route to cheer Isobel along the first and second fields &amp;#8212; the up and down bit of the course &amp;#8212; then climbed the bank to the finish line, by the observatory. She did well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An hour to go before the men&amp;#8217;s race. My family found a place to sit and Gail sorted them out with hot drinks and snacks. I got myself ready. I knew a few people from the Saturday morning runs: Ifan, the animal beast monster; Ross, the &lt;a href="http://www.gowertriathlon.com/results.asp" title="Ross Simpson, winner of the Gower olympic distance triathlon"&gt;race-winning triathlete&lt;/a&gt;, who&amp;#8217;d competed in another event yesterday and been training on the bike this morning; Raul, who couldn&amp;#8217;t believe I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be doing the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-coast-half-marathon.html" title="My report on the Gower coast half marathon, 2010"&gt;Gower coastal half marathon&lt;/a&gt; next weekend; and Simon who asked if I was running, and then said, shame, he wouldn&amp;#8217;t win. I laced my shoes tightly and double-knotted them: at &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011.html"&gt;Bridgend&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#8217;d almost left one stuck in the mud. I recognised a few more athletes from Bridgend and &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html" title="Welsh castles relay, 2011"&gt;Brecon&lt;/a&gt;. Many have the look &amp;#8212; skinny, long-limbed, elastic &amp;#8212; but by no means all, and, even at the age of 47, I&amp;#8217;m far from being the oldest: these guys never give up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tail-enders in the women&amp;#8217;s race were finishing. Not long now. I jogged across the pitch and back, keeping warm. Go!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people complain about running laps rather than a single extended circuit, but, as someone new to the course, it suits me. I gave it more than at &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011.html"&gt;Bridgend&lt;/a&gt;, striding out on the downhills, digging in on the climbs. Ross came alongside me on the second lap. He runs so smoothly. Go on, Thomas! That was Gail. Mrs Smith, Isobel&amp;#8217;s ironman science teacher, had finished the women&amp;#8217;s race in time to take up a position on the second field and encourage everyone. Appreciated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up my pace on the final lap. Amazingly, Ross fell back. I&amp;#8217;d dropped him. One last push to the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="600" height="450"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2F&amp;set_id=72157628136270030&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157628136270030%2F&amp;set_id=72157628136270030&amp;jump_to=" width="600" height="450"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.clickonwales.org/2011/06/sport-sponsored-by-sport-wales/" title="Dr David Hedydd Davies, MBE"&gt;Dr Hedydd Davies&lt;/a&gt; handed me a letter as I crossed the line: an invitation to run for West Wales in the inter-regional championships in Builth Wells! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6350090562/" title="letter by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6051/6350090562_5c5a44f002.jpg" width="333" height="500" alt="letter"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m accepting, of course, but have two questions: what size vest? and should I get spikes?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Chris Fulcher for allowing me to use his wonderful photos. More of &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/102718880405756419943/WestGlamLeagueFairwood2011"&gt;his photos of the event can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-11-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cardiff Half, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Michael&amp;#8217;s Tom Tom guided us from the M4 to Grangetown Station. We parked alongside the Taff. Michael ate a banana and changed into his Swansea City shorts, which he thought appropriate since the route would be passing &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=85440788632" title="Cardiff FC's stadium looks like legoland!!!"&gt;Legoland&lt;/a&gt;. We made fall-back plans where to meet after then set off on foot, falling into line with the gathering crowds heading the same way. Ahead rose the metallic curve of the national arts centre, gleaming in the sunlight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisbewick/2530299841/" title="Wales Millenium Centre by Chris Bewick, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3082/2530299841_d018dd7422.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Wales Millenium Centre"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it say on the front? That&amp;#8217;s a classic pub quiz question.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the stones sing in silence. I don&amp;#8217;t know. Something like that. It&amp;#8217;s in Welsh and English.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; ?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on then, what does it say?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know either, Michael admitted. Now we were right there beneath the imposing lettering but didn&amp;#8217;t bother checking. The runners village was swarming with runners getting ready. We had to prepare.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plas Roald Dahl is built on a scale to accommodate 15000 runners and supporters &amp;#8212; excepting toilet facilities. Queues for the portaloos folded back on themselves. We shook hands and separated. With half an hour to go I stripped off and deposited my kit bag. I made my way to the start, down to the waterfront, left, past the Senedd, left again, then tried to find the right starting pen. My number was blue, meaning an expected finishing time between 1:20 and 1:30. The instructions from the PA alternated between English and Welsh, happily noting the sun had come out, there was no wind, the route was flat &amp;#8212; the event record could well be broken.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In amongst the packed athletes I discovered Mike Rimmer, Mark, Pippa and Michael (again). They were huddled close to the 1:30 pace-maker. Push up, Mike ordered, and I don&amp;#8217;t want to see you till the end of the race! I squeezed and twisted and wriggled a few metres forward then gave up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a welcome message from the mayor we were off, shuffling, walking, striding, jogging, running. After &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html" title="Bristol half marathon, 2011, when I got my pace all wrong"&gt;Bristol&lt;/a&gt;, I took it easy to begin with, settling into the race rather than wasting energy trying to weave through the pack. Soon the roads broadened, proper city avenues and boulevards, and I could run my own pace.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro-cyclist David Millar recently tweeted about his specialism, time-trialling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;TT&amp;#8217;s are weird. Imagine the best long-distance runners being set off at 1min intervals to TT 20km. Be considered mad. Cycling = Madness. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125523908874084353"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A TT generally involves the athlete emptying their tank completely in order to post the fastest time they are physically capable of. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125528302248136704"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A mass-start race involves tactics and economising of effort in order to cross the finish-line first. Winner often the freshest at the end. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125529177037348864"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting, as far as it goes &amp;#8212; but in a regular bike race tactics and positioning are paramount and in athletics a strong athlete can run off the front. For me, the half marathon is a time trial. I&amp;#8217;m racing against the clock and emptying the tank. I look for the mile markers and check my time as I pass them. A 6:10 pace would bring me in at around 1 hour and 21 minutes, just under.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miles 8 and 9, the route heads in then out on the same arterial road, doubling back at a spectator-packed roundabout. It gives you a chance to watch faster runners, some really fast runners &amp;#8212; and to appreciate the scale of the event. Go on Ifan! I shouted. His head stayed down, he was working hard. He&amp;#8217;d heard me. My legs still felt good. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At mile 10 there&amp;#8217;s a climb. It&amp;#8217;s not so steep but it&amp;#8217;s long enough and it comes at just the wrong stage of the race. I&amp;#8217;d slipped a few seconds. The arithmetic was getting harder. Dig in!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gordonplant/2705863581/" title="Cardiff Bay by gordonplant, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3260/2705863581_e4ce2d5006.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Cardiff Bay"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the final stretch, along the Cardiff Bay barrage. You&amp;#8217;re exposed to the wind but today there wasn&amp;#8217;t any, just a fabulous approach to the capital, towards the Norwegian Church, the Assembly, the &lt;a href="http://images.google.com/search?tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=cardiff+armadillo"&gt;Armadillo&lt;/a&gt;. Those efforts along the Avon towpath, the interval sessions on Oxwich beach &amp;#8212; now they make sense: you know how it feels to run at tempo when legs are burning and lungs are heaving. I was going to do it!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6329991144/" title="1:21:31.07 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6053/6329991144_2e8410288b.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:21:31.07"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:21:31:07 it said on my watch. My official chip time, received in a text message an hour or so later, was 1:21:30, a personal best by almost half a minute. I was wiped out but not hurting, not like &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html" title="Bristol half marathon, 2011, when I got my pace all wrong"&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d finished 110th.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6330006162/" title="Cardiff half marathon 2011 race results for Thomas Guest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6117/6330006162_8acba32865.jpg" width="500" height="321" alt="Cardiff half marathon 2011 race results for Thomas Guest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gordonplant/" title="gordonplant's photostream, on flickr"&gt;gordonplant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisbewick"&gt;Chris Bewick&lt;/a&gt; for allowing me to use their fine photos of Cardiff Bay and the Millenium Centre in this article.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cardiff-half-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cardiff-half-2011</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Gwent cross country league, Bridgend, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6234349086/" title="Newbridge fields, Bridgend, cross country course by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6224/6234349086_3d3a5cec9c.jpg" width="500" height="391" alt="Newbridge fields, Bridgend, cross country course"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drove from Swansea along the M4, the car buffeted by gusting winds, windscreen wipers swiping away the rain. We parked at Bridgend recreation centre and walked along a concrete-lined service road and past a wet playground. There was the race HQ &amp;#8212; Bridgend Athletics club.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isobel was nervous. What time is it? There should be a tent. Stay close to me. Is that Andrew? What time is it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were lots of tents and lots of tall track-suited men who could have been Andrew. Striped tape stretched between plastic posts, marking out the route. There was the finish line. The PA system chattered away. 7 minutes till the novice boys&amp;#8217; race, the first event of the day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found the Swansea Harriers tent and reported in. &amp;#163;1 for the under 13 event, &amp;#163;4 for seniors. Isobel fell in with some friends and was gone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked over the bridge and onto the fields, heading for the start. The novice boys were on the course now, stretched in a line between the river and the rugby pitch. Spectators struggled to control umbrellas. Dogs tugged at leads.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isobel found me again, wanting to hand over her clothes. Half an hour, I said. Keep warm. Do you need the loo? Are you thirsty? I&amp;#8217;d keep those on, really, don&amp;#8217;t get cold. But she wanted to be ready. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novice girls swung round towards the bridge. The first runner passed, straight-faced, serious. She wouldn&amp;#8217;t be caught. More lone front runners, then clumps. Go on! Well run! Towards the back, tears, girls walking, being urged to push on.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6230068047/" title="U13 U13 Boys cross country race, Newbridge Fields, Bridgend by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6230068047_653525fc23.jpg" width="500" height="288" alt="U13 U13 Boys cross country race, Newbridge Fields, Bridgend"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The under 13 boys&amp;#8217; race now. They shivered and twitched then set off at a sprint. Isobel was with her team getting final words of advice. The under 13 boys were on their way back. The leaders hadn&amp;#8217;t slowed down at all. The girls lined up. Over a hundred of them, I should think. Aberdare, Aberystwyth, Barry, Bath, Bridgend, Bristol, Caerleon, Cardiff, Carmarthen, Chepstow, Gorseinon, Griffithstown, Llanelli, Lliswerry, Neath, Newport, Pembrokeshire, Penarth, Pontypridd, Port Talbot, Porthcawl, Rhondda, Stroud, Swansea, Taunton, Wells, Westbury, Weston.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She ran well, at a steady pace. I cut across the course to cheer her on at different points: by the river, at the bridge, near the woods, and I was there waiting at the finish line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;56th. I hugged her. Well done! I need spikes, dad. So muddy, I mean it is soooo muddy! I&amp;#8217;m really pleased, are you pleased? I didn&amp;#8217;t stop and walk. You did really well, I&amp;#8217;m proud of you. Really well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your turn now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, my turn. I got Isobel&amp;#8217;s kit, made sure she put it on, gave her money for a snack. No surprise to see Ifan Lloyd. I&amp;#8217;m guessing you know this course, I said. You could say that, yes. Yes, you could say. I knew I wouldn&amp;#8217;t see much of him during the race though. And there was Gary Irving, captain of the &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html"&gt;Welsh Castles Relay&lt;/a&gt; team, taller and thinner than ever. Was I over 50? No. Shame! We&amp;#8217;d have had a useful M50 team. Younger seniors crouched in the tent, swigging drinks, selecting footwear, unpeeling tights, rubbing muscles. I had stopped following the races now but was aware of the different age groups out on the course tracing different circuits different numbers of times, crossing and re-crossing. Some of the route posts had fallen over and loose tapes got trampled into the wet grass. The first senior women had finished, muddy and flushed. I got changed. Had a drink. Checked my laces. Queued for the toilet, then needed to go again. Jogged around the field. Now I was walking across the bridge to the start line. 5 minutes till off. And now we were off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fell into position in the middle of the pack. We passed the stone circle which marks the place where the &lt;a href="http://www.eisteddfod.org.uk/english/content.php?nID=55"&gt;Eisteddfod&lt;/a&gt; was held.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on daddy! There was Isobel with a friend. Come on Swansea!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6237143908/" title="Gwent League, Bridgend 2011, by Chris and Maxine Fulcher by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6036/6237143908_9902e8bdc4.jpg" width="500" height="332" alt="Gwent League, Bridgend 2011, by Chris and Maxine Fulcher"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran through mud churned by previous runners. I clung to the edges where the grass gave more traction. Downhill, I followed the slope, not the route. I slowed into corners, took them wide, then pushed on when we hit gravel and harder ground. Bang, man down! A sniper got him. Uphill in chopped strides, looking for footholds. Isobel appeared again. I waved, feeling good. The lead runners swerved ahead, rattling round far corners of the course. On the second lap I started moving up the field. The heel of my right shoe was too loose and stuck in the mud. Lace up more tightly next time. Field, field, woods, bridge, field. 3rd and final lap. I had something left. I charged for the line and funneled in, collecting a cardboard position token to be handed to my team manager.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seasoned runners bring two bottles of water. One for drinking, one for washing. A sign at the recreation centre said cross country runners were &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to use the facilities but we did anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day the &lt;a href="http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2011/res111.htm"&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; came through, and an email from Kevin Corcoran.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an outstanding day for the Senior Men with wins for Dewi Griffiths (Senior Men &amp;amp; Under 23), Mark Roberts (V40) and Ifan Lloyd (V50).  Dewi led our men to team victory over Cardiff and we also won the B Team Division in the process.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Chris and Maxine Fulcher for allowing me to take a copy of their fine &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6237143908"&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt;. More of &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/102718880405756419943/GwentLeagueBridgend2011#"&gt;their photos of the event can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gwent-cross-country-league-bridgend-2011</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol Half Marathon, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The half marathon I enjoyed most was the first one I ran, the Bath half, back in &amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not even sure, 12 years ago? I didn&amp;#8217;t know if I&amp;#8217;d be able to finish because I hadn&amp;#8217;t run the distance in training, so I started slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the race progressed I realised I &lt;strong&gt;would&lt;/strong&gt; finish, no problem, and I remember overtaking people in the second loop and sprinting the last stretch along Great Pulteney Street, crossing the line with a time of 1:42:15. Oh, I felt just great!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I&amp;#8217;ve run a few more half marathons and at each one I&amp;#8217;ve gone faster. At first I hacked chunks from my personal best but as time went on I was reduced to chipping away smaller gains. In 2003 I went below an hour and a half at Bristol, beating Steve Cram. In 2006 I returned to Bath and clocked &lt;a href="bath_half_2006.pdf"&gt;1:23:14&lt;/a&gt;. Wow! I didn&amp;#8217;t think I could better that but running the same event in 2007 I got down to 1:21:58 &amp;#8212; which meant running the first 9 miles at a speed of 6 minutes and 15 seconds per mile and then running the final 4 miles at the same speed, even though at every step every bit of me wanted it to end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day I retired from half marathons. I couldn&amp;#8217;t go any faster and I couldn&amp;#8217;t face up to going any slower and I hurt and I had had enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept running though. Cross country is my favourite, all weather, all terrain. I started going out with a group close to where I live, on Gower. Sand dunes, wooded tracks, marshland. Cefn Bryn from all faces. I joined a club in Bristol, where I work, threading through the alleyways and parkland of North Bristol. Then I hooked up with some friends for training runs on Wednesday lunchtimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gavinedmonds/5830288813/" title="GBR_1140 by Gavin Edmonds, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5152/5830288813_bf2b13d048_z.jpg" width="426" height="640" alt="GBR_1140"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, 6 March 2011, and friends from all of these groups were running the Bath half marathon. The weather was good. I was in fine form. As I said in an email to Andy:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m thinking my build-up for the Bath half has been pretty much perfect, except for my failure to enter, that is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andy went on to finish the race in a time of 1:21:51 &amp;#8212; fully half a second a mile faster than I&amp;#8217;d ever run. That did it! Later that week I signed up for the Bristol half marathon, to be run on September 11th 2011.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years since I&amp;#8217;ve been away, the Bristol half has become a huge event. I&amp;#8217;d been assigned a white number which meant I&amp;#8217;d be starting in the first section of the first wave. It still took me over 30 seconds to pass beneath the start line and I spent the first couple of miles dodging joggers with ipods and sharp elbowed veterans. Beneath the suspension bridge the race stretched out. I galloped along the portway. Soon after doubling back at Shirehampton I pulled alongside someone I knew.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Is that Neil?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Tom, How&amp;#8217;s it going?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Too damn fast. I&amp;#8217;m going too fast.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Nah, you&amp;#8217;re fine!&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shook my head. I &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt; going too fast but I couldn&amp;#8217;t slow down. Even though I was hurting and hadn&amp;#8217;t even gone halfway I let momentum take me past Neil and on to Spike Island. Already I wanted it over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route came back to the centre of town then cruelly swerved out again on an unwelcome tour of the sights. Great for spectators. Cobbles. Ramps. &lt;a href="http://www.seenoevilbristol.co.uk/"&gt;Grafitti&lt;/a&gt;. I was being overtaken. Falling away. Neil came smoothly past.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well done mate,&amp;#8221; I muttered.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;400m to go. At least I had space around me. Noone passed me in the final straight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pressed the button on my stop watch and collapsed, wiped out. I hurt and I knew I was going to hurt more tomorrow and the day after. There was Neil. I eased up on to my feet, started moving, slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6137800028/" title="1:22:14.94 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6076/6137800028_a469bae0a1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:22:14.94"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:22:14 my watch said.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the event has grown bigger they&amp;#8217;ve figured out how to organise it. You aren&amp;#8217;t allowed to pile-up round the finish line snatching goodie bags and hugging loved ones. They keep the exhausted, elated runners moving past a succession of hand-outs: space blanket, water, medal, banana, T-shirt, energy drink, leaflet, bag &amp;#8230; and after this personal awards ceremony you emerge light-headed into the sunshine in millenium square.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil ran 1:22:06, comfortably. For him, this was a training run: he&amp;#8217;s looking for a fast time in Stroud. My official time, &lt;a href="http://www.runbristol.com/SearchResults.aspx"&gt;online now&lt;/a&gt;, is 1:22:15. That&amp;#8217;s over a second a mile slower than I&amp;#8217;ve run before. I give in.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-09-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh castles relay 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We sat outside yesterday after an afternoon spent in the garden. The rain which had been forecast hadn&amp;#8217;t happened, and with any luck we&amp;#8217;d beat the forecast tomorrow as well, when I was due to run a mountain stage of the &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/" title="Welsh Castles relay website"&gt;Welsh Castles Relay&lt;/a&gt;. Odd to think the race was already half done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning the wind blew and the rain sliced down in diagonal lines. I pinned my number on my vest, packed some dry clothes, a banana, a flask of sweet tea. We arrived in Brecon &amp;#8212; me, Dan, Fynn, Cai, Schnorbie &amp;#8212; in good time, but to no obvious sign that stage 15 of the race would be finishing and stage 16 starting. Had we found the right place?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brief damp tour of the city centre later and runners had started to gather outside the &lt;a href="http://www.wellingtonbrecon.com/"&gt;Wellington Hotel&lt;/a&gt;. We huddled in an archway, shaking legs, keeping warm. Like penguins, someone said. Soon after the final runner signed in we were off. The road began to rise as soon as we left town, heading up into the Brecon Beacons national park. Water streamed down the gutters. Supporters gathered in lay-bys cheering us on.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Go on, Swansea!&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5824412733/" title="Welsh castles relay by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2789/5824412733_8bcd8584aa_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Welsh castles relay"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we were out of the tree line and on the mountain proper. The peaks were shrouded in mist. Streams tumbled white and fast. I was moving up the field. Sooner than I expected came the sign, one mile to go. I pushed on. The road neared the pass leaving us suddenly exposed. The wind ripped into us. I couldn&amp;#8217;t slow down now, couldn&amp;#8217;t let those runners I&amp;#8217;d passed catch me again. Dan was at the side of the road cheering me on, running with me. &amp;#8220;How far to go?&amp;#8221; The wind tore away his reply. Not far. It couldn&amp;#8217;t be far. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did I do? Not sure. I just wanted to get out of the wind, get warm and dry. At the start of the stage Gary said we were the second place veterans team but some 30 minutes behind the first place team. I hope Ifan won the &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/faq/tell-us-more/what-is-and-the-jeff-wood-stage.html"&gt;Jeff Wood stage&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drove back to Swansea and refuelled at the &lt;a href="http://uplandsdiner.co.uk" title="Can you b-eat the beast?"&gt;Uplands Diner&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5824885931/" title="Can you b-eat the beast? by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5193/5824885931_e8b79e99f5_z.jpg" width="640" height="238" alt="Can you b-eat the beast?"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite how an event like this ever gets organised, I don&amp;#8217;t know &amp;#8212; so my thanks to the organisers, especially to Gary who sorted out the Swansea Harriers veterans team. Thanks too to Dan, Fynn, Cai and Schnorbie for transport and support.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-06-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh castles relay preview</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5809004730/sizes/o" title="Welsh Castles Relay route by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2183/5809004730_3d040b28f7_z.jpg" width="444" height="640" alt="Welsh Castles Relay route"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I copied this fine map from the &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/storage/wcr-race-programme/27th%20Welsh%20Castles%20Relay%20Programme.pdf"&gt;2009 Welsh Castles Relay programme&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/" title="Welsh Castles relay website"&gt;WCR&lt;/a&gt; combines the disciplines of relay running, stage-racing and sight-seeing:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;All runners start each stage simultaneously, normally as the first runner from the previous stage finishes [&amp;#8230;] Thus each stage functions as a separate race. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/storage/wcr-information-pack/Team_%20information%202011.pdf" title="wcr team information (PDF)"&gt;WCR team information pack&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend 58 teams will race over 20 stages from Caernarfon Castle in the north all the way down to Cardiff Castle in the south. I&amp;#8217;ll be running for the Swansea Harriers veterans team and my race within a race is &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/stage-16/"&gt;stage 16, Brecon to the Beacons Reservoir&lt;/a&gt;, one of 6 mountain stages. I&amp;#8217;m not as sharp as I&amp;#8217;d like, having been resting a hamstring injury for the past few weeks but I&amp;#8217;m &lt;strong&gt;so&lt;/strong&gt; looking forward to it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poring through the &lt;a href="http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/storage/wcr-information-pack/Team_%20information%202011.pdf" title="wcr team information (PDF)"&gt;information pack&lt;/a&gt; I discover:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teams are relied on to conform to standards of good fellowship and sportsmanship to make the event enjoyable to all, without the necessity for rules to take account of every possible occurrence &amp;#8230; The use of water cannons and water pistols are not permitted.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-06-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-preview</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-preview</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Gower coast half marathon</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I ran the &lt;a href="http://www.endurancelife.com/event.asp?series=36&amp;amp;location=98"&gt;Gower coast half marathon&lt;/a&gt; today. It&amp;#8217;s a cracking route, heading past Fall Bay, round Worms Head, over the top of Rhossili Down, through Hillend, around Broughton Burrows, over Llanmadoc Hill, down to Llangennith, back along the soggy side of Rhossili Down to Mewslade, and then up and down the coast path to the finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wind had dropped and the sun was out. It was wet and muddy underfoot after all the recent rainfall.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly I found myself up with the leaders coming over Rhossili Down. Slowing up would probably be a good idea but running along Llangennith beach in the sunshine felt wonderful. The sand was firm and the waves were high and white. By Llanmadoc Hill I even had a small lead but by now my legs felt leaden. Running through the marshland below Rhossili Down was nasty. I wanted it to end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I ran a half marathon (2007) it took 1 hour and 22 minutes. Although the Gower course was a mile or two longer, and despite the challenging terrain, I reckoned I&amp;#8217;d be able to finish it in 1:40. Just keep going until 1:40, I told myself. I kept checking my watch. 1:40 passed. I slipped and stumbled along one of those rocky rural lanes which becomes a stream at this time of year. 1:45. I was on the coast path above Mewslade, my favourite beach. 1:50.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually finished with a time of 1:52:51. That&amp;#8217;s about twice as long as any of my training runs. I failed to spot the very last route marker and ended up going a few extra metres along a lane to the finish line rather than directly through a field &amp;#8212; which sadly meant Gail, Isobel and Alex didn&amp;#8217;t get to see me running. They did see me awarded my prize, though. A medal and some tokens to future Endurance Life events. Yes, I won!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the tokens, and thanks too for organising such a great event, but I think I shall retire unbeaten.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-11-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-coast-half-marathon</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-coast-half-marathon</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol Half Marathon, 2008</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations Gail!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2856888882/" title="gail-bristol-half-2008 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3226/2856888882_56bcdab564.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="gail-bristol-half-2008" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather couldn&amp;#8217;t have been better for today&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.bristolhalfmarathon.com"&gt;Bristol half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. The organisers seemed to have learned from previous years: a staggered start and a route which finished by meandering around the centre kept human traffic manageable and made a great event for spectators &amp;#8212; even if some of the runners must have found it hard to keep approaching the finish only to head out again, like aeroplanes circling in wait for a landing slot. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bristolhalfmarathon.com"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.bristolhalfmarathon.com/images/65.gif" alt="Route map"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cheered Gail on twice at Queens Square (at opposite corners), by the Hole in the Wall pub, crossing Redcliffe Bridge, and finally in the home straight.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-09-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2008</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2008</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bath half</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bathhalfmarathon.co.uk/site.aspx?i=re0&amp;amp;y=2007&amp;amp;g=0&amp;amp;t=Thomas+Guest"&gt;That&amp;#8217;s me!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/files/bathhalf.jpeg" alt="photo"/&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2007-03-25</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bath-half</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bath-half</link>
<category>Running</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
