<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Following the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As ever, I&amp;#8217;m watching the Tour de France &amp;#8212; or maybe I should say I&amp;#8217;m &lt;strong&gt;following&lt;/strong&gt; the tour, since I get much of my fix online, direct from &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/geraintthomas86" title="Geraint Thomas"&gt;riders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://inrng.com" title="The Inner Ring"&gt;commentators&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com" title="Cycling News"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I like the mountain stages. The scenery, the history, the combat. Winners and losers. The Pyrenees have disappointed with the favourites marking each other and no one prepared to make a sustained attack. We had this in 2010, and we still don&amp;#8217;t know who won that race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll on the Alps. As &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/inrng" title="The Inner Ring, on Twitter"&gt;@inrng&lt;/a&gt; points out, the &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage19" title="Inner Ring analysis of stage 19"&gt;Alpe d&amp;#8217;Huez stage is just under 110km&lt;/a&gt;, a sprint. Andy Schleck: don&amp;#8217;t look back!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2011/jul/09/team-sky-bradley-wiggins"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2011/7/9/1310205980831/Team-Skys-Bradley-Wiggins-007.jpg" alt="Bradley Wiggins, crashed out on stage 7"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrible to see Bradley Wiggins collapsed on the tarmac nursing a broken collarbone and knowing his race was over. What if? He&amp;#8217;d shed so much weight in preparation for the mountains there wasn&amp;#8217;t much left of him but what remained &amp;#8212; self-belief, humour, quality &amp;#8212; well, the climbers wouldn&amp;#8217;t have dropped him and he&amp;#8217;d have smashed them in the final time trial. There may yet be positives. Geraint Thomas is off the leash and riding with flair and abandon. He&amp;#8217;s no threat in the GC and could well grab a breakaway stage. Team Sky will build and regroup and throw everything at the Vuelta where Wiggo could yet become the first Briton to win a Grand Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the flatter stages have provided better racing. Cavendish has been a great winner. He also lost well, to Greipel, just the once. For the fourth consecutive year, he&amp;#8217;s fastest. Victory margins haven&amp;#8217;t been massive but to end up in green you have to run a marathon and a sprint, repeatedly. Is all about conserving energy. He can do it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Liggett and Paul Sherwen are putting in a solid performance. Ned Boulting too. Chris Boardman sounds dull, especially when voicing the sponsors&amp;#8217; messages which bookend the ad breaks:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve often wondered, why do they have second and third place on the podium? &amp;#8230; Yellow isn&amp;#8217;t a colour, it&amp;#8217;s a state of mind &amp;#8230; When my team had to lift me off my bike at the end of a stage, I knew I&amp;#8217;d done enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take (some of) it back about Chris Boardman: his analysis of &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage16"&gt;stage 16&lt;/a&gt;, the one which finished with a treacherous descent into Gap, was spot on. There&amp;#8217;s Andy Schleck moaning people don&amp;#8217;t want to see a race won downhill, yet he hasn&amp;#8217;t raced uphill either, not really. Or as CB described it: throwing the toys out of his pram.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour</link>
<category>Schleck</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 15, fear and respect</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees.html"&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about the failures and disappointments which made the opening week of this year&amp;#8217;s tour so compelling, and complained that the action had dropped when it should have peaked, in the mountains. Having shaken off the field, Contador and Schleck seemed unable to get to grips with each other. That all changed on stage 15, though again failure and disappointment underpinned the racing. Schleck sprang away from the elite climbers on the Port de Bal&amp;egrave;s, with Contador in hot pursuit. Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain came off but the momentum of his attack continued &amp;#8212; now carried by Contador and a few other elite riders.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve already seen Schleck doesn&amp;#8217;t have the team support Contador does; but he looked cruelly exposed on that mountain road, struggling to re-fit his chain. It took a couple of goes. He had to fend off a motorbike. He needed help from a couple of spectators to shove him back on course. By then, the leader on the road was Contador.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last we were treated to the sight of Schleck racing uphill. He tore up the road. He nearly caught Contador, but the Spaniard was lucky to be in the perfect group for a super-fast descent. At the end of that descent, the end of the stage, Contador had the yellow jersey.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleck was furious. He &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; furious. I think he&amp;#8217;s also wiped out, physically and emotionally. Anger fuelled his final climb up the Bal&amp;egrave;s but a tankful of anger won&amp;#8217;t get take over the Tourmalet. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview afterwards Contador was asked if he was afraid of Schleck. Fear? No, he said. Respect, yes. Contador lost a lot of respect for attacking when the race leader suffered a mechanical failure. Maybe even self-respect. He was jeered on the podium. He &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/news/contador-defends-his-attack-on-the-bales"&gt;toughed it out with the press&lt;/a&gt;, claiming he hadn&amp;#8217;t known about Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain falling off. Later on, from his hotel room, he posted a public apology on &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XdOJLuePexs"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain hadn&amp;#8217;t come off? I think Contador would have caught him. Schleck was already looking back to see who was where. He needed to face forwards and give it everything. I also thought Contador would attack on the final Pyrenean stage. He&amp;#8217;s been holding something back. I thought that he was too classy to accept winning the Tour by beating the clock in a time trial. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m not so sure he would have attacked, when defence and a decent time-trial would have sufficed. He will attack, if only to regain some respect. Sadly, I doubt Schleck has enough left.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect</link>
<category>Schleck</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 14, Pyrenees</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The first week of the Tour is normally a prelude to the real action &amp;#8212; someone unexpected wears yellow, sprinters stretch their legs, commentators and journalists clock up a few words, everyone looks forward to the real race. This year has seen a first week like no other. Looking back, amazingly, it&amp;#8217;s the failures and disappointments which stand out:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     Cav&amp;#8217;s failure to contest the opening sprints
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Armstrong&amp;#8217;s poor luck and subsequent inability to follow the leaders (and now look how far he has fallen!)
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Frank Schleck&amp;#8217;s broken shoulder, meaning he won&amp;#8217;t be there for his brother
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     yellow jersey Cancellara cancelling the sprint finish at the end of stage 2. How could he do that?
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on. If this opening week offered so much drama, what would we get when the route hit the mountains?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story unfolds. Unimaginably, Andy Schleck beat Contador in the first Alpine stage, and in the next stage the two of them &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers.html"&gt;toyed with each other&lt;/a&gt; briefly then teamed up to demolish any wannabes. Now we&amp;#8217;re in the Pyrenees, where the tour should be decided. Yesterday Contador and Schleck reached stalemate, again, like a joke with no punchline. Come on guys, this race deserves better!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On the subject of Armstrong, has he really cracked, or is he trying to drop so far down the GC that he&amp;#8217;ll be allowed a break-away stage win?)
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees</link>
<category>Schleck</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 9, dancing climbers</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The best climbers seem to dance up the slopes and today, on the Madeleine, two of the very best performed a wonderful pas de deux. Schleck flashed, Contador darted. The elastic between them pinged and sang. Might their rivals not take advantage of this energy-sapping flirtation? What rivals! A gruelling stage had already unravelled them. Contador and Schleck stopped playing and chased home. The race is between them now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If I attacked one more time I would have dropped myself,&amp;#8221; said Andy Schleck afterwards, but he looked as if he&amp;#8217;d just stepped out of the shower after a good night&amp;#8217;s sleep, rather than completed a mountain stage of the world&amp;#8217;s toughest race. Bring on the Pyrenees. Contador is too classy a rider to win the tour in a time trial. He&amp;#8217;s getting stronger. Watch him attack!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers</link>
<category>Schleck</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Week One</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, a rest day today, after a week of quite literal thrills and spills. Yesterday provided a fitting finale.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember last year, that final mountain stage on Mont Ventoux? It was meant to decide the general classification but by then Contador, already in yellow, had enough of a lead to ride defensively and cover the attacks. Andy Schleck couldn&amp;#8217;t shake him off. The stage was effectively neutralised. Yesterday, on the first Alpine stage, it looked like Schleck hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped at the summit of Ventoux at all. There he was, still poised on Contador&amp;#8217;s shoulder, a fresh-faced skinny executioner kitted out in white. This time Contador didn&amp;#8217;t look so clever. Schleck may not have taken much time out of his rival but he beat him convincingly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/races/97th-tour-de-france-gt/stage-8/results"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com//2010/07/11/2/bettiniphoto_0056537_1_full_600.jpg" alt="Schleck the skinny executioner"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</link>
<category>Schleck</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
