<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Cardiff Half, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Michael&amp;#8217;s Tom Tom guided us from the M4 to Grangetown Station. We parked alongside the Taff. Michael ate a banana and changed into his Swansea City shorts, which he thought appropriate since the route would be passing &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=85440788632" title="Cardiff FC's stadium looks like legoland!!!"&gt;Legoland&lt;/a&gt;. We made fall-back plans where to meet after then set off on foot, falling into line with the gathering crowds heading the same way. Ahead rose the metallic curve of the national arts centre, gleaming in the sunlight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisbewick/2530299841/" title="Wales Millenium Centre by Chris Bewick, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3082/2530299841_d018dd7422.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Wales Millenium Centre"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it say on the front? That&amp;#8217;s a classic pub quiz question.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the stones sing in silence. I don&amp;#8217;t know. Something like that. It&amp;#8217;s in Welsh and English.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; ?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on then, what does it say?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know either, Michael admitted. Now we were right there beneath the imposing lettering but didn&amp;#8217;t bother checking. The runners village was swarming with runners getting ready. We had to prepare.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plas Roald Dahl is built on a scale to accommodate 15000 runners and supporters &amp;#8212; excepting toilet facilities. Queues for the portaloos folded back on themselves. We shook hands and separated. With half an hour to go I stripped off and deposited my kit bag. I made my way to the start, down to the waterfront, left, past the Senedd, left again, then tried to find the right starting pen. My number was blue, meaning an expected finishing time between 1:20 and 1:30. The instructions from the PA alternated between English and Welsh, happily noting the sun had come out, there was no wind, the route was flat &amp;#8212; the event record could well be broken.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In amongst the packed athletes I discovered Mike Rimmer, Mark, Pippa and Michael (again). They were huddled close to the 1:30 pace-maker. Push up, Mike ordered, and I don&amp;#8217;t want to see you till the end of the race! I squeezed and twisted and wriggled a few metres forward then gave up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a welcome message from the mayor we were off, shuffling, walking, striding, jogging, running. After &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html" title="Bristol half marathon, 2011, when I got my pace all wrong"&gt;Bristol&lt;/a&gt;, I took it easy to begin with, settling into the race rather than wasting energy trying to weave through the pack. Soon the roads broadened, proper city avenues and boulevards, and I could run my own pace.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro-cyclist David Millar recently tweeted about his specialism, time-trialling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;TT&amp;#8217;s are weird. Imagine the best long-distance runners being set off at 1min intervals to TT 20km. Be considered mad. Cycling = Madness. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125523908874084353"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A TT generally involves the athlete emptying their tank completely in order to post the fastest time they are physically capable of. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125528302248136704"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A mass-start race involves tactics and economising of effort in order to cross the finish-line first. Winner often the freshest at the end. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/millarmind/status/125529177037348864"&gt;@millarmind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting, as far as it goes &amp;#8212; but in a regular bike race tactics and positioning are paramount and in athletics a strong athlete can run off the front. For me, the half marathon is a time trial. I&amp;#8217;m racing against the clock and emptying the tank. I look for the mile markers and check my time as I pass them. A 6:10 pace would bring me in at around 1 hour and 21 minutes, just under.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miles 8 and 9, the route heads in then out on the same arterial road, doubling back at a spectator-packed roundabout. It gives you a chance to watch faster runners, some really fast runners &amp;#8212; and to appreciate the scale of the event. Go on Ifan! I shouted. His head stayed down, he was working hard. He&amp;#8217;d heard me. My legs still felt good. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At mile 10 there&amp;#8217;s a climb. It&amp;#8217;s not so steep but it&amp;#8217;s long enough and it comes at just the wrong stage of the race. I&amp;#8217;d slipped a few seconds. The arithmetic was getting harder. Dig in!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gordonplant/2705863581/" title="Cardiff Bay by gordonplant, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3260/2705863581_e4ce2d5006.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Cardiff Bay"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the final stretch, along the Cardiff Bay barrage. You&amp;#8217;re exposed to the wind but today there wasn&amp;#8217;t any, just a fabulous approach to the capital, towards the Norwegian Church, the Assembly, the &lt;a href="http://images.google.com/search?tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=cardiff+armadillo"&gt;Armadillo&lt;/a&gt;. Those efforts along the Avon towpath, the interval sessions on Oxwich beach &amp;#8212; now they make sense: you know how it feels to run at tempo when legs are burning and lungs are heaving. I was going to do it!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6329991144/" title="1:21:31.07 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6053/6329991144_2e8410288b.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:21:31.07"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:21:31:07 it said on my watch. My official chip time, received in a text message an hour or so later, was 1:21:30, a personal best by almost half a minute. I was wiped out but not hurting, not like &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html" title="Bristol half marathon, 2011, when I got my pace all wrong"&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d finished 110th.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6330006162/" title="Cardiff half marathon 2011 race results for Thomas Guest by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6117/6330006162_8acba32865.jpg" width="500" height="321" alt="Cardiff half marathon 2011 race results for Thomas Guest"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gordonplant/" title="gordonplant's photostream, on flickr"&gt;gordonplant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chrisbewick"&gt;Chris Bewick&lt;/a&gt; for allowing me to use their fine photos of Cardiff Bay and the Millenium Centre in this article.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-10-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cardiff-half-2011.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cardiff-half-2011.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bristol Half Marathon, 2011</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The half marathon I enjoyed most was the first one I ran, the Bath half, back in &amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not even sure, 12 years ago? I didn&amp;#8217;t know if I&amp;#8217;d be able to finish because I hadn&amp;#8217;t run the distance in training, so I started slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the race progressed I realised I &lt;strong&gt;would&lt;/strong&gt; finish, no problem, and I remember overtaking people in the second loop and sprinting the last stretch along Great Pulteney Street, crossing the line with a time of 1:42:15. Oh, I felt just great!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I&amp;#8217;ve run a few more half marathons and at each one I&amp;#8217;ve gone faster. At first I hacked chunks from my personal best but as time went on I was reduced to chipping away smaller gains. In 2003 I went below an hour and a half at Bristol, beating Steve Cram. In 2006 I returned to Bath and clocked &lt;a href="bath_half_2006.pdf"&gt;1:23:14&lt;/a&gt;. Wow! I didn&amp;#8217;t think I could better that but running the same event in 2007 I got down to 1:21:58 &amp;#8212; which meant running the first 9 miles at a speed of 6 minutes and 15 seconds per mile and then running the final 4 miles at the same speed, even though at every step every bit of me wanted it to end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day I retired from half marathons. I couldn&amp;#8217;t go any faster and I couldn&amp;#8217;t face up to going any slower and I hurt and I had had enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept running though. Cross country is my favourite, all weather, all terrain. I started going out with a group close to where I live, on Gower. Sand dunes, wooded tracks, marshland. Cefn Bryn from all faces. I joined a club in Bristol, where I work, threading through the alleyways and parkland of North Bristol. Then I hooked up with some friends for training runs on Wednesday lunchtimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/gavinedmonds/5830288813/" title="GBR_1140 by Gavin Edmonds, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5152/5830288813_bf2b13d048_z.jpg" width="426" height="640" alt="GBR_1140"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, 6 March 2011, and friends from all of these groups were running the Bath half marathon. The weather was good. I was in fine form. As I said in an email to Andy:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m thinking my build-up for the Bath half has been pretty much perfect, except for my failure to enter, that is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andy went on to finish the race in a time of 1:21:51 &amp;#8212; fully half a second a mile faster than I&amp;#8217;d ever run. That did it! Later that week I signed up for the Bristol half marathon, to be run on September 11th 2011.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years since I&amp;#8217;ve been away, the Bristol half has become a huge event. I&amp;#8217;d been assigned a white number which meant I&amp;#8217;d be starting in the first section of the first wave. It still took me over 30 seconds to pass beneath the start line and I spent the first couple of miles dodging joggers with ipods and sharp elbowed veterans. Beneath the suspension bridge the race stretched out. I galloped along the portway. Soon after doubling back at Shirehampton I pulled alongside someone I knew.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Is that Neil?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Tom, How&amp;#8217;s it going?&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Too damn fast. I&amp;#8217;m going too fast.&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Nah, you&amp;#8217;re fine!&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shook my head. I &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt; going too fast but I couldn&amp;#8217;t slow down. Even though I was hurting and hadn&amp;#8217;t even gone halfway I let momentum take me past Neil and on to Spike Island. Already I wanted it over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route came back to the centre of town then cruelly swerved out again on an unwelcome tour of the sights. Great for spectators. Cobbles. Ramps. &lt;a href="http://www.seenoevilbristol.co.uk/"&gt;Grafitti&lt;/a&gt;. I was being overtaken. Falling away. Neil came smoothly past.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well done mate,&amp;#8221; I muttered.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;400m to go. At least I had space around me. Noone passed me in the final straight.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pressed the button on my stop watch and collapsed, wiped out. I hurt and I knew I was going to hurt more tomorrow and the day after. There was Neil. I eased up on to my feet, started moving, slowly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6137800028/" title="1:22:14.94 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6076/6137800028_a469bae0a1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="1:22:14.94"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:22:14 my watch said.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the event has grown bigger they&amp;#8217;ve figured out how to organise it. You aren&amp;#8217;t allowed to pile-up round the finish line snatching goodie bags and hugging loved ones. They keep the exhausted, elated runners moving past a succession of hand-outs: space blanket, water, medal, banana, T-shirt, energy drink, leaflet, bag &amp;#8230; and after this personal awards ceremony you emerge light-headed into the sunshine in millenium square.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil ran 1:22:06, comfortably. For him, this was a training run: he&amp;#8217;s looking for a fast time in Stroud. My official time, &lt;a href="http://www.runbristol.com/SearchResults.aspx"&gt;online now&lt;/a&gt;, is 1:22:15. That&amp;#8217;s over a second a mile slower than I&amp;#8217;ve run before. I give in.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-09-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bristol-half-marathon-2011.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Two and a bit pencils later</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/sketching-skeletons-at-bristol-museum.html" title="Sketching skeletons at Bristol Museum"&gt;Six months ago I decided&lt;/a&gt; to visit Bristol Museum on Wednesday evenings and draw interesting things until I got to the end of my sketchbook. Two and a half pencils and 51 pictures later, I&amp;#8217;m done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/5474708308/" title="Two and a bit pencils later by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5059/5474708308_1297ba0e07.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Two and a bit pencils later" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ve made any great progress as an artist but I&amp;#8217;m happy at least to get my eye back in. Besides, in my day job, as a computer programmer, it&amp;#8217;s hard to truly finish anything, so it&amp;#8217;s good to &amp;#8212; well &amp;#8212; finish something.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="400" height="300"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2F&amp;set_id=72157624789595765&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=71649"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=71649" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157624789595765%2F&amp;set_id=72157624789595765&amp;jump_to=" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My appreciation of the museum has grown. I&amp;#8217;ve had time to read labels and walk through those quiet upper rooms filled with silverware and crockery. I&amp;#8217;ve noticed small details in familiar paintings. I can point out the scars in the stonework caused by war-time bomb damage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late opening on Wednesdays may be a recent idea but it&amp;#8217;s proved a rapid success. When I first started coming it seemed like I had the place to myself. Every so often a gallery attendant would drift by, but that was it. Now, though, I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who turns up to sketch, and on most Wednesdays it seems there&amp;#8217;s an event going on: &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/plinth-project-by-rob.html"&gt;statues have been unveiled&lt;/a&gt;, presentations made, films shown; the year of the rabbit kicked off; exhibitions have changed; and one evening the main hall was packed with dancing brownies and balloon-filled bin-liners were emptied on them from the first floor gallery. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-02-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/two-and-a-bit-pencils-later.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/two-and-a-bit-pencils-later.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sketching skeletons at Bristol Museum</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Skeletons have interesting lines, corners and shadows, which is why I like drawing them. Here&amp;#8217;s a sketch of the Moa skeleton at Bristol museum, which you&amp;#8217;ll find just around the corner from the &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/england/7440296.stm"&gt;spiky plant-eating scelidosaurus&lt;/a&gt; and opposite the camarasaurus leg. (Courtesy of the BBC, here&amp;#8217;s a &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/bristol/content/panoramas/museum3_360.shtml"&gt;panorama&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4929241864/" title="Moa skeleton at Bristol museum by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4137/4929241864_17164a1ce5_z.jpg" width="454" height="640" alt="Moa skeleton at Bristol museum" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, no wings! Moas are &amp;#8212; were &amp;#8212; wingless, unlike other &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ratite"&gt;ratites&lt;/a&gt;, other birds even, but what really impressed me about this specimen were its powerful legs and hips, and its chunky feet &amp;#8212; which unfortunately stretched down below the bottom of my sketch book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attendant told me I was lucky, an hour ago the gallery was full of noisy kids, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to sit there and draw. I nodded. Long day? I thought. Where better for kids to go on a wet day at the end of the summer holidays? A few weeks ago I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to sit there and draw either, not after 5pm. Late opening on Wednesdays is a &lt;a href="http://www.bristol.gov.uk/ccm/content/press-releases/2010/jul/late-night-opening-at-city-museum---art-gallery.en"&gt;recent innovation&lt;/a&gt;. And a year ago I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to get into the museum without &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/banksy-vs-bristol-museum.html"&gt;queuing for three hours first&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I intend to fill my new sketch book, get my eye back in. Wednesdays are good. I&amp;#8217;ve started now. Here&amp;#8217;s a line drawing of The Wrestler, by Henri Gaudier-Brzeska, which reminds me of &lt;a href="http://www.kettlesyard.co.uk"&gt;Kettle&amp;#8217;s Yard&lt;/a&gt;. Wonderful sculpture, poor picture. I&amp;#8217;m working on it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4927073230/" title="The Wrestler, Henri Gaudier-Brzeska by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4120/4927073230_2a071fa6f2_b.jpg" width="510" height="766" alt="The Wrestler, Henri Gaudier-Brzeska" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-08-25</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/sketching-skeletons-at-bristol-museum.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/sketching-skeletons-at-bristol-museum.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mumbles Triathlon 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching today&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.mumblestri.com/"&gt;Mumbles triathlon&lt;/a&gt;. Conditions were perfect: bright and warm but, at 07:00 in the morning, not yet too hot. No wind, no waves. Swansea bay looked at its best. I knew at least three people taking part but had trouble identifying them. Everyone looks much the same in a wetsuit and swimming hat. I also spotted a cyclist I see on the train. The leading swimmer went like a torpedo. He also swam the triangular route directly, cutting between a couple of boats moored offshore. Everyone else followed a curving line back to the slipway. Then it all got a bit confusing, because the event combined a short and long sprint, and I couldn&amp;#8217;t tell who was in which event.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4735356462/" title="Waiting for the off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4093/4735356462_cca0bf5db5_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Waiting for the off"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Triathlon - not for spectators</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/wp-content/gallery/2009-activity-wales-gower-peninsula-triathlon/mje15467.jpg" alt="Gower Triathon"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard.html"&gt;been to see&lt;/a&gt; a triathlon. Certainly the event impressed me. Equally it left me in no hurry to participate. The combination of three disciplines and punishing weather conditions exposed endurance athletes as stubborn masochists. Why would anyone do that to themselves? As Richard&amp;#8217;s acerbic blog entry &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info/2009/08/triathlon-bbc-tv/" title="Triathlon &amp;amp;mdash; More Boring on TV than Handball?"&gt;Triathlon &amp;#8212; more boring on TV than Handball?&lt;/a&gt; points out, a triathlon boils down to averages and costume changes. However, as &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info/2009/08/triathlon-bbc-tv/comment-page-1/#comment-1095"&gt;lima&lt;/a&gt; comments:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;you people are so damn stupid. have any of you ever done a triathlon???? I doubt! So please shut the f&amp;#8230; up!!!!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/"&gt;Gower Triathlon&lt;/a&gt; goes right past my house. It&amp;#8217;s a popular event, so popular, in fact, that when Mike told me about it they&amp;#8217;d already sold out; but when I checked the &lt;a href="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; I found they&amp;#8217;d just allocated 100 more places. I took that as a sign and signed up. Only a month to go now. I can cycle and run, and I reckon I can cycle and then run. It&amp;#8217;s the swimming and transitions which scare me. I&amp;#8217;m off to watch the &lt;a href="http://www.mumblestri.com/"&gt;Mumbles triathlon&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow morning and see how it&amp;#8217;s done.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-25</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-harder.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-harder.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chris Hutt, cycling activist, mischievous plumber</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terrible news. Chris Hutt has been found dead at his home &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/chrishutt"&gt;@chrishutt&lt;/a&gt;. Bristol and cycling has lost such a special man.
   &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/CllrJonRogers/status/10814984695"&gt;@CllrJonRogers&lt;/a&gt;, 1:57 AM Mar 21st
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terrible news indeed. I&amp;#8217;m shocked and saddened.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never met Chris myself, but I subscribe to his &lt;a href="http://greenbristolblog.blogspot.com/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and follow him on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/chrishutt"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#8217;ve exchanged emails and tweets.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris styled himself as a &amp;#8220;grumpy old man about town&amp;#8221;, but in reality he contributed much more than moaning. At the start of the year, when the city was gripped by winter, when others complained about the council&amp;#8217;s failure to clear the pavements of ice, he and the indomitable Jon Rogers were out &lt;a href="http://greenbristolblog.blogspot.com/2010/01/ice-man-cometh.html"&gt;shovelling&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bristol-Bath cycle path, the foundation of Sustrans, and ultimately the nomination of Bristol 2010 as Britain&amp;#8217;s first cycling city &amp;#8212; he had a part in all these things, and we will remember him with thanks for this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;#8217;t realise is that Chris Hutt was also:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; the best plumber in the west. He plumbed in the four fountains on the [Bristol-Bath cycle] route and when the fountain on Castle Green was first installed he plumbed it so red wine came out of one side and orange out of another.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://www.kingswoodpeople.co.uk/news/Tributes-Bristol-cycling-campaigner-dead-home/article-1931446-detail/article.html"&gt;John Grimshaw&lt;/a&gt;, Sustrans.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a photo of that fountain. Isobel and Alex are pretending to be the fish which decorate the frieze on its sides.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/209291883/" title="2005 014 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/86/209291883_1a44d8a556.jpg" width="500" height="374" alt="2005 014" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-03-21</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/chris-hutt.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/chris-hutt.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mountain Bikes going downhill</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://davesbikeblog.squarespace.com/blog/2010/3/8/evolution-the-mountain-bike.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://davesbikeblog.squarespace.com/storage/ritchey_mountain_bike-number-1_02.jpg" alt="Ritchey Mountain bike"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In yet another great blog post, Dave Moulton discusses the &lt;a href="http://davesbikeblog.squarespace.com/blog/2010/3/8/evolution-the-mountain-bike.html"&gt;evolution of the mountain bike&lt;/a&gt;. He starts by setting the scene:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a bike boom in the mid 1970s in America, this was part of the fitness movement. European road bikes, which were for the most part fully equipped racing bikes, were being imported into the US.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sadly many of these bikes were barely used. No wonder so many classic road bikes from this period end up on ebay in mint condition. As Dave Moulton says:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The average American is keen to try different sports, but only a few will dedicate the time and effort to reach any level of expertise. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s true. A thoroughbred road bike is an unforgiving machine &amp;#8212; just &lt;em&gt;looking&lt;/em&gt; at the saddle is enough to make a grown man wince. Add skinny tyres, handlebars you need to bend over to reach, gears calibrated for hardened professionals, and you have a machine all too likely to stay in storage. You need to be fit and confident to enjoy riding a road bike.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You even more confidence to ride off-road, though. You&amp;#8217;ll need to be fitter, too. Cefn Bryn, at the back of my house, is popular with mountain bikers. The gradients are steep. The paths are muddy, edged with gorse, and strewn with gritty nuggets of bryn stone: tough on foot, treacherous on wheels.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why ever did the mountain bike catch on?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Moulton:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My take on why the Mountain Bike took off when it did. There was a whole generation of young adults who had grown up in the 1970s with BMX bikes; they remembered how they used to perform jumps and stunts. The MTB was possibly seen as an adult version of a BMX.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe. I think he&amp;#8217;s right to associate the mountain bike&amp;#8217;s acceptance with fun and leisure, rather than exercise. But it&amp;#8217;s the next paragraph which rings true with me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the general public too, here was a bike that was easier to ride than a road bike, with its upright position and fat tires.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right! And let&amp;#8217;s not forget decent brakes. Those low gears, designed for use on hills, make zipping across town a snip. Urban riding is about starting, stopping, negotiating obstacles. A mountain bike performs well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought my first mountain bike, a Specialized Rockhopper, in Sydney, where I worked for three months as a bike courier. It did the job admirably and performed equally well in the same role in Melbourne. It wasn&amp;#8217;t the fastest machine to take on the great &lt;a href="http://www.bv.com.au/great-rides/90962/" title="The 2010 Victorian bike ride route. I took part in the 1989 ride"&gt;Victorian bike ride&lt;/a&gt;, but we never went further than 100km in a day. It was a reliable, solid bike for touring the Tasmanian hills.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rockhopper came back back with me to England. I ended up in Cambridge, one of the few British cities where bikes are truly popular for getting about, where it served me well until someone stole it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years later, in Bristol, I acquired another mountain bike. I can&amp;#8217;t remember what brand. I got it second hand from a colleague who was trading up to a full-suspension model: I just wanted something sturdy enough to attach a child seat. If you&amp;#8217;re carrying a child, you want comfort and safety.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is: I never used my mountain bikes off-road. A classically-styled mountain bike is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the 2 wheel equivalent of the ridiculous, grid-locked  4 wheel drive. Their design is sturdy, versatile, and well-suited to general road use. Hence their enduring popularity. My children&amp;#8217;s bikes look like mountain bikes. The bargain bikes you pick up in supermarkets look like mountain bikes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/raleigh-diva.jpg" alt="Raleigh Diva"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, what a mountain bike looks like has changed. In an effort to persuade people to upgrade, manufacturers keep adding new features. Isobel&amp;#8217;s bike has suspension: that&amp;#8217;s what kids&amp;#8217; bikes come with now (and let&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophasis#Paralipsis" title="Oops, I just did mention it"&gt;not mention&lt;/a&gt; the hand bag). Combine this spongy suspension with a heavy steel frame and knobbly tyres, and you&amp;#8217;ve got a clumsy, energy-sapping machine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/apollo-fs26-mtb.png" alt="Full suspension MTB"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m convinced the current trend for &lt;a href="http://bristolalleycats.net/"&gt;fixed wheel bikes&lt;/a&gt; is a reaction against the over-engineering of the urban mountain bike. Some off-road features have no place in a city. A fixie is simple, nimble, direct. A fixie can be fast, too. It has direct power transmission and few moving parts. The &lt;a href="http://www.chrishoy.com/"&gt;fastest cyclist on the planet&lt;/a&gt; rides a fixed wheel.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/odeum/4151052440"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2625/4151052440_f67f1cea28.jpg" alt="ride your bike in the rain, Brenton Salo, Flickr"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fixie won&amp;#8217;t catch on like the mountain bike, though. Oh, I&amp;#8217;m sure manufacturers are delighted to cash in on these stripped-down machines; they&amp;#8217;ll hold on to the surplus cogs, derailleurs and shifters until people realise they need them. Without gears, cycling is too much work, especially for a beginner. Pushing a bike up a hill is neither cool nor fun.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cannondale.com/gbr/eng/Products/Bikes/Recreation-Urban/Bad-Boy/Bad-Boy/Details/1477-0BRD7-Bad-Boy-700"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/bad-boy-700.jpg" alt="Bad Boy 700"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reckon Jonny has the right idea. His matt black &lt;a href="http://www.cannondale.com/gbr/eng/Products/Bikes/Recreation-Urban/Bad-Boy/Bad-Boy/Details/1477-0BRD7-Bad-Boy-700" title="Bad boy 700, 2010 model. Jonny's rides the 2009 model, I think"&gt;Cannondale Bad Boy 700&lt;/a&gt; comes within a whisker of being camp (you &lt;em&gt;Bad boy!&lt;/em&gt; you), but it&amp;#8217;s just about perfect for urban use: no suspension, sealed bearings, disc brakes, slick tyres. Its stealth finish won&amp;#8217;t ever look dirty. And look at the range of gears!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone can afford a Cannondale, though. If manufacturers truly want to benefit from the fixie they should cross it with the mountain bike. Then we&amp;#8217;d have something simple, safe, accessible. Something cool enough to be seen out with. Something so much fun to ride it won&amp;#8217;t get left in the shed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.brentonsalo.com/"&gt;Brenton Salo&lt;/a&gt; for kindly allowing me to use his cycling in the rain &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/odeum/4151052440" title="ride your bike in the rain, Brenton Salo, Flickr"&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-03-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mountain-bikes-going-downhill.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/mountain-bikes-going-downhill.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Art attack, Shark attack!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4115721350/" title="happy birthday closed by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2534/4115721350_4d71e4ccc1_o.png" width="371" height="529" alt="happy birthday closed" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fishing in a boat. What could be more peaceful?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on, lift the flap&amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4114904591/" title="happy birthday open by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2686/4114904591_f4f8259fb5_o.png" width="470" height="491" alt="happy birthday open" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrggh! Shark.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the birthday card, Alex.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-11-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/art-attack-shark-attack.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/art-attack-shark-attack.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tour of Britain 2009</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I took my bike to &lt;a href="http://www.fredbakercycles.co.uk/"&gt;Fred Baker cycles&lt;/a&gt; to investigate a transmission problem &amp;#8212; the freehub sometimes failed to latch, especially after freewheeling. It turned out the whole wheel needed changing. They had some basic quality spares in the shop but I decided to order a decent replacement. The bike was still usable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening I watched the Tour of Britain highlights &lt;a href="http://www.itv.com/cycling"&gt;programme on ITV4&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="http://www.tourofbritain.co.uk/_ns_race/stage5_route.asp"&gt;Stage 5&lt;/a&gt; route was a slog through the potteries. I can&amp;#8217;t put my finger on why exactly, but the event seemed low-key: minor roads, poor surfaces, huddles of school kids clutching flimsy flags. Maybe the over-enthusiastic commentary put me off: those slopes weren&amp;#8217;t mountains, hardly hills even, and three spectators doesn&amp;#8217;t make a crowd. I missed the slick pazazz of the well rehearsed Tour de France coverage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, I decided to check out the event for real. After all, the statistics showed the riders were going every bit as fast as any stage in a proper tour, and &lt;a href="http://www.southwesttourofbritain.co.uk/"&gt;Stage 6 would be starting in Frome&lt;/a&gt;, not 30 miles away.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3931297430/" title="Road closure by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3429/3931297430_0ce98fb80e_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="Road closure" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning was a glorious one for cycling. The bike seemed fine. I avoided freewheeling and got to Frome before 9. The race was to start from Market Yard Car Park. I bought a bacon roll and a coffee, snaffled some energy bar samples, listened to the live event radio, wandered around the town centre. They&amp;#8217;d held a &lt;a href="http://www.southwesttourofbritain.co.uk/info-for-residents-businesses/road-closures/"&gt;Cobble Wobble&lt;/a&gt; race up Catherine Hill the evening before, and the shop windows along the street had cycle-themed displays. At about 9:30 a posse of police motorbike riders rolled up. A good day to commit a crime, someone said. Soon after came the team cars, glossy road bikes strapped to their roofs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3931299072/" title="Police bikes by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2421/3931299072_cecc59c28e.jpg" width="382" height="500" alt="Police bikes" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having watched a few riders sign in I decided to head out of town. I wanted to see the peleton at full speed, not rolling out of a car park. I was surprised to be allowed to use the actual stage route less than half an hour before the race was due to start. As I climbed the hill out of town I noticed a crowd of pupils standing in front of their school at the side of the road. They wore bright yellow reflective vests. As I passed, out of the saddle and stamping hard on the pedals, they cheered and waved their flags.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3931302098/" title="Here they come! by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2673/3931302098_809d25d166.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Here they come!" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few miles down the road I found a good place to stop. For the next 20 minutes police riders flashed by. It seemed more like a motorbike race than a bicycle race. All of a sudden the peleton arrived, at speed. Seconds later, they were gone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my way back, just before Pensford, my freehub abruptly and finally stopped working. I now had a bike suitable for downhill only. I got a taxi back into Bristol. Later that evening I watched the TV coverage. I saw Somerset and Devon bathed in sunshine, a high-speed breakaway topping Exmoor, pegged back by a ruthless peleton alongside the Torridge estuary, a last gasp sprint. Colour me convinced.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-09-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2009.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2009.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>On the move</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;#8217;s finally happening: today, we move out of our wonderful home on Cobourg Road, BS6 5HU. Actually, Gail left with Isobel and Alex yesterday, ready for their first day of the new term today. We&amp;#8217;re off to the Gower, South Wales, which has been Gail&amp;#8217;s dream destination for a long while. The schools and beaches are better. I shall be keeping my job in Bristol, which I enjoy &amp;#8212; and I still like Bristol too. I&amp;#8217;ll be working in the Bristol office for three days a week and from home the other two days. Where will home be? Initially Uplands, Swansea, camping in a large room at my brother&amp;#8217;s house. Eventually Reynoldston, assuming our purchase goes through. Change is good. Wish us luck!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-09-02</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/on-the-move.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/on-the-move.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Porlock Hill on a bicycle</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The road signs warn you early about Porlock Hill.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3789309966/" title="Early warning by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2642/3789309966_f8b3eb8720.jpg" width="390" height="500" alt="Early warning" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you snub the alternative route and reach the base of the hill you&amp;#8217;ll be offered the option of the scenic woodland Toll Road.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3789305024/" title="Decisions by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2537/3789305024_d59fcc0ff7.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Decisions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s true, the air here is acrid with the smell of burned out brakes and clutches &amp;#8212; maybe that&amp;#8217;s why the house is for sale &amp;#8212; and you&amp;#8217;ll see a line of cars parked hard against roadside while pale-faced drivers recover.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.activeexmoor.com/site/cycling/exmoor-cycle-route/map"&gt;Exmoor cycle route&lt;/a&gt;, signed in the picture, follows the toll road too. That&amp;#8217;ll be a pound please!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went straight up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The road climbs approximately 400 m (1,300 ft) in less than 2 miles (3.2 km) up onto Exmoor: a very steep hill with gradients of up to 1 in 4 and hairpin bends. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A39_road#Porlock_Hill"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My normal tactic when cycling uphill is not to use the lowest gear: keep it in reserve in case the going gets &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; tough. Porlock Hill blew that strategy apart on the first switchback. For the rest of the climb I was in bottom gear, out of the pedals, sweating and yawing like a porpoise
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I reached the top of the steep bit my legs were jelly. The road continued to climb, albeit more gently, for some way. A few miles on, the A39 from Lynmouth to Lynton is equally steep, but for a mercifully short section.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the return journey this morning from Combe Martin to Taunton, taking the B3558 across the top of Exmoor. It&amp;#8217;s a rolling route but nowhere near as severe as the coast road. This time my enemy was filthy weather. It felt like riding through a sodden sponge. Rain bounced up from the road and the wind shook great gobs of water from the trees as I passed beneath. Does Alberto Contador ever stop to wring out his socks, I wondered?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     Soaking in Simonsbath.
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Drenched at Exford.
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Wet through by Wheddon Cross.
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bag of &lt;a href="http://www.rolysfudge.co.uk/"&gt;Roly&amp;#8217;s lemon and stem ginger fudge&lt;/a&gt; dispelled the gloom and sped me on my way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rolysfudge.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.rolysfudge.co.uk/images/serve.jpg" alt="Roly's fudge"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-08-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/porlock-hill-on-a-bicycle.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cycle parking at work</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The cycle parking where I work is both secure and free so I suppose I shouldn&amp;#8217;t grumble &amp;#8230; but, hey, this is the interweb and one of the things which bugs me every single working day is my ongoing struggle with the wall-mounted cycle racks. Parking my bike involves me balancing on one leg and holding the bike vertically in place with the thigh of my other leg while fastening the lock at the wall with both hands. To make things harder the kitchen staff at la Tasca (don&amp;#8217;t go there!) spilled a vat of crusty, slimy, rank cooking fat on the floor, and, several weeks on, it&amp;#8217;s obvious they aren&amp;#8217;t bothered about clearing it up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3553979581/" title="Cycle parking by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3618/3553979581_d55e7c3299.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Cycle parking" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at this though! Elsewhere in the car park, at no little expense, one of the building tenants has rented a car parking space and turned it into a superior level-access cycle park.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3553980357/" title="Cycle parking by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3579/3553980357_1a0d777885.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Cycle parking" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-05-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cycle-parking-at-work.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cycle-parking-at-work.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Review: Becoming Drusilla</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/becoming-drusilla.jpg" alt="Becoming Drusilla cover"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s hard for me to be objective about &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;Becoming Drusilla&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info" title="Richard Beard's home page"&gt;friend of mine&lt;/a&gt; wrote it and I&amp;#8217;ve met its subject, Dru, a few times &amp;#8212; though she spelled her name &amp;#8220;Drew&amp;#8221; then, short for Andrew, and very male she appeared too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book centres on a journey which starts in Bristol then heads out of Chepstow on foot along &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Offa%27s_Dyke"&gt;Offa&amp;#8217;s Dyke&lt;/a&gt;. As the two of them walk, Richard mulls over his relationship with Dru, past and present, and tries to work out how it all happened. Dru identifies wildlife and knows all the words to some arcane songs. They squabble over directions. Mid-way, they abandon the Dyke, instead heading for St Davids, Pembrokeshire.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a cracking book, if something of a conundrum for book-sellers. On which shelf do you put a travel book which is also a biography and indeed an autobiography, which covers gender issues with wit and intelligence? Oh, and it also includes some rather good haiku and illustrations. &lt;strong&gt;So pile it high near the front, then!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.com/"&gt;&lt;img style="float:left;" src="http://www.facebook.com/profile/pic.php?uid=AAAAAQAQW2Pbi8-IS-Gq5OCcRAGQQwAAAAkNWQzqa9aqZz9B1znkyFAp" alt="Dru Marland, self-portrait"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Becoming-Drusilla-Friends-Three-Genders/dp/0099507730"&gt;Becoming Drusilla&lt;/a&gt; has just been relaunched in paperback. Richard and Dru will be &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=85841341768" title="Becoming Drusilla, Bristol Launch. A Facebook group"&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt; from the book in the Green Room at the Tobacco Factory, Bristol, on Friday 8th May, 7:45 pm.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to meeting Dru again. It must be almost a decade since we last met in person. Now, of course, I&amp;#8217;ve read her biography. I&amp;#8217;m also her friend on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/people/Dru-Marland"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; which doesn&amp;#8217;t mean much since I barely use Facebook. She has a &lt;a href="http://dru-withoutamap.blogspot.com/"&gt;fine blog&lt;/a&gt; and her Flickr &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/belvedere/"&gt;photostream&lt;/a&gt; includes some beautiful photographs and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/belvedere/sets/72157594410663343/"&gt;illustrations&lt;/a&gt;. See you on Friday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: looks like Richard is unwell and won&amp;#8217;t be able to make it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-05-06</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-becoming-drusilla.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/review-becoming-drusilla.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shredded garden and cubed oak</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My favourite work in the &lt;a href="http://www.forestofdean-sculpture.org.uk/"&gt;Forest of Dean sculpture trail&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.forestofdean-sculpture.org.uk/sculptures/current/raw/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Raw&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, photographed here by &lt;a href="http://www.mattburns.co.uk/"&gt;Matt Burns&lt;/a&gt;, provides an affirmative answer to the question set by the artist:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Could you cube up a whole tree, trunk and branches from the largest size to the smallest one cut?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/floater81/3443221768/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3552/3443221768_ace4044e15_d.jpg" alt="Cubed Oak"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting cube has a side of about 2m, easy enough to climb up on. What&amp;#8217;s most impressive is the huge space around it &amp;#8212; the space occupied by a mature oak tree.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3476286193/" title="Shredderbox by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3556/3476286193_1d123065c0_s.jpg" width="75" height="75" alt="Shredderbox" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend we created our own sculpture, &amp;#8220;Shredded garden&amp;#8221;. With our neighbour&amp;#8217;s permission, we pushed his garden through a letter box. Here&amp;#8217;s the result. &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/sets/72157617288800804/"&gt;(Full story.)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3476285417/" title="What do you get if you put a garden through a shredder? by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3304/3476285417_9ffc867556_b.jpg" width="100%" alt="What do you get if you put a garden through a shredder?" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/shredded-garden-and-cubed-oak.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/shredded-garden-and-cubed-oak.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Clevedon pier &#215; 2</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite cycling &lt;a href="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps/ms?hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=113564543700840270791.000454691bcbd5be2f4c6&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=12"&gt;routes&lt;/a&gt; is the one Owen showed me. Head out of Bristol over the suspension bridge, on through Failand and Wraxall, then to Clevedon and back via Portishead. It&amp;#8217;s got a bit of everything: hills, flatlands, woods, seafront, views over the docks. If you&amp;#8217;ve got time, visit the sea front at Clevedon, or the Portishead marina. Here&amp;#8217;s a snap I took of Clevedon Pier just after 9 in the morning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3356001841/" title="Clevedon Pier"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3539/3356001841_331466daba_b.jpg" width="100%" alt="Clevedon Pier" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on in the afternoon &lt;a href="http://www.mattburns.co.uk/"&gt;Matt Burns&lt;/a&gt; took this wonderful shot. It almost makes me want to take up photography.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/floater81/3356995999" title="Clevedon Pier by Matt Burns"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3611/3356995999_02d1d1d630_b.jpg" width="100%" alt="Clevedon"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-03-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/clevedon-pier-times-2.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/clevedon-pier-times-2.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>I&#8217;m on twitter</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Having just posted a &lt;a href="http://wordaligned.org/articles/longest-common-subsequence"&gt;monster article&lt;/a&gt; on Word Aligned, I&amp;#8217;m trying out something smaller. I&amp;#8217;m &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/thomasguest"&gt;@thomasguest&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-03-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/im-on-twitter.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/im-on-twitter.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Frosty and friend</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/3255502980/" title="Frosty and friend by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3082/3255502980_13d268a2f1.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Frosty and friend" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-02-05</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/frosty-and-friend.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/frosty-and-friend.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Snowball fight at St Barnabas</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.st-barnabasprimary.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://www.st-barnabasprimary.co.uk/images/logo.gif" alt="St Barnabas primary school logo"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well done &lt;a href="http://www.st-barnabasprimary.co.uk"&gt;St Barnabas primary school&lt;/a&gt; for opening as usual today when so many other Bristol schools closed because of the snow. It&amp;#8217;s not that a day off school would have damaged my children&amp;#8217;s education, but rather that the school playground turned out to be the perfect venue for a snowball fight. Children, parents, teachers &amp;#8212; everyone who made it in, joined in; and we all learned something about each other.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-02-05</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/snowball-fight-at-st-barnabas.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/snowball-fight-at-st-barnabas.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The foxes return</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We wondered what had become of the foxes which used to visit our garden &amp;#8212; we hadn&amp;#8217;t seen them for a couple of months. This weekend, all became clear: they&amp;#8217;d been lying low to raise a family of four cubs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cubs haven&amp;#8217;t learned the meaning of caution yet. Here&amp;#8217;s one looking at me from the other end of a raised vegetable patch. I think that&amp;#8217;s a seed pod from an acacia tree in its mouth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/files/cub_raised_bed.jpg" width="100%" alt="fox cub at the other end of vegetable patch"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More fox photos &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/sets/72157600207441824/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2007-05-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-foxes-return.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-foxes-return.html</link>
<category>Self</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
