<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>New shoes and pedals</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/back-to-the-velodrome&quot;&gt;Last time I went to the velodrome&lt;/a&gt; I decided I needed proper cycle shoes &amp;#8212; ones which attach directly to the pedals, I mean. The fact that I&amp;#8217;m heading off to cycle in the Alps in a couple of weeks gave me extra motivation to invest in a pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out it is isn&amp;#8217;t quite as easy as going into a shop and spending some money. You need to work out what &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bicycle_pedal&quot;&gt;exactly you want to buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A track bike needs a more extreme type of shoe and pedal: the shoe is stiff, its connection with the pedal solid &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s all about maximum transfer of power. The same goes for road racing. You can&amp;#8217;t walk far in road/track shoes. Different priorities apply to mountain-biking, cycle touring and more casual sport use: you need to be able to detach yourself easily and walk around comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadly speaking, there are two main attachment systems, one designed for road- and track-racing, and one better suited for mountain biking: but once you&amp;#8217;ve settled which one of these to go for, you have a continuum of choice; road shoes which fit to mountain-bike style pedals, pedals with a cleated side and a flat side, etc. I decided to go for the popular Shimano SPD system &amp;#8212; I wanted shoes I could walk in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m ashamed to admit that I went into the bicycle shops at the top and bottom of Park Street, looked at what they had, asked advice, checked prices, then made my actual purchase &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclexpress.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Cycle Express online shop&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d like to support the local shop, but they were asking for almost twice as much money as a deal I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclexpress.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Cycle Express online shop&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; (really!): a difference so large I didn&amp;#8217;t have the nerve to ask if they could match my internet price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
1 x MT31 Shoes - Size 42 @ &amp;pound;32.99 = &amp;pound;32.99
1 x M520 SPD Pedals - PDM 520 Pedals - Black @ &amp;pound;17.49 = &amp;pound;17.49
--------------------------------
Shipping Ex VAT  = &amp;pound;0.00
Shipping Inc VAT = &amp;pound;0.00
Discounts = &amp;pound;5.05
Total Ex VAT     = &amp;pound;38.66
Total Inc VAT    = &amp;pound;45.43
Total UKP        = &amp;pound;45.43 (your card will be charged in UKP)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordered Monday, dispatched Tuesday, arrived Wednesday (morning), fitted Wednesday (evening), used Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/2826660193/&quot; title=&quot;cycle-shoes-and-pedals by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3058/2826660193_225373a3f5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;cycle-shoes-and-pedals&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-09-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/new-shoes-and-pedals</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/new-shoes-and-pedals</link>
<category>Shoes</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
