<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>1st Ever Swansea Half Marathon</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14765094316" title="Crossing the Tawe by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3890/14765094316_26248cf75f_c.jpg" width="532" height="800" alt="Crossing the Tawe"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, a half marathon is a race against the clock, a notoriously ruthless opponent. I prefer trail and cross-country races, where tactics and conditions take precedence over minutes and seconds. There&amp;#8217;s only one half marathon tactic. Also, the city races are all fast and flat and &lt;a href="http://www.walesonline.co.uk/news/wales-news/cardiff-half-marathon-too-short-1892034"&gt;accurately measured&lt;/a&gt;, meaning you can directly compare your times at Cardiff and Bristol, or your time in Cardiff to Neil&amp;#8217;s time in Bristol or Matt&amp;#8217;s time in Bath. There&amp;#8217;s nowhere to hide.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is that one and only tactic?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run an even pace, or
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t go out too fast, or
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t slow down, or
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep going, for, in my case, 80 minutes-ish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but the -ish matters! My personal best of 1:21:30, Cardiff 2011, was 90-ish seconds over. At the start of this year, 2014, I decided I&amp;#8217;d return to Cardiff, and I decided to try and go under 80 minutes. Effectively, I&amp;#8217;d have to cover a distance which previously took me 60 seconds in just under 59 seconds, and I&amp;#8217;d have to repeat that record breaking performance 81 and a half times in a row.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a calculated task requires planning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;img src=/images/fr10.png alt="Forerunner 10"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assist me in my race against time, since the start of the year I&amp;#8217;ve been using a &lt;a href="http://www.garmin.com/uk/forerunner10"&gt;Garmin Forerunner 10&lt;/a&gt;, a device which is not so much a watch as a tagging device: it knows where I am, and when, how fast I&amp;#8217;m going, how fast I&amp;#8217;m supposed to be going, and it can recall this information for subsequent analysis. As well as the Garmin, I devised a training routine which includes an extended early morning run. Once a week I meet anyone prepared to join me for a 90 minute run which culminates &amp;#8212; 10 miles in and after a couple of hills &amp;#8212; with 2 miles run at tempo. The idea is to build stamina and to get used to running on weary legs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/118158286/embed/9f3f903672f26c3370c7f5d9871a9b7b8dce46ea'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans to race the clock in Cardiff in October advanced in April when the word got out that this year, for the first time ever, &lt;a href="http://www.swanseahalfmarathon.co.uk/"&gt;Swansea would be hosting a half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. The date had been set for July 20th, meaning I&amp;#8217;d have time to prepare, and &amp;#8212; if the race didn&amp;#8217;t go well &amp;#8212; time to regroup and reset my strategy for Cardiff. I signed up sharpish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601322910" title="And they&amp;#x27;re off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3850/14601322910_32c1418472_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="And they&amp;#x27;re off"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 20th. Race day. Start time, 08:30. With entries limited to 2000 the race was a sell out and when I arrived, with an hour to go, the runners&amp;#8217; village &amp;#8212; the patch of grass filling the gaps between the museums and the LC2 &amp;#8212; the village was buzzing but not rammed. I saw Rob Falconer stretching before the race. I jogged a slow loop to the sea front and back around the marina, briefly hooking up with Steve Smith. Gary Irving, marshalling for the day, was stationed on the path in front of the Marriott with a group of cadets at what would be mile 10 of the race. It&amp;#8217;s tough going from here, he warned me. The path narrows, and there are lots of twists and turns. Could be nasty.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last swig of water. Isobel had come to support me, and I knew Dan would be down too. I walked to the start line with Eamonn. Being near the front could only help.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601319720" title="Paper shower by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2919/14601319720_4bb6df2ab3_z.jpg" width="426" height="640" alt="Paper shower"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first three miles along Oystermouth Road I ran alongside Raul. At each mile, my Garmin bleeped and displayed a lap time. I was hitting 6 minute miling. That would do it. Coming through Blackpill I got a cheer from Simon Beer. The crowds thickened in Mumbles. My race number had my name on it and I was wearing my Swansea Harriers club vest meaning I got lots of local, personalised support. There was Iain standing on the pavement. Raul had dropped back. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14784837161" title="I ran with the chap in the blue vest for a while by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2899/14784837161_484aeb60bd_c.jpg" width="534" height="800" alt="I ran with the chap in the blue vest for a while"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached the turning point, Verdis, Knab Rock, alongside a bearded runner in a light blue vest. 5 miles, flat, only one turn, barely any wind and the sun had yet to burn through the mist. I pushed on and caught another Swansea Harrier, Adam. We worked together for a couple of miles. Past the half way stage now, and I was flying. Mile 8 felt like the fastest yet. Adam had fallen back. The next runner, some way ahead, also wore a Swansea Harriers vest. Surely not Eamonn?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14787650752" title="Mile 7 or 8, I think by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5560/14787650752_2cf87b226f_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Mile 7 or 8, I think"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through 10 miles in 60:06. It was Eamonn! We were running through searing July sunshine. I no longer felt light on my feet. I focused on how I&amp;#8217;d felt running along the towpath, how I&amp;#8217;d held my pace when my legs were screaming. The path narrowed and swerved.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14788100175" title="Tawe pedestrian bridge by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5558/14788100175_ed51358c7f_c.jpg" width="532" height="800" alt="Tawe pedestrian bridge"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see runners ahead of me, crossing the bridge over the mouth of the Tawe, zig-zagging through the development zone on the other side of the river. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to think about which way to go! I slowed into the bends and accelerated wearily out of them, forcing myself back up to speed. I was still catching runners who&amp;#8217;d been ahead of me for the past hour or so. On the last cruel switchback just before crossing the Tawe for the second time, on the Sail Bridge, I saw Eamonn. All the way, Tom, push for the line, he said. I saw Alan Davies and wondered why he wasn&amp;#8217;t running. There was Dan, my brother. There were Isobel and Cai.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601482137" title="Last push. Breathless by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3908/14601482137_77ca790d44_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Last push. Breathless"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14785631184" title="Stop the Garmin by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5588/14785631184_7bc9038117_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Stop the Garmin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What time? I didn&amp;#8217;t know. I didn&amp;#8217;t see a clock on the line. I gulped in air and watched the next few runners finish. I gave Isobel a hug. Eamonn finished, then Kneath. At last I checked my watch. 1:19:36. I had gone under 80 minutes by a few precious seconds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/168338222/embed/c796f64e8214972efd71284322744a78413ce144'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the official results were published I was credited with a gun time of 1:19:38 and a chip time of 1:19:36. Racing the clock turned out to be a great tactic for placing well: I&amp;#8217;d finished 10th overall, having been 15th at the half-way point, and I came first in my age category. My prize, apparently, is to be a new running watch. It&amp;#8217;s late.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.dirtygreentrainers.com/"&gt;Dirty Green Trainers&lt;/a&gt; sports photographers for the images used on this page, and for permission to publish them here.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-07-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tour of Britain 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2009.html"&gt;I watched the start&lt;/a&gt; of a Tour of Britain stage. This year I caught the end of a stage, joining the crowds gathered on Constitution Hill, a vicious little cobbled climb near the centre of Swansea.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked slowly up the road. A sea mist obscured the view back over Swansea Bay. I stopped about &amp;frac34; of the way up. I waited. The riders were late &amp;#8212; headwinds and rain had slowed their progress over the Black Mountains. I called Dan. He said he was about &amp;#8531; of the way up the hill, with a couple of friends. I walked back down to meet them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car came past. A convoy of police riders. Then nothing. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&amp;#8217;s Brad Wiggins? someone next to me asked. What colour is he wearing? Black with a green band, I said. He rides for Team Sky. I don&amp;#8217;t know where he is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A police 4x4 stormed up the hill, flattening the spectators back against the sides of the road. And now the leading riders were here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4987111756/" title="Heavy going by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4112/4987111756_f22f4fa392_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Heavy going" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d been assuming the pros would demolish the hill. Not so. They made it look hard going, hauling round mighty gears, their spindly bikes buckling beneath them. It&amp;#8217;s true, you get close enough to touch them. Some of these guys are way too big and solid to ride up hills.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-09-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Constitution Hill</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.tourofbritain.co.uk/_ns_race/default.asp?section=stage3_route"&gt;Welsh stage&lt;/a&gt; of the Tour of Britain finishes in Swansea. Soon after 1pm the leading riders hurtle through the city centre along Kingsway, which is where the race will also finish, but not before they&amp;#8217;ve taken on a couple of steep climbs. First Bryn-y-M&amp;ocirc;r, near where Dan lives, then Constitution Hill, which is where I plan to be watching.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; the leading riders will face a last few metres of flat before the road veers upwards and onto over 300 metres of steep cobbles that lead them up onto the Swansea skyline. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hills + cobbles? Ouch!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/w2CURwHjJiw?#t=9s&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/w2CURwHjJiw?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=Constitution+Hill,+Swansea"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; indicated that Constitution Hill featured in the Keith Allen&amp;#8217;s sensitive, wry evocation of a Swansea youth, &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120394/" title="Twin Town, imdb"&gt;Twin Town&lt;/a&gt;. The road is now closed to traffic after too many idiots copied the Lewis twins&amp;#8217; driving stunt (seconds 7 to 17 of the YouTube montage above).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4941877207/" title="At the foot of Constitution Hill by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4140/4941877207_45790f4563.jpg" width="408" height="500" alt="At the foot of Constitution Hill" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode up Constitution Hill on Thursday, on my way back home from Swansea station. The train was 45 minutes late, spoiling my plans to meet the family at Parc Abertawe in time for Toy Story 3. I needed to do something to vent my frustration. It&amp;#8217;s a tough little climb, tougher than it looks from the bottom, especially if you&amp;#8217;re carrying a rucksack with a 15&amp;#8221; laptop in it, but the view from the top over Swansea bay is stunning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4941878625/" title="At the top of Constitution Hill by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4097/4941878625_6ef34d810b.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="At the top of Constitution Hill" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-08-30</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/constitution-hill</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/constitution-hill</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mumbles Triathlon 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching today&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.mumblestri.com/"&gt;Mumbles triathlon&lt;/a&gt;. Conditions were perfect: bright and warm but, at 07:00 in the morning, not yet too hot. No wind, no waves. Swansea bay looked at its best. I knew at least three people taking part but had trouble identifying them. Everyone looks much the same in a wetsuit and swimming hat. I also spotted a cyclist I see on the train. The leading swimmer went like a torpedo. He also swam the triangular route directly, cutting between a couple of boats moored offshore. Everyone else followed a curving line back to the slipway. Then it all got a bit confusing, because the event combined a short and long sprint, and I couldn&amp;#8217;t tell who was in which event.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4735356462/" title="Waiting for the off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4093/4735356462_cca0bf5db5_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Waiting for the off"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tesco Express car park, Sketty</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Good to see &lt;a href="http://bristolcars.blogspot.com/2009/12/bus-passengers-cost-shops-money.html"&gt;bus passengers being told just where they stand&lt;/a&gt; in one of Bristol&amp;#8217;s premiere shopping centres. Over in Swansea, too, the car &amp;rarr; driver &amp;rarr; bus  &amp;rarr; passenger heirarchy is rigidly enforced.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4173953288/" title="DSC00031 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2631/4173953288_7652259fa3.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="DSC00031" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, while waiting with Alex for the 118, this bus parking area in Sketty was permanently occupied by a stream of cars using the new Tesco Express. The driver of S866NLT kept the engine running while a brave shopping partner visited the outside world &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;s nothing worse than a cold car, and if you&amp;#8217;re sad enough to use a bus you&amp;#8217;ll probably enjoy exhaust fumes too.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-12-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tesco-express-car-park-sketty</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tesco-express-car-park-sketty</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
