<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Gnoll, West Glamorgan League, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Conditions in Gnoll Park for the second West Glamorgan league fixture were perfect. I hadn&amp;#8217;t expected to run since Alex had a rubgy game, but his misfortune in fracturing a finger in training (all better now, thankfully) gave me a chance to compete.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Gnoll the women and men race different distances, the men running two long loops of the estate to the women&amp;#8217;s one. Some women may feel slighted by this discrepancy but it does make for some fun on the course for spectators and runners alike. A staggered start means there&amp;#8217;s plenty of action and overtaking.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived to collect my number the estate was buzzing. I found out afterwards that 366 athletes completed the course, a league record: I&amp;#8217;m proud to have been part of that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confident in my form and lifted by the occasion, I set out fast. A tight loop took us back to the start, where we got a rousing cheer from the women who were awaiting their own start, before heading out on the first long loop. The course is truly mixed terrain. What was meadow became gravel and now we were heading up through woodland. Watch out for roots and rocks! There&amp;#8217;s a long level section through some felled forestry, then a long downhill before another grassy climb to complete the circuit. My brother Dan had turned up to support after all &amp;#8212; there he was with Schnorbie!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30201417311/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Gnoll Park XC, West Glamorgan League"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8130/30201417311_951dfdd480_c.jpg" width="533" height="800" alt="Gnoll Park XC, West Glamorgan League"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gareth Poston pulled alongside me. He&amp;#8217;s a running rival who proved too strong at &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/port-talbot-half-marathon-2016"&gt;Port Talbot&lt;/a&gt;, but beatable at &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/llanmadoc-xc-2016"&gt;Llanmadoc&lt;/a&gt;. Today, he opened a gap at the beginning of the second lap. I did my best to keep him in sight; to use him to keep me ahead of my chasers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30669799592/in/dateposted-friend/" title="gnoll-2"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5523/30669799592_e470c3a441_c.jpg" width="533" height="800" alt="gnoll-2"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up through the woods, back over the stream. Now I was passing the tail of the women&amp;#8217;s race, overtaking, concentrating on holding my line and not clattering into anyone. I didn&amp;#8217;t look behind me but could hear spectators cheering for Royston Whitehouse, a V50 rival who could surely strike if I slowed up. I pushed hard up the final climb and held on to the line. I came in first V50, just 3 seconds ahead of Royston Whitehouse, and 12th overall with a time of 35:07.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/739466227/embed/66de9f84f0805a0c2eaf70610c1db24200a745ef'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-10-09</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gnoll-west-glamorgan-league-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gnoll-west-glamorgan-league-2016</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Llanmadoc, West Glamorgan League, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The first fixture of the West Glamorgan league was held on a fine but fresh day. I cycled across from home and ran a warm up along the track through the woods following the start of the race route. In wet weather the path floods. Today it was quite dry. No need for trail shoes: I opted for the racing flats which have served me so well this year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some turn out, too! Word got round that the start was to be delayed by 15 minutes &amp;#8212; agricultural traffic on the narrow Gower roads had held up participants. I stayed warm, shook out my legs, chatted to friends.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30711411816/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Llanmadoc, Gwent League XC"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5792/30711411816_bef79e6abf_c.jpg" width="533" height="800" alt="Llanmadoc, Gwent League XC"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a fast, jostling start. I held my place and let others hare off &amp;#8212; there would be time to peg them back. Coming out of the initial wooded section the wind was on our backs. I felt lively, quick, comfortable. Now we entered the next forested section. The track becomes less firm, more sandy, winding and lumpy in places. The pace had settled down. I passed Eamonn, Charles, Paul.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the beach now, running across the slope on soft stand studded with rocks and pebbles. There is no easy line on this terrain. I could see the estuary and the cast-iron lighthouse. Turning the corner the wind slammed at full force into our faces. The exposed mile or so back along the beach suddenly looked a long way. The race leaders were strung out ahead battling the gale.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Work together boys!&amp;#8221;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice came from Alan Davies, the V60 wizard from Llanelli.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Work into the wind together,&amp;#8221; he urged, indicating with an arm that I should tuck in behind him.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tucked in. Alan is too skinny to be a great windbreak; nonetheless, the combination of the shelter he gave and the respite from making the pace made things easier. We were gaining on runners in front. After a minute or so I took the lead, Alan now sheltering behind me. Fighting the wind felt easier now I knew I could loop back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught a Swansea Harrier, James Dean, who&amp;#8217;s coming back to full fitness. &amp;#8220;Hang in,&amp;#8221; I said, but he was cooked.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The echelon had grown as we came to the end of the beach section and on to the marshy path. The headland gave some shelter. I pulled away from the group knowing the race was nearly done. I would be better attacking on the short climb than trying to sprint for the line.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30286516445/in/dateposted-friend/" title="7th place at Llanmadoc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8550/30286516445_fea0963278_c.jpg" width="532" height="800" alt="7th place at Llanmadoc"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to finish in 7th place with a time of 28:46, my highest ever finish in a West Glamorgan league race. The only thing I got wrong was failing to start my Garmin until 4 minutes in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/724914141/embed/24d20bf138e29c18ccec536ad1ab009b69b81cec'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30651152932/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Swansea harriers at Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5789/30651152932_a66eb16d95_z.jpg" width="640" height="373" alt="Swansea harriers at Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-09-25</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/llanmadoc-xc-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/llanmadoc-xc-2016</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>One week, three races</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I DNF the Cardiff half marathon. This year I went one worse and DNS the Swansea half. Consequently I was determined to turn up in good shape to complete this year&amp;#8217;s Cardiff half.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racing the week before probably wasn&amp;#8217;t a great idea &amp;#8230; but the race happened to be a short one and close to home &amp;#8230; and the weather was perfect &amp;#8230; and I hadn&amp;#8217;t raced in a while &amp;#8230; and Alex didn&amp;#8217;t have a rugby game and &amp;#8230; well, I went! 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Llandmadoc is the first fixture of the &lt;a href="http://westglamleague.co.uk"&gt;West Glamorgan cross country league&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s four and a half miles, out along a woodland trail then back on the beach. I tried to run within myself on the outward section and fell in with Peter Osborne, another V50 who I&amp;#8217;ve battled with on several occasions. He upped the pace as we hit the sloping sand around the point and then he was gone. Coming back along the beach in the blazing sun, there was a gap of 50m to the next group of runners &amp;#8212; a gap I reduced but never closed. Despite my conservative start, when we went through the wet sand I felt as energetic as one of the many stranded jellyfish which littered the course. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href="http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=147384&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Llanmadoc&amp;amp;date=27-Sep-15"&gt;finished 19th in a time of 28:32&lt;/a&gt;, officially first in my category but second really since Peter beat me and he&amp;#8217;s an age band up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21803789231/in/photostream/" title="Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5722/21803789231_138ac20159_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I avoided the track training session with Bristol and West on Monday evening &amp;#8212; the same session, last year, had been one too many. If I&amp;#8217;d had doubts about running the cross country race just a week before the half marathon, my main target for the year, then I had real concerns about testing myself at the &lt;a href="http://www.bristolandwestac.org/aztec-west-fast-5k/"&gt;Aztec West 5K&lt;/a&gt; on the Tuesday. I felt I was running well and knew a PB was possible on the fast Aztec West course, but did I want to know just how well I was running? A slow time would have rocked my confidence before Sunday&amp;#8217;s longer race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I went. As for times, I had no idea during the race because I forgot my watch. In contrast to Llanmadoc, my legs felt strong, decidedly sprightly in fact. I settled in with Will Smith and Paul Deaton, friends from Southville Running Club, and we barreled round the three lap course, overtaking some very decent runners who&amp;#8217;d started more quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21875414812/in/photostream/" title="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5816/21875414812_10a39d89f2_z.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21264629634/in/photostream/" title="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/569/21264629634_b53ab1d8aa_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="SRC at Aztec West 5k"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will accelerated with 200m to go, attacking the next three runners, and Paul went with him. I let them go. After the final sharp left, Paul faded, enough encouragement for me to sprint past him. When the &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=146231&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Sep-15"&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; were announced I discovered I&amp;#8217;d won the V50 category with a PB of 17:22.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" data-footer="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21861865806/in/photostream/" title="Aztec West 5K. Charge for the line"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/728/21861865806_aa925a0096_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Charge for the line"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Cardiff. The race is bigger than ever &amp;#8212; twenty two thousand entrants in 2015. Despite this, it was straightforward getting to the start line warmed up and ready. The elite athletes (including me!) have their own baggage drop round the back of the castle in Bute Park. From there, it&amp;#8217;s a short stroll to the right start pen. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='https://www.strava.com/activities/406748447/embed/9e8c528271c129e91657b724a243c43d982c9342'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t think I set off too quickly but my 10K time was 37:10, on target for a 78:30 finish. I guess my legs were still dialled into my 5K pace. Ifan had set out even more quickly, but I caught him around the half way point. In a half marathon I usually feel a glow during the middle of the event; the sensation that I&amp;#8217;m going fast, but at a sustainable tempo. This time, the sensation never came. I wasn&amp;#8217;t glowing, I was aching. Enduring. Maintaining a steady pace seemed impossible and I found myself repeatedly dropping then being passed by the same group of runners. Why couldn&amp;#8217;t we team up and work together? I went through 10 miles in 1:00:25, still on course for a personal best but hurting badly. Ifan went past me again at around mile 11. I didn&amp;#8217;t even try and go with him. My muscles were sore, my feet were sore. I knew I&amp;#8217;d complete the course but I was no longer shooting for a personal best; I just wanted to finish without losing too much time. Actually, I just wanted to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the final turn I realised that 80 minutes was still on and managed to sprint for the line. My time, 79:43, was just 7 seconds off my PB.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Swansea half, aftermath</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014"&gt;Clocking a sub-80 half marathon at Swansea&lt;/a&gt; was my finest running performance in 2014. Things were bound to cool off after that.  Just four days later I showed up for the Purdown Pursuit, the final event of the &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php"&gt;Tach summer series&lt;/a&gt;. The race started late and required re-routing; it was a sweltering evening and there&amp;#8217;d been a fire on the course. I took the downhill sections cautiously on sore legs but still managed &lt;a href="http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=PP_result14.inc"&gt;4th place with a time of 42.39&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks later I finished 5th at the Blaise Blazer mob match. It&amp;#8217;s one of my favourite races and I set a personal best for the course of &lt;a href="http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=106696&amp;amp;event=4MMT&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=4-Aug-14"&gt;23.51&lt;/a&gt;, picking runners off steadily in the final stages then holding on in the final sprint from the top of the steps to the folly. Southville RC put on a spirited defence of the team prize we&amp;#8217;d won the year before and, once the results had been counted and checked, to our surprise, it was announced we&amp;#8217;d retained the trophy. Later that evening after a recount the results were corrected; Westbury Harriers had, in fact, wrested the coveted Blazer Cup from our grasp.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mistake was not resting up over the summer. I wanted to go under 80 minutes for a second time at the Cardiff half marathon, a far more established and prestigious event than the one I&amp;#8217;d run in Swansea, and one at which friends from both Bristol and South Wales would compete. On the Monday before the race I tweaked my hamstring towards the end of a track session with Bristol &amp;amp; West at Whitehall. Not good. During the remainder of the week I rested before lining up on Sunday in Cardiff ready to race. I stormed the first mile in 5:40, hit a similar pace for the second, and then felt the injury ping. I pulled up and walked along the pavement, assessing the damage. I figured I could at least jog around the barrage to the Senedd but I couldn&amp;#8217;t. Instead I ended up limping from Pennarth to the centre, reaching the baggage collection around the time I should have been finishing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21815444008/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Masters XC 2015 by Alex Williams"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/644/21815444008_6cf2fe1c90_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Masters XC 2015 by Alex Williams"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t race again until the combined Welsh Inter-regional and Welsh Masters cross country championships. This is a proper cross-country course featuring mud, meadows, woodland tracks, slopes. The weather played its part: rain during the week and freezing temperatures on the day filled the puddles with ice; grass sparkled with frost as the sun broke through. I ran a measured race ending up with an individual &lt;a href="http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=118689&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Builth+Wells&amp;amp;date=13-Dec-14"&gt;silver in the MV50&lt;/a&gt; category just two seconds behind Peter Coles, the category winner. I &lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt; get a gold medal as one of Swansea Harriers&amp;#8217; winning MV50 team. In the inter-regional competition, we came second, I think. There are so many competitions being run in the same race it&amp;#8217;s hard to remember. What I do remember thinking is, what a shame such a great event gets such a low turnout. In an age where people part with serious money to tackle military-themed tough guy obstacle courses, for just a couple of quid you get to represent club and region on a challenging course in a fabulous setting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21382218343/in/dateposted-friend/" title="Welsh Masters XC 2014, Swansea Harriers gold medal V50 team"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5661/21382218343_9716029e5c_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Welsh Masters XC 2014, Swansea Harriers gold medal V50 team"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moustache, by the way, was for movember
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-07</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-aftermath</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-aftermath</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>1st Ever Swansea Half Marathon</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14765094316" title="Crossing the Tawe by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3890/14765094316_26248cf75f_c.jpg" width="532" height="800" alt="Crossing the Tawe"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, a half marathon is a race against the clock, a notoriously ruthless opponent, and since the city halves are fast, flat and &lt;a href="http://www.walesonline.co.uk/news/wales-news/cardiff-half-marathon-too-short-1892034"&gt;accurately measured&lt;/a&gt;, you can compare your time in Cardiff to your time in Bristol, or your time in Cardiff to Neil&amp;#8217;s time in Brighton or Matt&amp;#8217;s time in Bath. There&amp;#8217;s nowhere to hide.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that&amp;#8217;s whay I prefer trail and cross country, where conditions and tactics seem more important than minutes and seconds. For a half marathon conditions are either suitable for a PB or unsuitable, and there&amp;#8217;s just one tactic:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run an even pace, or
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t go out too fast, or
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t slow down, or
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep going, for, in my case, 80 minutes-ish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but the -ish matters! My personal best of 1:21:30, Cardiff 2011, the last time I ran a half, was 90 seconds over. At the start of this year, 2014, I decided to do something about that. I&amp;#8217;d return to Cardiff and I&amp;#8217;d try and go under 80 minutes. Effectively, I&amp;#8217;d have to cover a distance which previously took me 60 seconds in just under 59 seconds, and I&amp;#8217;d have to repeat that record breaking performance 81 and a half times in a row.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a calculated task requires planning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;img src=/images/fr10.png alt="Forerunner 10"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assist me in my race against time I&amp;#8217;ve been using a &lt;a href="http://www.garmin.com/uk/forerunner10"&gt;Garmin Forerunner 10&lt;/a&gt;, a device which is not so much a watch as a tagging device: it knows where I am, and when, how fast I&amp;#8217;m going, how fast I&amp;#8217;m supposed to be going, and it can recall this information for subsequent analysis. As well as the Garmin, I devised a training routine which includes an extended early morning run. Once a week I meet anyone prepared to join me for 90 minutes in a session which culminates &amp;#8212; 10 miles in and after a couple of hills &amp;#8212; with 2 miles run at tempo. The idea is to build stamina and to get used to running on weary legs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/118158286/embed/9f3f903672f26c3370c7f5d9871a9b7b8dce46ea'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans to race the clock in Cardiff in October were brought forward in April when the word got out that this year, for the first time ever, &lt;a href="http://www.swanseahalfmarathon.co.uk/"&gt;Swansea would be hosting a half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. The date had been set for July 20th, meaning I&amp;#8217;d have time to prepare, and &amp;#8212; if the race didn&amp;#8217;t go well &amp;#8212; time to regroup and reset my strategy for Cardiff. I signed up sharpish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601322910" title="And they&amp;#x27;re off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3850/14601322910_32c1418472_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="And they&amp;#x27;re off"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. July 20th. Race day. Start time, 08:30. With entries limited to 2000 the race was a sell out and when I arrived, with an hour to go, the runners&amp;#8217; village &amp;#8212; the patch of grass filling the gaps between the museums and the LC2 &amp;#8212; the village was buzzing. I saw Rob Falconer stretching before the race. I jogged a slow loop to the sea front and back around the marina, briefly hooking up with Steve Smith. Gary Irving, marshalling for the day, was stationed on the path in front of the Marriott with a group of cadets at what would be mile 10. It&amp;#8217;s tough going from here, he warned me. The path narrows and there are lots of twists and turns. Could be nasty.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last swig of water. Isobel had come to support me and I knew Dan would be down too. I walked to the start line with Eamonn. Being near the front could only help.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601319720" title="Paper shower by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2919/14601319720_4bb6df2ab3_z.jpg" width="426" height="640" alt="Paper shower"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first three miles along Oystermouth Road I ran alongside Raul. At each mile my Garmin bleeped and displayed a lap time. I was hitting 6 minute miling. That would do it. Coming through Blackpill I got a cheer from Simon Beer. The crowds thickened in Mumbles. My race number had my name on it and I was wearing my Swansea Harriers club vest which meant I got lots of local and personalised support. There was Iain standing on the pavement. Raul had dropped back. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14784837161" title="I ran with the chap in the blue vest for a while by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2899/14784837161_484aeb60bd_c.jpg" width="534" height="800" alt="I ran with the chap in the blue vest for a while"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached the turning point, Verdis, Knab Rock, alongside a bearded runner in a light blue vest. 5 miles, flat, only one turn, barely any wind and the sun had yet to burn through the mist. I pushed on and caught another Swansea Harrier, Adam. We worked together for a couple of miles. Past the half way stage now and I was flying. Mile 8 felt like the fastest yet. Adam had fallen back. The next runner, some way ahead, also wore a Swansea Harriers vest. Surely not Eamonn?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14787650752" title="Mile 7 or 8, I think by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5560/14787650752_2cf87b226f_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Mile 7 or 8, I think"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through 10 miles in 60:06. It was Eamonn! We were running through searing July sunshine. I no longer felt light on my feet. I focused on how I&amp;#8217;d felt running along the towpath, how I&amp;#8217;d held my pace when my legs were screaming. As Gary had warned, the path narrowed and swerved.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14788100175" title="Tawe pedestrian bridge by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5558/14788100175_ed51358c7f_c.jpg" width="532" height="800" alt="Tawe pedestrian bridge"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see runners ahead crossing the bridge over the mouth of the Tawe, zig-zagging through the development zone on the other side of the river. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to have to think about which way to go! I slowed into the bends and accelerated wearily out of them, forcing myself back up to speed. I was still catching runners who&amp;#8217;d been ahead of me for the past hour or so. On the last cruel switchback just before crossing the Tawe for the second time, on the Sail Bridge, I saw Eamonn. All the way, Tom, push for the line, he shouted. I saw Alan Davies and wondered why he wasn&amp;#8217;t running. There was Dan, my brother. There were Isobel and Cai.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601482137" title="Last push. Breathless by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3908/14601482137_77ca790d44_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Last push. Breathless"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14785631184" title="Stop the Garmin by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5588/14785631184_7bc9038117_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" alt="Stop the Garmin"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What time? I didn&amp;#8217;t know. I didn&amp;#8217;t see the usual race clock on the line. I gulped in air and watched the next few runners finish. I gave Isobel a hug. Eamonn came in, then Kneath. At last I checked my watch. 1:19:36. I had gone under 80 minutes by a few &amp;#8212; several! &amp;#8212; precious seconds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height='405' width='590' frameborder='0' allowtransparency='true' scrolling='no' src='http://www.strava.com/activities/168338222/embed/c796f64e8214972efd71284322744a78413ce144'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the official results were published I was credited with a gun time of 1:19:38 and a chip time of 1:19:36. Racing the clock turned out to be a great tactic for placing well: I finished 10th overall, having been 15th at the half-way point, and I came first in my age category. My prize, apparently, is to be a new running watch. It&amp;#8217;s late.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.dirtygreentrainers.com/"&gt;Dirty Green Trainers&lt;/a&gt; sports photographers for the images used on this page, and for permission to publish them here.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-07-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tour of Britain 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2009.html"&gt;I watched the start&lt;/a&gt; of a Tour of Britain stage. This year I caught the end of a stage, joining the crowds gathered on Constitution Hill, a vicious little cobbled climb near the centre of Swansea.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked slowly up the road. A sea mist obscured the view back over Swansea Bay. I stopped about &amp;frac34; of the way up. I waited. The riders were late &amp;#8212; headwinds and rain had slowed their progress over the Black Mountains. I called Dan. He said he was about &amp;#8531; of the way up the hill, with a couple of friends. I walked back down to meet them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car came past. A convoy of police riders. Then nothing. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&amp;#8217;s Brad Wiggins? someone next to me asked. What colour is he wearing? Black with a green band, I said. He rides for Team Sky. I don&amp;#8217;t know where he is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A police 4x4 stormed up the hill, flattening the spectators back against the sides of the road. And now the leading riders were here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4987111756/" title="Heavy going by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4112/4987111756_f22f4fa392_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Heavy going" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d been assuming the pros would demolish the hill. Not so. They made it look hard going, hauling round mighty gears, their spindly bikes buckling beneath them. It&amp;#8217;s true, you get close enough to touch them. Some of these guys are way too big and solid to ride up hills.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-09-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Constitution Hill</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.tourofbritain.co.uk/_ns_race/default.asp?section=stage3_route"&gt;Welsh stage&lt;/a&gt; of the Tour of Britain finishes in Swansea. Soon after 1pm the leading riders hurtle through the city centre along Kingsway, which is where the race will also finish, but not before they&amp;#8217;ve taken on a couple of steep climbs. First Bryn-y-M&amp;ocirc;r, near where Dan lives, then Constitution Hill, which is where I plan to be watching.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; the leading riders will face a last few metres of flat before the road veers upwards and onto over 300 metres of steep cobbles that lead them up onto the Swansea skyline. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hills + cobbles? Ouch!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/w2CURwHjJiw?#t=9s&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/w2CURwHjJiw?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=Constitution+Hill,+Swansea"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; indicated that Constitution Hill featured in the Keith Allen&amp;#8217;s sensitive, wry evocation of a Swansea youth, &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120394/" title="Twin Town, imdb"&gt;Twin Town&lt;/a&gt;. The road is now closed to traffic after too many idiots copied the Lewis twins&amp;#8217; driving stunt (seconds 7 to 17 of the YouTube montage above).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4941877207/" title="At the foot of Constitution Hill by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4140/4941877207_45790f4563.jpg" width="408" height="500" alt="At the foot of Constitution Hill" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode up Constitution Hill on Thursday, on my way back home from Swansea station. The train was 45 minutes late, spoiling my plans to meet the family at Parc Abertawe in time for Toy Story 3. I needed to do something to vent my frustration. It&amp;#8217;s a tough little climb, tougher than it looks from the bottom, especially if you&amp;#8217;re carrying a rucksack with a 15&amp;#8221; laptop in it, but the view from the top over Swansea bay is stunning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4941878625/" title="At the top of Constitution Hill by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4097/4941878625_6ef34d810b.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="At the top of Constitution Hill" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-08-30</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/constitution-hill</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/constitution-hill</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mumbles Triathlon 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching today&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.mumblestri.com/"&gt;Mumbles triathlon&lt;/a&gt;. Conditions were perfect: bright and warm but, at 07:00 in the morning, not yet too hot. No wind, no waves. Swansea bay looked at its best. I knew at least three people taking part but had trouble identifying them. Everyone looks much the same in a wetsuit and swimming hat. I also spotted a cyclist I see on the train. The leading swimmer went like a torpedo. He also swam the triangular route directly, cutting between a couple of boats moored offshore. Everyone else followed a curving line back to the slipway. Then it all got a bit confusing, because the event combined a short and long sprint, and I couldn&amp;#8217;t tell who was in which event.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4735356462/" title="Waiting for the off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4093/4735356462_cca0bf5db5_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Waiting for the off"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tesco Express car park, Sketty</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Good to see &lt;a href="http://bristolcars.blogspot.com/2009/12/bus-passengers-cost-shops-money.html"&gt;bus passengers being told just where they stand&lt;/a&gt; in one of Bristol&amp;#8217;s premiere shopping centres. Over in Swansea, too, the car &amp;rarr; driver &amp;rarr; bus  &amp;rarr; passenger heirarchy is rigidly enforced.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4173953288/" title="DSC00031 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2631/4173953288_7652259fa3.jpg" width="375" height="500" alt="DSC00031" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, while waiting with Alex for the 118, this bus parking area in Sketty was permanently occupied by a stream of cars using the new Tesco Express. The driver of S866NLT kept the engine running while a brave shopping partner visited the outside world &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;s nothing worse than a cold car, and if you&amp;#8217;re sad enough to use a bus you&amp;#8217;ll probably enjoy exhaust fumes too.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-12-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tesco-express-car-park-sketty</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tesco-express-car-park-sketty</link>
<category>Swansea</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
