<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Following the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As ever, I&amp;#8217;m watching the Tour de France &amp;#8212; or maybe I should say I&amp;#8217;m &lt;strong&gt;following&lt;/strong&gt; the tour, since I get much of my fix online, direct from &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/geraintthomas86" title="Geraint Thomas"&gt;riders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://inrng.com" title="The Inner Ring"&gt;commentators&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com" title="Cycling News"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I like the mountain stages. The scenery, the history, the combat. Winners and losers. The Pyrenees have disappointed with the favourites marking each other and no one prepared to make a sustained attack. We had this in 2010, and we still don&amp;#8217;t know who won that race.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll on the Alps. As &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/inrng" title="The Inner Ring, on Twitter"&gt;@inrng&lt;/a&gt; points out, the &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage19" title="Inner Ring analysis of stage 19"&gt;Alpe d&amp;#8217;Huez stage is just under 110km&lt;/a&gt;, a sprint. Andy Schleck: don&amp;#8217;t look back!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2011/jul/09/team-sky-bradley-wiggins"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2011/7/9/1310205980831/Team-Skys-Bradley-Wiggins-007.jpg" alt="Bradley Wiggins, crashed out on stage 7"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrible to see Bradley Wiggins collapsed on the tarmac nursing a broken collarbone and knowing his race was over. What if? He&amp;#8217;d shed so much weight in preparation for the mountains there wasn&amp;#8217;t much left of him but what remained &amp;#8212; self-belief, humour, quality &amp;#8212; well, the climbers wouldn&amp;#8217;t have dropped him and he&amp;#8217;d have smashed them in the final time trial. There may yet be positives. Geraint Thomas is off the leash and riding with flair and abandon. He&amp;#8217;s no threat in the GC and could well grab a breakaway stage. Team Sky will build and regroup and throw everything at the Vuelta where Wiggo could yet become the first Briton to win a Grand Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the flatter stages have provided better racing. Cavendish has been a great winner. He also lost well, to Greipel, just the once. For the fourth consecutive year, he&amp;#8217;s fastest. Victory margins haven&amp;#8217;t been massive but to end up in green you have to run a marathon and a sprint, repeatedly. Is all about conserving energy. He can do it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Liggett and Paul Sherwen are putting in a solid performance. Ned Boulting too. Chris Boardman sounds dull, especially when voicing the sponsors&amp;#8217; messages which bookend the ad breaks:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve often wondered, why do they have second and third place on the podium? &amp;#8230; Yellow isn&amp;#8217;t a colour, it&amp;#8217;s a state of mind &amp;#8230; When my team had to lift me off my bike at the end of a stage, I knew I&amp;#8217;d done enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take (some of) it back about Chris Boardman: his analysis of &lt;a href="http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage16"&gt;stage 16&lt;/a&gt;, the one which finished with a treacherous descent into Gap, was spot on. There&amp;#8217;s Andy Schleck moaning people don&amp;#8217;t want to see a race won downhill, yet he hasn&amp;#8217;t raced uphill either, not really. Or as CB described it: throwing the toys out of his pram.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tour of Britain 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2009.html"&gt;I watched the start&lt;/a&gt; of a Tour of Britain stage. This year I caught the end of a stage, joining the crowds gathered on Constitution Hill, a vicious little cobbled climb near the centre of Swansea.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked slowly up the road. A sea mist obscured the view back over Swansea Bay. I stopped about &amp;frac34; of the way up. I waited. The riders were late &amp;#8212; headwinds and rain had slowed their progress over the Black Mountains. I called Dan. He said he was about &amp;#8531; of the way up the hill, with a couple of friends. I walked back down to meet them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car came past. A convoy of police riders. Then nothing. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&amp;#8217;s Brad Wiggins? someone next to me asked. What colour is he wearing? Black with a green band, I said. He rides for Team Sky. I don&amp;#8217;t know where he is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A police 4x4 stormed up the hill, flattening the spectators back against the sides of the road. And now the leading riders were here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4987111756/" title="Heavy going by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4112/4987111756_f22f4fa392_z.jpg" width="640" height="480" alt="Heavy going" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d been assuming the pros would demolish the hill. Not so. They made it look hard going, hauling round mighty gears, their spindly bikes buckling beneath them. It&amp;#8217;s true, you get close enough to touch them. Some of these guys are way too big and solid to ride up hills.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-09-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tour-of-britain-2010.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 15, fear and respect</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees.html"&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about the failures and disappointments which made the opening week of this year&amp;#8217;s tour so compelling, and complained that the action had dropped when it should have peaked, in the mountains. Having shaken off the field, Contador and Schleck seemed unable to get to grips with each other. That all changed on stage 15, though again failure and disappointment underpinned the racing. Schleck sprang away from the elite climbers on the Port de Bal&amp;egrave;s, with Contador in hot pursuit. Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain came off but the momentum of his attack continued &amp;#8212; now carried by Contador and a few other elite riders.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve already seen Schleck doesn&amp;#8217;t have the team support Contador does; but he looked cruelly exposed on that mountain road, struggling to re-fit his chain. It took a couple of goes. He had to fend off a motorbike. He needed help from a couple of spectators to shove him back on course. By then, the leader on the road was Contador.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last we were treated to the sight of Schleck racing uphill. He tore up the road. He nearly caught Contador, but the Spaniard was lucky to be in the perfect group for a super-fast descent. At the end of that descent, the end of the stage, Contador had the yellow jersey.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleck was furious. He &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; furious. I think he&amp;#8217;s also wiped out, physically and emotionally. Anger fuelled his final climb up the Bal&amp;egrave;s but a tankful of anger won&amp;#8217;t get take over the Tourmalet. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview afterwards Contador was asked if he was afraid of Schleck. Fear? No, he said. Respect, yes. Contador lost a lot of respect for attacking when the race leader suffered a mechanical failure. Maybe even self-respect. He was jeered on the podium. He &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/news/contador-defends-his-attack-on-the-bales"&gt;toughed it out with the press&lt;/a&gt;, claiming he hadn&amp;#8217;t known about Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain falling off. Later on, from his hotel room, he posted a public apology on &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XdOJLuePexs"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/XdOJLuePexs&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if Schleck&amp;#8217;s chain hadn&amp;#8217;t come off? I think Contador would have caught him. Schleck was already looking back to see who was where. He needed to face forwards and give it everything. I also thought Contador would attack on the final Pyrenean stage. He&amp;#8217;s been holding something back. I thought that he was too classy to accept winning the Tour by beating the clock in a time trial. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m not so sure he would have attacked, when defence and a decent time-trial would have sufficed. He will attack, if only to regain some respect. Sadly, I doubt Schleck has enough left.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-15-fear-and-respect.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 14, Pyrenees</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The first week of the Tour is normally a prelude to the real action &amp;#8212; someone unexpected wears yellow, sprinters stretch their legs, commentators and journalists clock up a few words, everyone looks forward to the real race. This year has seen a first week like no other. Looking back, amazingly, it&amp;#8217;s the failures and disappointments which stand out:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
     Cav&amp;#8217;s failure to contest the opening sprints
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Armstrong&amp;#8217;s poor luck and subsequent inability to follow the leaders (and now look how far he has fallen!)
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     Frank Schleck&amp;#8217;s broken shoulder, meaning he won&amp;#8217;t be there for his brother
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
     yellow jersey Cancellara cancelling the sprint finish at the end of stage 2. How could he do that?
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on. If this opening week offered so much drama, what would we get when the route hit the mountains?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story unfolds. Unimaginably, Andy Schleck beat Contador in the first Alpine stage, and in the next stage the two of them &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers.html"&gt;toyed with each other&lt;/a&gt; briefly then teamed up to demolish any wannabes. Now we&amp;#8217;re in the Pyrenees, where the tour should be decided. Yesterday Contador and Schleck reached stalemate, again, like a joke with no punchline. Come on guys, this race deserves better!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On the subject of Armstrong, has he really cracked, or is he trying to drop so far down the GC that he&amp;#8217;ll be allowed a break-away stage win?)
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-14-pyrenees.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 11, sprint battle</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What battle? Understandably lost in the controversy is the fact that Mark Cavendish has roared back into the form he had last year. He leapt away from the pack and took the stage comfortably. No, the real battle was 500m from the line, fought between Cav&amp;#8217;s lead-out man, Mark Renshaw from HTC Columbia, and Julian Dean from Garmin-Transitions. You could see it coming &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;d been barging and shoving on very a fast run-in. Everyone was wound up tight. Dean cut across Renshaw. Either Renshaw had to back down, or he had to force Dean away, or there&amp;#8217;d be an almighty pile-up. Renshaw was furious. He lost his head. He used his head, butting Dean three times with it. Then &amp;#8212; and this did not look good &amp;#8212; he cut in front of Tyler Farrar, the Garmin-Transitions sprinter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this happened in a couple of seconds, at high speed. It did look brutal. At least no one got hurt, but the judges came down hard. Mark Renshaw has been eliminated from the Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sprint finish is all about the individual who gets to the line first, but it&amp;#8217;s also all about the team. Cavendish always stresses his wins are team victories: the HTC Columbia train sets him up, he just has to finish the job. HTC Columbia had already lost one rider, Adam Hansen, on stage 2, evidently without too many adverse effects, but can they do without the world&amp;#8217;s best lead-out man, Mark Renshaw? More importantly, how will Cav respond? He&amp;#8217;s hot-headed and impetuous. I hope he doesn&amp;#8217;t do something stupid.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-11-sprint-battle.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-11-sprint-battle.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF 2010, Stage 9, dancing climbers</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The best climbers seem to dance up the slopes and today, on the Madeleine, two of the very best performed a wonderful pas de deux. Schleck flashed, Contador darted. The elastic between them pinged and sang. Might their rivals not take advantage of this energy-sapping flirtation? What rivals! A gruelling stage had already unravelled them. Contador and Schleck stopped playing and chased home. The race is between them now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If I attacked one more time I would have dropped myself,&amp;#8221; said Andy Schleck afterwards, but he looked as if he&amp;#8217;d just stepped out of the shower after a good night&amp;#8217;s sleep, rather than completed a mountain stage of the world&amp;#8217;s toughest race. Bring on the Pyrenees. Contador is too classy a rider to win the tour in a time trial. He&amp;#8217;s getting stronger. Watch him attack!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stage-9-dancing-climbers.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Week One</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, a rest day today, after a week of quite literal thrills and spills. Yesterday provided a fitting finale.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember last year, that final mountain stage on Mont Ventoux? It was meant to decide the general classification but by then Contador, already in yellow, had enough of a lead to ride defensively and cover the attacks. Andy Schleck couldn&amp;#8217;t shake him off. The stage was effectively neutralised. Yesterday, on the first Alpine stage, it looked like Schleck hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped at the summit of Ventoux at all. There he was, still poised on Contador&amp;#8217;s shoulder, a fresh-faced skinny executioner kitted out in white. This time Contador didn&amp;#8217;t look so clever. Schleck may not have taken much time out of his rival but he beat him convincingly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/races/97th-tour-de-france-gt/stage-8/results"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com//2010/07/11/2/bettiniphoto_0056537_1_full_600.jpg" alt="Schleck the skinny executioner"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Stages 0 and 1</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Chapeau, &lt;a href="http://www.itv.com/sport/tourdefrance/"&gt;ITV4&lt;/a&gt;, for the live coverage, even if I can&amp;#8217;t see myself getting to watch much of it. The prologue stage has definitely whetted the appetite. I&amp;#8217;m pleased Cancellara won. &amp;#8220;My body worked at 100% for exactly ten minutes,&amp;#8221; he said. It&amp;#8217;s almost unthinkable that another expert clock-racer, Brad Wiggins, could drop almost a minute over such a short course, but he did. I&amp;#8217;ve read Wiggo&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Pursuit-Glory-Autobiography-Bradley-Wiggins/dp/0752884034"&gt;In Pursuit of Glory: The Autobiography&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; one for the fans, I think, but one thing I did take from it was how accurately Wiggo can calibrate his form on the track. He knows how long it takes for him to ride a kilometre in a covered velodrome to within a second. A wet road in Rotterdam is less predictable, and Wiggo wanted to avoid trouble. Cancellara has more panache and his bike-handling skills are sans pareil. So he won. Can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him attack the &lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;cobbled roads&lt;/a&gt; in stage 3.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com/2010/04/09/2/img_0669_600.jpg" alt="Going. To. Be. Carnage"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hardened campaigner got going when the going got tough. Armstrong took a chunk out of Wiggins and other GC rivals in the &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr/2010/TDF/LIVE/us/0/classement/index.html"&gt;prologue&lt;/a&gt;. He also got the first strike in against Contador (let&amp;#8217;s not forget that he lost 22 seconds to the Spaniard over the same stage last year). I&amp;#8217;ll bet he rattles Contador some more on the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/17414049508"&gt;cobbles&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking forwards to the highlights of Stage One this evening, especially when it became obvious it would end with a bunch sprint. About time to see Cavendish stretch his legs. Except it didn&amp;#8217;t happen like that. Cav has had a rotten run-in to the Tour this year. Always volatile and unpredictable, he&amp;#8217;s turning into very a loose cannon. He tumbled on the final bend taking out rival Oscar Freire. Last year no one got close to Cav. And this year other riders would do well to stay away from him. With Cav down the other riders had to improvise the final kilometre and they made a spectacular mess of it, staging a mass pile up instead of a mass sprint. Quelle horreur!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Yellow on Sunday?</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Race favourite Cadel Evans looked a bit shaky in yesterday&amp;#8217;s mountain stage, so no surprise to see the Spanish climber Carlos Sastre attack today from the foot of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpe_d%27Huez"&gt;Alpe-d&amp;#8217;Huez&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpe_d%27Huez"&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/1e/Lacets_AlpedHuez.jpg/400px-Lacets_AlpedHuez.jpg" alt="Alpe d'Huez"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A magnificent climb saw him finish almost two minutes clear from his rivals. He&amp;#8217;s now in yellow. Assuming there&amp;#8217;s no major change amongst the leaders in tomorrow&amp;#8217;s relatively tame stage he will start the time trial on Saturday with a lead of 94 seconds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the previous time trial, stage 4, Evans gained 76 seconds over Sastre over a distance of 29.5km. Saturday&amp;#8217;s penultimate stage is 53km, so if Evans and Sastre perform similarly Evans might expect to be leading the race on Sunday by (76 &amp;times; 53 &amp;divide; 23.5) &amp;minus; 94 seconds, which comes out at around 76 seconds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sastre looked exhausted by the finish today but the maillot jaune will surely revive him. Evans wasn&amp;#8217;t exactly taking it easy.  Others remain in contention. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As J-F. Pescheux, race director (3 Tours de France as a rider, 27 as an organizer) &lt;a href="http://www.letour.fr/2008/TDF/LIVE/us/2000/etape_par_etape.html"&gt;puts it&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This final individual time trial along rolling roads in the Allier and the Cher will fine-tune the individual and team overall placings. A last battle between the top riders could still take place here
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-23</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/yellow-on-sunday.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/yellow-on-sunday.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>No stopping Mark Cavendish</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;That makes &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; once he hit the front there was no stopping him as he confirmed his status as the fastest finisher on the planet. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/7514166.stm"&gt;BBC Sport&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/no-stopping-mark-cavendish.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/no-stopping-mark-cavendish.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Google street view of the Tour de France</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/mpl?ie=UTF&amp;amp;moduleurl=http://maps.google.com/mapfiles/mapplets/tourdefrance2008/tourdefrance2008_en.xml&amp;amp;ll=45.460131,1.208496&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;z=6&amp;amp;layer=c"&gt;Formidable&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-18</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/google-street-view-of-the-tour-de-france.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/google-street-view-of-the-tour-de-france.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Fastest sprinter in the Tour completes a hat-trick!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.markcavendish.com"&gt;&lt;img width="500px" src="http://www.markcavendish.com/images/banner1.jpg" alt="Mark Cavendish"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another classic finish as the Tour hurtled at top speed into the centre of Narbonne today. &lt;a href="http://www.markcavendish.com"&gt;Mark Cavendish&lt;/a&gt; crossed the line first, which means he&amp;#8217;s won more stages in a single Tour than anyone else from the UK. I knew he&amp;#8217;d do it, but I didn&amp;#8217;t know he&amp;#8217;d do it so soon after Saturday&amp;#8217;s awesome display of power. The big question now: Can he make it over the Alps? A freak accident made the Pyrennees tough going, and he had to dig deep today. I&amp;#8217;d love to see him storming round the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es &amp;#8212; if he gets there, he&amp;#8217;ll win the final stage too. 
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-17</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour-completes-a-hattrick.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour-completes-a-hattrick.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Fastest sprinter in the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/7503565.stm"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" src="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/44827000/jpg/_44827299_cavendishap226.jpg" alt="[Mark Cavendish]"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Cavendish left the other sprinters for dead today, winning his second stage of this year&amp;#8217;s Tour.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/other_sports/cycling/7503565.stm"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; impressed me too:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And after the race he confirmed his intention to complete this year&amp;#8217;s Tour before joining his GB Olympics team-mates at their track training camp.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m okay and I will keep going for as long as I can,&amp;#8221; said Cavendish. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone remember Mario Cipollini heading home after the first week of the tour? I reckon Cavendish is chasing a hat-trick
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2008-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour.html</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/fastest-sprinter-in-the-tour.html</link>
<category>Tour</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
