<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Gower Triathlon, 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.foor.co.uk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/foor-quantum.png" alt="Foor quantum"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wetsuit is designed for warmth and durability. Getting it on and off is a struggle, and any extended swim turns into a battle with wet neoprene. Contrast this with a triathlon wetsuit, which is flexible, taut and sleek, the sort of thing a porpoise would look good in. I had no intention of spending money on a triathlon wetsuit, though. What&amp;#8217;s the point in forking out when I might not even like triathlons? Besides, not having a proper wetsuit was a good excuse.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael ruined that strategy. He turned up last night with a &lt;a href="http://www.foor.co.uk"&gt;Foor Quantum F3&lt;/a&gt; racing wetsuit. It&amp;#8217;s too small for me, it might fit you, give it a try in the bath, he said. Caveat emptor and all that. Good luck tomorrow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id="continue-reading"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It fitted. When, at last, I marched into Port Eynon bay alongside 326 similarly clad athletes, a shade after 7 o&amp;#8217;clock this morning, it felt good. I tried a few strokes. Oh, it was good.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I wasn&amp;#8217;t. Despite the suit, I found myself flailing and out of breath. No one warned me about triathlon being a contact sport. Swimmers barged, kicked and gouged. The orange buoys marking the route had seemed so close together from the shore. At sea-level I could barely make them out on the foamy horizon. And then I was trying to cut a racing line around one at the same time as a hundred others.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the swim about half way down the field. I felt pretty dejected coming back up the beach. Thank goodness some people were cheering me on. I felt much better once I&amp;#8217;d got on my bike. The rolling course suited me. I know these roads. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding near the centre line coming up Cefn Bryn, overtaking.  A van coming down the hill. A sheep leapt from the bracken and dashed through a cluster of cyclists. The van slammed on its brakes. The sheep stopped abruptly, all four legs rigid, eyes goggling, then sprang back into the verge. It sprinted alongside the race for another couple of hundred metres before finally veering across the road and safely away.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain came. My shoes filled with water. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4830108778/" title="End of the cycle leg by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4078/4830108778_13fc408798_z.jpg" width="541" height="640" alt="End of the cycle leg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;#8217;d been told about training for a triathlon: try running immediately after cycling, otherwise you won&amp;#8217;t know what it feels like. Good advice! Shame I ignored it, choosing instead to find out on race day. At least I didn&amp;#8217;t fall over. I stumbled into the transition area, racked my bike, swigged some water. Then off on the run, the best bit of which was finishing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the &lt;a href="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/Final.xls"&gt;results&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My entry reads: 357, Thomas Guest, MV, M, 13:19, 3:16, 45:28, 20:52, 1:22:53, 30, 8
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;357 was my race number. MV means Male Veteran. M means Male. The agony of the swim lasted barely 13 minutes. I then spent over 3 minutes getting ready for the cycling. 45 and a half minutes on the bike was good, my best stage, and just under 21 minutes for the run and second transition isn&amp;#8217;t too bad. I came 30th overall, and 8th out of around 100 male veterans, amazing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I do another one? I like sports which involve getting from A to B. For me, the feeling you get when you can cover ground efficiently, in control, you can&amp;#8217;t beat it. Now if I could get that feeling when swimming &amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my dad and Fynn for coming along to support me, to everyone else who cheered me on &amp;#8212; you made a big difference, thanks &amp;#8212; to Michael for lending me the wetsuit, and to the organisers and marshals who ran everything with efficiency and good humour.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-triathlon-2010</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/gower-triathlon-2010</link>
<category>Triathlon</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mumbles Triathlon 2010</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching today&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.mumblestri.com/"&gt;Mumbles triathlon&lt;/a&gt;. Conditions were perfect: bright and warm but, at 07:00 in the morning, not yet too hot. No wind, no waves. Swansea bay looked at its best. I knew at least three people taking part but had trouble identifying them. Everyone looks much the same in a wetsuit and swimming hat. I also spotted a cyclist I see on the train. The leading swimmer went like a torpedo. He also swam the triangular route directly, cutting between a couple of boats moored offshore. Everyone else followed a curving line back to the slipway. Then it all got a bit confusing, because the event combined a short and long sprint, and I couldn&amp;#8217;t tell who was in which event.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4735356462/" title="Waiting for the off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4093/4735356462_cca0bf5db5_z.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Waiting for the off"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard-with-a-vengeance</link>
<category>Triathlon</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Triathlon - not for spectators</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/wp-content/gallery/2009-activity-wales-gower-peninsula-triathlon/mje15467.jpg" alt="Gower Triathon"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href="http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard.html"&gt;been to see&lt;/a&gt; a triathlon. Certainly the event impressed me. Equally it left me in no hurry to participate. The combination of three disciplines and punishing weather conditions exposed endurance athletes as stubborn masochists. Why would anyone do that to themselves? As Richard&amp;#8217;s acerbic blog entry &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info/2009/08/triathlon-bbc-tv/" title="Triathlon &amp;amp;mdash; More Boring on TV than Handball?"&gt;Triathlon &amp;#8212; more boring on TV than Handball?&lt;/a&gt; points out, a triathlon boils down to averages and costume changes. However, as &lt;a href="http://www.richardbeard.info/2009/08/triathlon-bbc-tv/comment-page-1/#comment-1095"&gt;lima&lt;/a&gt; comments:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;you people are so damn stupid. have any of you ever done a triathlon???? I doubt! So please shut the f&amp;#8230; up!!!!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/"&gt;Gower Triathlon&lt;/a&gt; goes right past my house. It&amp;#8217;s a popular event, so popular, in fact, that when Mike told me about it they&amp;#8217;d already sold out; but when I checked the &lt;a href="http://www.gowertriathlon.co.uk/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; I found they&amp;#8217;d just allocated 100 more places. I took that as a sign and signed up. Only a month to go now. I can cycle and run, and I reckon I can cycle and then run. It&amp;#8217;s the swimming and transitions which scare me. I&amp;#8217;m off to watch the &lt;a href="http://www.mumblestri.com/"&gt;Mumbles triathlon&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow morning and see how it&amp;#8217;s done.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-25</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-harder</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-harder</link>
<category>Triathlon</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>1997 Bath Triathlon</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I can remember watching the 1997 Bath Triathlon. The breaking news that morning, there&amp;#8217;d been a car crash in Paris. Diana Spencer had been injured. She&amp;#8217;s dead, Mel said. The sky was heavy. Rain during the week had the river running fast and high. In went the wet-suited competitors. The current swept several away immediately and over the three lap course several more succumbed. The survivors clambered out, struggling to unpeel wetsuits on the move, fastening shoes and helmets with damp fingers, then off on bicycles straight up Bathwick Hill. The rain started. It was one of those summer storms when the sky tears apart. Gutters turned into streams. Rain drops hit the pavement and bounced back up again. The cyclists jammed on their brakes coming down the hill. Spoked wheels threw up plumes of spray. The shower ended abruptly. By now everything was soaked. The event should have ended but exhausted runners continued to trudge round the city centre. They didn&amp;#8217;t look like athletes. They didn&amp;#8217;t look like fun-runners. They looked beaten.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-06-24</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tri-hard</link>
<category>Triathlon</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
