<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Welsh Castles Relay 2018, Veterans Team Winners!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/41996615514/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Castles Relay 2011, mountain stage from Brecon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1723/41996615514_3904bc79d8_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Castles Relay 2011, Brecon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven years ago I ran my &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011&quot;&gt;first Welsh Castles Relay&lt;/a&gt;, completing the mountain stage out of Brecon. This photo is a reminder not all June weekends are hot and dry. My fingers were so cold at the finish I couldn&amp;#8217;t untie my shoe laces. That year we won the Monarch of the Mountains prize, awarded to the veterans team completing the 6 designated mountain stages in the quickest total time. It&amp;#8217;s a prize we&amp;#8217;ve won a few times since but I&amp;#8217;ve never been in a team which won the overall competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/42667788802/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Welsh Castles relay 2018, Veterans Team winners&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1734/42667788802_d5cb2e9b40_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;531&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Welsh Castles relay 2018, Veterans Team winners&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, 2018, we put out a strong team. Even when &amp;#8212; inevitably, for a veterans team &amp;#8212; people dropped out with injury, substitutes leapt forward to accept the challenge. Yesterday I ran stage 7, a mountain stage where the tough part is actually the downhill.  By the end of the day we&amp;#8217;d gained a lead of almost 20 minutes over our closest rivals, Team Bath AC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today that lead was consolidated with some gutsy runs in sweltering heat, and we finished the 20 stage race in a time of 23 hours and 30 minutes &amp;#8212; 30 minutes ahead of Team Bath AC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A superb result! This feels special.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2018-06-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2018-vets-winners</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2018-vets-winners</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Aberavon, West Glamorgan League 2017</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, the final race of the West Glamorgan League, held on a bright and breezy spring morning on the shimmering expanse of Aberavon beach. Warming up on the firm sand, I quickly figured out there&amp;#8217;d be a tough headwind on the return leg of the out-and-back course. This was the fifth and final event of the season: if I ran a good race, I&amp;#8217;d finish as the overall V50 champion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/33538397981/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;west-glam-v&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3703/33538397981_e00d804b5f_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;321&quot; alt=&quot;west-glam-v&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For once, no jostling at the start &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;s plenty of room for everyone on Aberavon beach. Charles Walsh strode out alongside Matt Rees, hurtling towards the dunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/37457082440/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;West Glam 5, Aberavon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4469/37457082440_1c186e3f73_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;West Glam 5, Aberavon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the dunes the sand was powder dry. The air was dry. I was thirsty and weary already. Alan Davies pushed past, light on his feet. We were running alongside a high security fence. Turning left when we reached the river, we were into the midde section of the race. The sand was so soft; my feet slid. Paul Flynn passed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last we were on the wide hard sand of the beach. I remembered Llanmadoc and looked for runners to team with &amp;#8212; hoping to form an echelon and attack the headwind &amp;#8212; but everyone had spread out. I could see Alan&amp;#8217;s red Llanelli vest ahead, too far ahead to catch. Charles Walsh was still up front running strongly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/37714433201/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;West Glam 5, Aberavon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4469/37714433201_55db71827f_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;West Glam 5, Aberavon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wind whipped up the sand into flurries stinging my eyes and legs. I &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt; making ground on others again, tapping into some energy reserve. I caught up two or three places in the last kilometre, finishing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=182048&quot;&gt;12th overall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was first V50, a couple of positions in front of Royston Whitehouse, Alan Davies, V60, had come home in 7th place almost a minute ahead of me. So, whilst I knew I had won the V50 overall title for the 2016/17 season, I wasn&amp;#8217;t sure if an older runner had done better than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/915959617/embed/0ee68b09cd7d8f214a22aac86d8b30a6ced00bd8&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westglamleague.co.uk/individual-tables-2016-17/&quot;&gt;final tables&lt;/a&gt; were published they confirmed I had finished second in the league overall, behind Matt Rees, just a single point ahead of Alan Davies&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2017-03-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/aberavon-west-glamorgan-league-2017</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/aberavon-west-glamorgan-league-2017</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Margam Park, West Glamorgan League 2017</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/kenfig-west-glamorgan-league-2016&quot;&gt;Kenfig fixture&lt;/a&gt; seemed like a long time ago, so it was good to see some friends back on the circuit at Margam Park. It was cold enough outside, but the race HQ, the castle itself &amp;#8212; a 19th century Tudor gothic mansion &amp;#8212; was even colder. I changed quickly and hurried out to warm up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspecting the course it became evident the going would be varied. The first kilometre or so was on a well-surfaced road; but then, after a brief section of trail, there would be a boggy switchback climbing through a sequence of fields up to a rolling trail, from which a fast descent would bring you back to the road for a second lap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/32832794772/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Margam Park, West Glam League IV, 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/4/3940/32832794772_cda7405398_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Margam Park, West Glam League IV, 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran alongside Paul Flynn until we hit the soft uphill at which point I pulled ahead. Royston Whitehouse came past me on that first climb but by the top I had my nose back in front. I went hard on the trail and by the start of the second lap was on my own, with Eamonn Kirk 100m in front and a similar gap on Roy behind. I worked hard to catch Eamonn but it wasn&amp;#8217;t happening so I worked hard to stay ahead of Roy, aware of his fast finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, the finish: for some reason I hadn&amp;#8217;t worked out where it was, and assumed it would be at the foot of the climb and in front of the mansion, as fine a finale as you could wish for. I was horrified when I realised this was not the case and that, once again, I was on tarmac with no end in sight. Could there even be a third lap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/32172745173/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Margam Park, West Glam League IV, 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/292/32172745173_5df172c2d3_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Margam Park, West Glam League IV, 2017&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily not, and I held it together until the line, to finish in 14th overall and first V50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/832716951/embed/d3f25e85ca78c3786ebfebc57b31af7aeb02d160&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2017-01-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/margam-park-west-glamorgan-league-2017</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/margam-park-west-glamorgan-league-2017</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nos Galan, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Making it to the start line proves hard enough. The park and ride is chaotic, coaches blocked, cars queued, attendants overwhelmed. I roll up a kerb and squeeze into a space on the grasss verge to continue on foot. Soon enough I cross the bridge and begin to weave through the crowds packing Mountain Ash&amp;#8217;s small centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town is the race course. Barriers separate the track (the road, that is) from the stands (pavement). Getting anywhere is hard, what with dogs, children, babies, buggies, but somehow the PA keeps the agenda moving: the torch, the fireworks, the funfair, the mystery runner, and of course, soon, the races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A community centre has become a makeshift changing area. I find myself queuing with Eamonn for one of two toilet cubicles. Matt Rees is there too, treating this event as a speed session to temper a fearsome endurance training programme in preparation for next year&amp;#8217;s London marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s good to escape the crowds and join the runners warming up on the road. The event will be fast, I know, with elite runners at the front pulling the train along; but as I jog round the sharp bends and up the hill out of the town centre, it&amp;#8217;s hard for me to figure out how so many manage a PB on such a challenging course so close to Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales football team manager Chris Coleman turns out to be the mystery runner. The torch is lit, fireworks explode, and now we&amp;#8217;re being asked to line up at the start. At most races I run, the start line self-organises: the faster runners warm up last then fill the space at the front which the slower runners have left for them. This event is different, and it takes much pushing and shouting to get everyone packed behind the start line before &amp;#8212; bang! &amp;#8212; we&amp;#8217;re off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I charge off like crazy both Eamonn and Nick are ahead of me. I&amp;#8217;ve never been so far down the field in a 5K. I settle on the short uphill then stride out on the way back down, listening to the feverish commentary. It&amp;#8217;s thrilling to run through the packed town centre, crowds cheering and applauding, and already the first of three laps is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eamonn has a huge gap but I catch Nick on the final uphill, which spurs him on to go back past me. My finishing time of 17:42 is the quickest I&amp;#8217;ve run this year, just. Later I learn the course record has been broken by Swansea Harrier Kristian Jones with a time of 14:11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/32985541345/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Nos Galan selfie&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2874/32985541345_babede2f41_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; alt=&quot;Nos Galan selfie&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/817288845/embed/2d0059f869f51a6937090cfa112aa17f3d073651&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/32170674643/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Swansea Harriers at Nos Galan&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/4/3940/32170674643_ea6094aca4_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Swansea Harriers at Nos Galan&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-12-31</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/nos-galan-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/nos-galan-2016</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Kenfig, West Glamorgan League, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The West Glamorgan cross country league visited Kenfig nature reserve for the first time this year. I was looking forward to both the race and to visiting somewhere new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shoe selection bothered me. Spikes were not an option on the multi-terrain course, but should I use my trail shoes (which feel clunky) or my light-weight racing shoes (barely any grip)? After warming up in both on the soft sandy trail I went for the trail shoes. I needed all the traction I could get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/quad-bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quad bike&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another first: the organisers led out the race on a quad bike. Runners did what they could to avoid the softest sand in the middle of the track, preferring to use the grassy verges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/31799491711/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Kenfig, West Glamorgan 3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/611/31799491711_402d531a5f_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;531&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;Kenfig, West Glamorgan 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about a mile of this pacy dodging and weaving &amp;#8212; stand back, dog walkers and spectators! &amp;#8212; we took a turn to the left onto a firmer track through common land. Cows ambled along to their own agenda, not bothered by the event. I passed Charles Walsh and Will Munday. I passed Eamonn. Once again I had Alan Davies for company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another left turn and we were on a short fast section of rough road, the wind on our backs. Alan strode out and I stayed with him. The counter-clockwise loop repeated, and wewere passing runners still on their first circuit. Now for the hard part, the final mile on soft sand back to the race finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I scanned the horizon for some sign of the Kenfig visitor centre but could see nothing but sand dunes. The pace felt so slow compared to the high energy start along the same track. I was exhausted but guessed others would feel the same way. Don&amp;#8217;t look back, press on. Alan pulled a slight gap and suddenly the finish was there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/31106772683/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Kenfig, West Glamorgan 3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/261/31106772683_32e194d88a_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;533&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;Kenfig, West Glamorgan 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westglamleague.co.uk/november-27th-2016/&quot;&gt;I came in 14th&lt;/a&gt;, one place behind Alan Davies, closely followed by Will Munday and Eamonn Kirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/787046923/embed/c986d9a761f20e6d133c4b1d25abdc85c2bed137&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-11-27</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/kenfig-west-glamorgan-league-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/kenfig-west-glamorgan-league-2016</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>British and Irish Masters International, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My two worst races in 2016 have been the two biggest. First, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/world-half-marathon-championships-2016&quot;&gt;the world half marathon championships in Cardiff&lt;/a&gt;, which I entered a year in advance. Second, the British and Irish Masters International, which I was selected to compete in just three weeks before it took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases catching a cold before the event blunted my performance. I struggled round the streets of Cardiff in atrocious conditions, finishing over three minutes down on the time I&amp;#8217;d hoped and trained for. The half marathon is a tough event and I can still remember the mounting pain I felt as I slogged through Roath with rain slicing across me. Happily, though, I&amp;#8217;d let noone down but myself. In Glasgow things were rather different. I had been selected for the Welsh team. It was a full weekend, involving flights, a hotel, dinner, an awards ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the hotel late on the Friday night to find some of the senior team members in the foyer nursing half pints and soft drinks. They were talking about how much slower runners were these days, apparently a discussion they have every year. Bernie Jones, the team manager, went to collect the vest I&amp;#8217;d ordered in advance. Unfortunately the small vests had been taken and the best he could do was a medium which came mid-way down my thighs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday, race day. I liked the look of the course: a grassy, undulating loop of Tolcross Park, soft in places but no standing water. There were team photographs by the rose garden. I warmed up, puffing and blowing, missing the usual spring in my legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eamonn had lent me one of his old vests, a small, so I at least looked the part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t go out hard. For the first two laps I ran with Royston Whitehouse and Alan Davies, two runners who I&amp;#8217;d taken a minute out of at Bridgend. Then I faded badly. I felt like I couldn&amp;#8217;t breathe. I had to rein my effort in and suffered the indignity of being an easy target for runners who had paced themselves better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30997229086/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Welsh master at Glasgow Tolcross Park&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5551/30997229086_9981eed75a_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Welsh master at Glasgow Tolcross Park&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst of it is that if it weren&amp;#8217;t for the cold, I was in great form. Oh, I&amp;#8217;m under no illusions, I was never going to challenge the leaders in my category, but I could at least have run to my full ability and scored for my team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call it a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/787044332/embed/b169a64d4b601f57073fec85ba5de6e8ab68e64d&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the V35-V50 race was a true education: I have &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; seen such fast cross country running. The Irish team smashed the course, tailing an unfortunate English hare for three high speed laps then flying round the final lap at full tilt to take the top three spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/31917320325/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Masters runners go international&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/379/31917320325_7eb93aca6d_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; alt=&quot;Masters runners go international&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-11-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/british-and-irish-masters-international-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/british-and-irish-masters-international-2016</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Newbridge Fields, Gwent League, 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Newbridge fields is closest to home of the Gwent League events and, since changing jobs at the end of August, it&amp;#8217;s even closer to where I work. During the weeks before the event I&amp;#8217;d reconoitred the course in my lunch break. It&amp;#8217;s a straightforward route, three flat laps around the boundary of the playing fields and back alongside the Ogmore, each finishing with a bridge crossing and a short switchback through a wooded meadow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late summer and early autumn have been dry, and even the meadow section wasn&amp;#8217;t bad underfoot as I warmed up. Yet again, no need for my spikes: I wore my light but grip-less racing flats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex&amp;#8217;s school friend, Nathan Jones, was in the Swansea Harriers tent near the race HQ. I&amp;#8217;ve been training with him on Tuesday evenings and it was no surprise to see the Welsh gold medal hanging round his neck. Unfortuntely I arrived too late to see his race. Apparently he&amp;#8217;d been disappointed to finish a close second, losing out to an English runner &amp;#8212; at least he has someone to aim for in the next fixture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well over 400 runners lined up at the start of the men&amp;#8217;s event. I positioned myself as close to the front as I dared, not wanting to get stuck in a queue around the first corner. We were off, surging forwards at speed. I held my position, using elbows and hands to make space for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/30255086442&quot; title=&quot;Attacking the slope&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5524/30255086442_1f72b4b3d1_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; alt=&quot;Attacking the slope&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into the technical meadow section at the end of the first lap, I was running well. My shoes had barely any grip in the mud, and I would have to rely on momentum and foot placement to carry me up the two short climbs. A Bristol University runner fell, got up, slipped over again; somehow I kept going and passed him. Spike- and stud-less I took no chances on the soft downhill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to hold my pace in the second lap. My starting speed had put me ahead of several runners who would normally be in front of me. I wanted to stay clear of them. Coming into the race, the first of this season&amp;#8217;s league, I knew my form was good. It was the West Wales championships. I had also been told that the selectors would have their eye on the results; a strong performance here would put me in contention for a place on the Welsh team at the masters international in Glasgow. So, some motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into the third lap now and I picked up my pace again. I recognised the runner ahead, Alex Hamblin, Westbury Harriers. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/blaise-blazer-2016&quot;&gt;Last time I saw him&lt;/a&gt; he had finished maybe 10m ahead of me in torrid conditions at the Blaise Blazer. Today, on a longer and flatter course, I was catching him. I passed him before the bridge. I passed two or three others too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dropped a couple of places in the final meadow section &amp;#8212; others were attacking the finish of the race, and I was unwilling to take risks in my slippery shoes. I sprinted with what little I had left for the line. I collected my position token and, as ever, a letter from Hedydd Davies iniviting me to represent West Wales in the inter-regional championships. The next two Swansea Harriers to finish were Eamonn and Ifan, two strong veteran runners who
normally leave me trailing by some distance: confirmation I&amp;#8217;d run well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/746820988/embed/0a162d40f39891a1254f6a5ff1e9213e89f7124e&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2016/sm161i.htm&quot;&gt;The results&lt;/a&gt; were published later that week confirming I&amp;#8217;d finished 74th out of 468 with a time of 38.27. Even better, I got a message from Bernie Jones, the Welsh Masters team manager. I&amp;#8217;d been selected to run for Wales at the home cross country international in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-10-16</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/newbridge-fields-gwent-league-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/newbridge-fields-gwent-league-2016</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Port Talbot Half Marathon 2016</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I suffered at the world half marathon championships held in Cardiff earlier in the year. I&amp;#8217;d put in the training but failed to shake off a heavy cold by race day, besides which the weather was foul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inaugural Port Talbot half marathon offered a chance to bury that memory. A small, local event with an entry limit of 200 people, staged on grit and tarmac cycle tracks in the beautiful forest of Afan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/28545281733/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Port Talbot Half Marathon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8073/28545281733_4b8fc4d06b_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; alt=&quot;Port Talbot Half Marathon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a technical opening section though width restrictions and around a fishing lake, we were on a firm gravel track heading gently downhill, and that&amp;#8217;s pretty much how it continued for the next 6 miles. The weather was cool, with a light breeze, the sun occasionally threatening to break through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself shoulder to shoulder with Gareth Poston. We worked together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We&amp;#8217;re not catching them,&amp;#8221; I said, meaning the group of 4 about 200m ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Wait for the uphill,&amp;#8221; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/28542441614/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Port Talbot Half Marathon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8507/28542441614_97eee290ff_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Port Talbot Half Marathon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt dehydrated and made sure I got some water in at the feed station at the turning point. Gareth pulled a lead on me, maybe as much as 20m, but I wasn&amp;#8217;t going to lose him. The track was heading uphill now. The next groups of runners were entering the feedzone. Time to dig in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught up with Gareth and again we worked together. A runner in a red vest, dropped from the fractured group of 4, was in sight. We went past him. Just a couple of miles from the finish we caught and passed another runner. Now I was hurting. Gareth pulled ahead. This time I let him go. I could see he was fading but I was too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished in 6th place with a time of 1:22:33, which I was pleased with on a sloping course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/29130788846/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Port Talbot Half Marathon&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8001/29130788846_4fbb734796_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Port Talbot Half Marathon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-08-21</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/port-talbot-half-marathon-2016</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/port-talbot-half-marathon-2016</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Rise and Fall of Trail Running</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;During the Christmas break I went on a long, slow run from home, through Stembridge to Llanmadoc, heading back via Burry. The weather was unseasonably mild. After several days of rain, the going was heavy. Cresting Llanmadoc hill, 4 miles in, after a steep, slippery climb, the view opened out: far ahead, Black Mountain and the Brecon Beacons, the salt marsh to my left, its maze of waterways reflecting the pale light; then Whitford Sands, the green smudge of pine trees, the cast-iron lighthouse pinned against the Loughor estuary. The glow that comes with exercising outside spread through my body. Not long ago I had been picking my way through the marshy lowland and now I was up here. I had earned my view of this landscape. Covered in mud, I was part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The award winning Stormy Castle&quot; href=&quot;https://www.architecture.com/StirlingPrize/Awards2014/Wales/StormyCastle.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/stormy-castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stormy Castle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahead of me stood an isolated building, plate glass windows, granite walls, rusting iron, concrete. My route skirted the perimeter joining the track which provided vehicle access. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.architecture.com/StirlingPrize/Awards2014/Wales/StormyCastle.aspx&quot;&gt;Stormy Castle&lt;/a&gt;, the nameplate read, gold on slate. Separate from the main building was what looked like a shed. Originally for livestock maybe? This too had grey stone walls; inset in the north wall was a floor-to-ceiling window. Looking in, I saw, placed in front of the window, a treadmill. Whoever inhabits Stormy Castle enjoys a gym with a view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madness, I thought. Why run on the spot in this fish tank when you could be outside? Don&amp;#8217;t peer at the view, engage with it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/heatheronhertravels/2479530671/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Abbots Pool, Bristol, Lake, Pond,&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3008/2479530671_55f30d3244_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;Abbots Pool, Bristol, Lake, Pond,&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next week, back at work again in Bristol, I went on my regular long run, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/388964204&quot;&gt;Abbots Pool Loop&lt;/a&gt;. St Mary Redcliffe&amp;#8217;s bell rang seven times as I passed through Queen Square. Usually I&amp;#8217;d hook up with one or more running friends here. Today, on a cloudy morning, 80 minutes before sunrise, I was on my own. I had no head torch. I ran through Millenium Square and along the harbour, negotiating steps and bridges to cross the harbour and river at Cumberland Basin. Soon I would be out of the city. My feet slipped as I left the access road to Ashton Court, the point where trail began. Road shoes which had been ideal for the pavements so far were now a liability. To my right I could just see the dark silhouettes of the red deer herd at rest. I could smell their damp, musky smell. At the northern boundary of the estate I crossed Beggars Bush Lane to continue along the farm track opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uneven ground, downhill, too fast, a cross-slope. My left foot slid underneath me and I instantly knew I could not recover, and that the stony ground was going to hurt when I struck it. In those few airborne milliseconds I also had time to reflect this was a bad place for this to happen: on my own, without a phone, about as far from civilisation as you can get by running 40 minutes from the city centre. I fell forwards full length, somehow turning in the air to take the impact on my left elbow and the back of my shoulder. The mud which precipitated my fall also mitigated its effects. I slid rather than scraped. Head and face untouched. Wrists and hands OK. Legs fine. Elbow hurting and bloody, but that was the worst of it. I&amp;#8217;d been lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I&amp;#8217;m not going to run on a treadmill, not even when it&amp;#8217;s dark and muddy. Especially not when it&amp;#8217;s dark and muddy. I&amp;#8217;ve tried head torches and they spoil my night vision. Have you run past Abbots Pool at dawn? Have you splashed through puddles on the towpath as the sun rises to colour in the Avon Gorge? You should. But I should be more careful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/388964204/embed/0903f50418446bf277f6e9531f55638a30c3a6ea&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heatheronhertravels.com/&quot;&gt;Heather Cowper&lt;/a&gt; for the photo of Abbots Pool, as seen in daylight, on a dry day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2016-01-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rise-and-fall-of-trail-running</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/the-rise-and-fall-of-trail-running</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Jess Coulson, British half-marathon champion</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Strangely I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten the pain suffered in the final miles of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races&quot;&gt;Cardiff half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. What pain? I&amp;#8217;ll run it again and get the PB I missed by 10 seconds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the event I caught up with the coverage on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bbc.in/1M9iTp2&quot;&gt;iplayer&lt;/a&gt;. I knew the headlines &amp;#8212; that Kenyan athletes had won both the men&amp;#8217;s and women&amp;#8217;s race &amp;#8212; but didn&amp;#8217;t know how. Both races turned out to be fascinating and thrilling to watch, the women&amp;#8217;s race especially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed the race would follow a standard script with the leader, Jerotich, ratcheting the pressure until she dropped her rivals, and then holding on. Soon after 10K a winning margin was established. The commentators were struggling to find anything to say. The kilometers ticked down. Jerotich runs with that efficient style the top endurance runners employ; quick, shuffling strides, feet barely clearing the tarmac. As a spectator you can sense the long hard miles of training and the long hard miles to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bbc.in/1M9iTp2&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/jerotich-areba-coulson.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jerotich areba coulson&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live coverage returned to the women&amp;#8217;s race coming along the straight road back from Roath. The winning margin remained in place, though it hadn&amp;#8217;t extended. Jerotich was frowning. What the commentators failed to notice was a yellow vest in the background. It could, of course, have been an elite male runner making a late surge, but the mystery athlete&amp;#8217;s hair was gathered into a swaying top-knot. Now the cameras went back to her. It&amp;#8217;s Rebecca Robinson, said the commentators, wrongly. It was Jess Coulson making her competitive half marathon debut and she was motoring, bouncing off her toes, eating the gap to the second runner, Areba. Wasteful, the commentators tutted, arms flapping all over the place. Maybe, but fast, gutsy and exciting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jess Coulson&amp;#8217;s effort brought the race back together. With 400m to go, suddenly three runners were in it. If Coulson wanted second place she may have struck a fraction early, passing Areba on the final left hander &amp;#8212; but she wanted first. It wasn&amp;#8217;t to be. Jerotich had something left and held on for the win; Areba came back for second; Coulson got third. Great race!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/jess-coulson-british-halfmarathon-champion</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/jess-coulson-british-halfmarathon-champion</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>One week, three races</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I DNF the Cardiff half marathon. This year I went one worse and DNS the Swansea half. Consequently I was determined to turn up in good shape to complete this year&amp;#8217;s Cardiff half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racing the week before probably wasn&amp;#8217;t a great idea &amp;#8230; but the race happened to be a short one and close to home &amp;#8230; and the weather was perfect &amp;#8230; and I hadn&amp;#8217;t raced in a while &amp;#8230; and Alex didn&amp;#8217;t have a rugby game and &amp;#8230; well, I went! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Llandmadoc is the first fixture of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk&quot;&gt;West Glamorgan cross country league&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s four and a half miles, out along a woodland trail then back on the beach. I tried to run within myself on the outward section and fell in with Peter Osborne, another V50 who I&amp;#8217;ve battled with on several occasions. He upped the pace as we hit the sloping sand around the point and then he was gone. Coming back along the beach in the blazing sun, there was a gap of 50m to the next group of runners &amp;#8212; a gap I reduced but never closed. Despite my conservative start, when we went through the wet sand I felt as energetic as one of the many stranded jellyfish which littered the course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=147384&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Llanmadoc&amp;amp;date=27-Sep-15&quot;&gt;finished 19th in a time of 28:32&lt;/a&gt;, officially first in my category but second really since Peter beat me and he&amp;#8217;s an age band up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21803789231/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5722/21803789231_138ac20159_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Me and Raul at the finish, Llanmadoc XC&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I avoided the track training session with Bristol and West on Monday evening &amp;#8212; the same session, last year, had been one too many. If I&amp;#8217;d had doubts about running the cross country race just a week before the half marathon, my main target for the year, then I had real concerns about testing myself at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bristolandwestac.org/aztec-west-fast-5k/&quot;&gt;Aztec West 5K&lt;/a&gt; on the Tuesday. I felt I was running well and knew a PB was possible on the fast Aztec West course, but did I want to know just how well I was running? A slow time would have rocked my confidence before Sunday&amp;#8217;s longer race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I went. As for times, I had no idea during the race because I forgot my watch. In contrast to Llanmadoc, my legs felt strong, decidedly sprightly in fact. I settled in with Will Smith and Paul Deaton, friends from Southville Running Club, and we barreled round the three lap course, overtaking some very decent runners who&amp;#8217;d started more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21875414812/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;SRC at Aztec West 5k&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5816/21875414812_10a39d89f2_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; alt=&quot;SRC at Aztec West 5k&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21264629634/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;SRC at Aztec West 5k&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/569/21264629634_b53ab1d8aa_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;SRC at Aztec West 5k&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will accelerated with 200m to go, attacking the next three runners, and Paul went with him. I let them go. After the final sharp left, Paul faded, enough encouragement for me to sprint past him. When the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=146231&amp;amp;event=5K&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=29-Sep-15&quot;&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; were announced I discovered I&amp;#8217;d won the V50 category with a PB of 17:22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21861865806/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Aztec West 5K. Charge for the line&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/728/21861865806_aa925a0096_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;Charge for the line&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Cardiff. The race is bigger than ever &amp;#8212; twenty two thousand entrants in 2015. Despite this, it was straightforward getting to the start line warmed up and ready. The elite athletes (including me!) have their own baggage drop round the back of the castle in Bute Park. From there, it&amp;#8217;s a short stroll to the right start pen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;https://www.strava.com/activities/406748447/embed/9e8c528271c129e91657b724a243c43d982c9342&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t think I set off too quickly but my 10K time was 37:10, on target for a 78:30 finish. I guess my legs were still dialled into my 5K pace. Ifan had set out even more quickly, but I caught him around the half way point. In a half marathon I usually feel a glow during the middle of the event; the sensation that I&amp;#8217;m going fast, but at a sustainable tempo. This time, the sensation never came. I wasn&amp;#8217;t glowing, I was aching. Enduring. Maintaining a steady pace seemed impossible and I found myself repeatedly dropping then being passed by the same group of runners. Why couldn&amp;#8217;t we team up and work together? I went through 10 miles in 1:00:25, still on course for a personal best but hurting badly. Ifan went past me again at around mile 11. I didn&amp;#8217;t even try and go with him. My muscles were sore, my feet were sore. I knew I&amp;#8217;d complete the course but I was no longer shooting for a personal best; I just wanted to finish without losing too much time. Actually, I just wanted to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the final turn I realised that 80 minutes was still on and managed to sprint for the line. My time, 79:43, was just 7 seconds off my PB.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/one-week-three-races</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Swansea half, aftermath</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014&quot;&gt;Clocking a sub-80 half marathon at Swansea&lt;/a&gt; was my finest running performance in 2014. Things were bound to cool off after that.  Just four days later I showed up for the Purdown Pursuit, the final event of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php&quot;&gt;Tach summer series&lt;/a&gt;. The race started late and required re-routing; it was a sweltering evening and there&amp;#8217;d been a fire on the course. I took the downhill sections cautiously on sore legs but still managed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=PP_result14.inc&quot;&gt;4th place with a time of 42.39&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks later I finished 5th at the Blaise Blazer mob match. It&amp;#8217;s one of my favourite races and I set a personal best for the course of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runbritainrankings.com/results/results.aspx?meetingid=106696&amp;amp;event=4MMT&amp;amp;venue=Bristol&amp;amp;date=4-Aug-14&quot;&gt;23.51&lt;/a&gt;, picking runners off steadily in the final stages then holding on in the final sprint from the top of the steps to the folly. Southville RC put on a spirited defence of the team prize we&amp;#8217;d won the year before and, once the results had been counted and checked, to our surprise, it was announced we&amp;#8217;d retained the trophy. Later that evening after a recount the results were corrected; Westbury Harriers had, in fact, wrested the coveted Blazer Cup from our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mistake was not resting up over the summer. I wanted to go under 80 minutes for a second time at the Cardiff half marathon, a far more established and prestigious event than the one I&amp;#8217;d run in Swansea, and one at which friends from both Bristol and South Wales would compete. On the Monday before the race I tweaked my hamstring towards the end of a track session with Bristol &amp;amp; West at Whitehall. Not good. During the remainder of the week I rested before lining up on Sunday in Cardiff ready to race. I stormed the first mile in 5:40, hit a similar pace for the second, and then felt the injury ping. I pulled up and walked along the pavement, assessing the damage. I figured I could at least jog around the barrage to the Senedd but I couldn&amp;#8217;t. Instead I ended up limping from Pennarth to the centre, reaching the baggage collection around the time I should have been finishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21815444008/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Masters XC 2015 by Alex Williams&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/644/21815444008_6cf2fe1c90_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Masters XC 2015 by Alex Williams&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t race again until the combined Welsh Inter-regional and Welsh Masters cross country championships. This is a proper cross-country course featuring mud, meadows, woodland tracks, slopes. The weather played its part: rain during the week and freezing temperatures on the day filled the puddles with ice; grass sparkled with frost as the sun broke through. I ran a measured race ending up with an individual &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepowerof10.info/results/results.aspx?meetingid=118689&amp;amp;event=ZXC&amp;amp;venue=Builth+Wells&amp;amp;date=13-Dec-14&quot;&gt;silver in the MV50&lt;/a&gt; category just two seconds behind Peter Coles, the category winner. I &lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt; get a gold medal as one of Swansea Harriers&amp;#8217; winning MV50 team. In the inter-regional competition, we came second, I think. There are so many competitions being run in the same race it&amp;#8217;s hard to remember. What I do remember thinking is, what a shame such a great event gets such a low turnout. In an age where people part with serious money to tackle military-themed tough guy obstacle courses, for just a couple of quid you get to represent club and region on a challenging course in a fabulous setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/21382218343/in/dateposted-friend/&quot; title=&quot;Welsh Masters XC 2014, Swansea Harriers gold medal V50 team&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5661/21382218343_9716029e5c_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Welsh Masters XC 2014, Swansea Harriers gold medal V50 team&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moustache, by the way, was for movember&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2015-10-07</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-aftermath</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-aftermath</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>1st Ever Swansea Half Marathon</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14765094316&quot; title=&quot;Crossing the Tawe by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3890/14765094316_26248cf75f_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;532&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;Crossing the Tawe&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, a half marathon is a race against the clock, a notoriously ruthless opponent, and since the city halves are fast, flat and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.walesonline.co.uk/news/wales-news/cardiff-half-marathon-too-short-1892034&quot;&gt;accurately measured&lt;/a&gt;, you can compare your time in Cardiff to your time in Bristol, or your time in Cardiff to Neil&amp;#8217;s time in Brighton or Matt&amp;#8217;s time in Bath. There&amp;#8217;s nowhere to hide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that&amp;#8217;s whay I prefer trail and cross country, where conditions and tactics seem more important than minutes and seconds. For a half marathon conditions are either suitable for a PB or unsuitable, and there&amp;#8217;s just one tactic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run an even pace, or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t go out too fast, or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t slow down, or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep going, for, in my case, 80 minutes-ish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but the -ish matters! My personal best of 1:21:30, Cardiff 2011, the last time I ran a half, was 90 seconds over. At the start of this year, 2014, I decided to do something about that. I&amp;#8217;d return to Cardiff and I&amp;#8217;d try and go under 80 minutes. Effectively, I&amp;#8217;d have to cover a distance which previously took me 60 seconds in just under 59 seconds, and I&amp;#8217;d have to repeat that record breaking performance 81 and a half times in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a calculated task requires planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=/images/fr10.png alt=&quot;Forerunner 10&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assist me in my race against time I&amp;#8217;ve been using a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garmin.com/uk/forerunner10&quot;&gt;Garmin Forerunner 10&lt;/a&gt;, a device which is not so much a watch as a tagging device: it knows where I am, and when, how fast I&amp;#8217;m going, how fast I&amp;#8217;m supposed to be going, and it can recall this information for subsequent analysis. As well as the Garmin, I devised a training routine which includes an extended early morning run. Once a week I meet anyone prepared to join me for 90 minutes in a session which culminates &amp;#8212; 10 miles in and after a couple of hills &amp;#8212; with 2 miles run at tempo. The idea is to build stamina and to get used to running on weary legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;http://www.strava.com/activities/118158286/embed/9f3f903672f26c3370c7f5d9871a9b7b8dce46ea&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plans to race the clock in Cardiff in October were brought forward in April when the word got out that this year, for the first time ever, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseahalfmarathon.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Swansea would be hosting a half marathon&lt;/a&gt;. The date had been set for July 20th, meaning I&amp;#8217;d have time to prepare, and &amp;#8212; if the race didn&amp;#8217;t go well &amp;#8212; time to regroup and reset my strategy for Cardiff. I signed up sharpish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601322910&quot; title=&quot;And they&amp;#x27;re off by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3850/14601322910_32c1418472_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;And they&amp;#x27;re off&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. July 20th. Race day. Start time, 08:30. With entries limited to 2000 the race was a sell out and when I arrived, with an hour to go, the runners&amp;#8217; village &amp;#8212; the patch of grass filling the gaps between the museums and the LC2 &amp;#8212; the village was buzzing. I saw Rob Falconer stretching before the race. I jogged a slow loop to the sea front and back around the marina, briefly hooking up with Steve Smith. Gary Irving, marshalling for the day, was stationed on the path in front of the Marriott with a group of cadets at what would be mile 10. It&amp;#8217;s tough going from here, he warned me. The path narrows and there are lots of twists and turns. Could be nasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last swig of water. Isobel had come to support me and I knew Dan would be down too. I walked to the start line with Eamonn. Being near the front could only help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601319720&quot; title=&quot;Paper shower by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2919/14601319720_4bb6df2ab3_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Paper shower&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first three miles along Oystermouth Road I ran alongside Raul. At each mile my Garmin bleeped and displayed a lap time. I was hitting 6 minute miling. That would do it. Coming through Blackpill I got a cheer from Simon Beer. The crowds thickened in Mumbles. My race number had my name on it and I was wearing my Swansea Harriers club vest which meant I got lots of local and personalised support. There was Iain standing on the pavement. Raul had dropped back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14784837161&quot; title=&quot;I ran with the chap in the blue vest for a while by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2899/14784837161_484aeb60bd_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;534&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;I ran with the chap in the blue vest for a while&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached the turning point, Verdis, Knab Rock, alongside a bearded runner in a light blue vest. 5 miles, flat, only one turn, barely any wind and the sun had yet to burn through the mist. I pushed on and caught another Swansea Harrier, Adam. We worked together for a couple of miles. Past the half way stage now and I was flying. Mile 8 felt like the fastest yet. Adam had fallen back. The next runner, some way ahead, also wore a Swansea Harriers vest. Surely not Eamonn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14787650752&quot; title=&quot;Mile 7 or 8, I think by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5560/14787650752_2cf87b226f_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;Mile 7 or 8, I think&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through 10 miles in 60:06. It was Eamonn! We were running through searing July sunshine. I no longer felt light on my feet. I focused on how I&amp;#8217;d felt running along the towpath, how I&amp;#8217;d held my pace when my legs were screaming. As Gary had warned, the path narrowed and swerved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14788100175&quot; title=&quot;Tawe pedestrian bridge by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5558/14788100175_ed51358c7f_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;532&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;Tawe pedestrian bridge&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see runners ahead crossing the bridge over the mouth of the Tawe, zig-zagging through the development zone on the other side of the river. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to have to think about which way to go! I slowed into the bends and accelerated wearily out of them, forcing myself back up to speed. I was still catching runners who&amp;#8217;d been ahead of me for the past hour or so. On the last cruel switchback just before crossing the Tawe for the second time, on the Sail Bridge, I saw Eamonn. All the way, Tom, push for the line, he shouted. I saw Alan Davies and wondered why he wasn&amp;#8217;t running. There was Dan, my brother. There were Isobel and Cai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14601482137&quot; title=&quot;Last push. Breathless by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3908/14601482137_77ca790d44_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;Last push. Breathless&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/14785631184&quot; title=&quot;Stop the Garmin by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5588/14785631184_7bc9038117_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; alt=&quot;Stop the Garmin&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What time? I didn&amp;#8217;t know. I didn&amp;#8217;t see the usual race clock on the line. I gulped in air and watched the next few runners finish. I gave Isobel a hug. Eamonn came in, then Kneath. At last I checked my watch. 1:19:36. I had gone under 80 minutes by a few &amp;#8212; several! &amp;#8212; precious seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&#x27;405&#x27; width=&#x27;590&#x27; frameborder=&#x27;0&#x27; allowtransparency=&#x27;true&#x27; scrolling=&#x27;no&#x27; src=&#x27;http://www.strava.com/activities/168338222/embed/c796f64e8214972efd71284322744a78413ce144&#x27;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the official results were published I was credited with a gun time of 1:19:38 and a chip time of 1:19:36. Racing the clock turned out to be a great tactic for placing well: I finished 10th overall, having been 15th at the half-way point, and I came first in my age category. My prize, apparently, is to be a new running watch. It&amp;#8217;s late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dirtygreentrainers.com/&quot;&gt;Dirty Green Trainers&lt;/a&gt; sports photographers for the images used on this page, and for permission to publish them here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-07-22</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/swansea-half-2014</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>110th Welsh Cross Country championships, Llandeilo</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Blame the wind, which started before Christmas and still hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped. Or the rain, which had been similarly persistent, flooding roads, train lines, villages and fields. I guess even the toughest
runners may have thought twice about showing up for another mudfest, even if this one was the Welsh championships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, you can only compete against those who turn up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked up, as instructed, on the outskirts of the Dinefwr estate, and caught the shuttle bus to the event. A massive tree, toppled by the recent storms, lay on the grass, its roots pointing upwards. The racing had already started: junior runners picked their way through the mud. I collected my number from the race HQ in front of Newton House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Davis, the commentator said, was hot favourite for the U13 boys&amp;#8217; event. You can tell it&amp;#8217;s Luke Davies, he said, because of his socks: one pink, one green. If Luke Davies felt the pressure of expectation, he responded well to it, taking an early lead and extending it all the way to the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain held off. The wind was strong but no gale. The senior event would be four times round a rolling, heavy, lovely course. I ran one as a warm up with Kneath, Eamonn, Raul and Martin. Dewi Griffiths, defending champion, was here, and although I&amp;#8217;d be on his team, I didn&amp;#8217;t want him lapping me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=582349755166585&amp;amp;set=a.582349438499950.1073741898.100001746967305&quot;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt;, taken by Gwynfor James.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great day for Swansea Harriers! Here&amp;#8217;s a snippet from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.swanseaharriers.co.uk/content/results-round-usa-llandeilo-cardiff-birmingham-brecon&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on the club&amp;#8217;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;#8230;] arguably the main highlight of the day showing the talent and strength in depth of the senior mens team, saw the B team win team SILVER, just, by a point! The SILVER winning team were Eamon Kirk (14th), Lewys Hobbs (16th), &lt;strong&gt;Thomas Guest&lt;/strong&gt; (21st) Matthew Richards (22nd), Raul Reismann (30th) and Kneath Philippart (35th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/12566784253&quot; title=&quot;Swansea harriers, Welsh cross country champions! by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3789/12566784253_843bb33ed4_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Swansea harriers, Welsh cross country champions!&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2014-02-15</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/110th-welsh-cross-country-championships-llandeilo</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/110th-welsh-cross-country-championships-llandeilo</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh Inter-Regional &amp; Masters XC Champs, 2013</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The cross country course at Builth Wells ticks all the boxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hills &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mud &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scenery &amp;#10003;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They even threw in a log jump (&amp;#10003;) this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;ve adjusted the course since I last ran it. If anything, it&amp;#8217;s better. What used to be a steady climb has been reversed, becoming a fast and treacherous descent, which you&amp;#8217;ll have to undertake on wobbly legs after a woodland ascent through ditches and streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day, as a representative of West Wales in the inter-regional championships, I was running in a red and black vest. Since the race included the Welsh Masters cross country championships, I was also running for Swansea Harriers, and &amp;#8212; for the first time ever &amp;#8212; running in the V50 category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rare combination gave me several chances so I struck out at a sharp pace, stretching my legs on the rolling prelude, and &amp;#8212; to my surprise &amp;#8212; found myself just behind Peter Coles, last year&amp;#8217;s V50 winner, on the first downhill. I passed him at speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/11455697276/&quot; title=&quot;2013 Welsh Inter-Regional Cross Country championships, Builth Wells by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2821/11455697276_658bec0be9_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;530&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;2013 Welsh Inter-Regional Cross Country championships, Builth Wells&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe if I&amp;#8217;d paced myself better I could have finished in the top 10. Maybe not. In the end &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/files/welsh-interregional-xc-2013.pdf&quot;&gt;I came 12th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/11407194815/&quot; title=&quot;Welsh masters cross country by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7296/11407194815_afb2369075_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Welsh masters cross country&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won a bronze medal in the masters V50 category, coming around minute behind V50 winner Ifan Lloyd and just 20 seconds behind Peter Coles. West Wales were the winning V50 team and Swansea Harriers were the winning V50 club.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-12-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-interregional-amp-masters-xc-champs-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-interregional-amp-masters-xc-champs-2013</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bargain!</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a member so I had to fork out a 50% premium to enter. For &amp;pound;6 I got:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a cup of tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a toasted tea-cake (help yourself to butter and jam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a route description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a protective cover for the route description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a brevet card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two cups of squash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a chocolate flapjack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aukweb.net/events/detail/13-408/#more&quot;&gt;100km of cycling&lt;/a&gt;, to include 2400m of climbing and some of the finest scenery in south Wales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another cup of tea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a ham roll (help yourself to salad)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9713256358/&quot; title=&quot;Carreg Cennen by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5330/9713256358_5d3a60a6b6_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Carreg Cennen&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-09-11</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bargain</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/bargain</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh castles relay 2013, the Drovers Armsless leg</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/wcr-stage14-profile.png&quot; alt=&quot;WCR stage 14 profile&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I heard Matt Burns would represent Southville Running Club on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/stage-14/&quot;&gt;Drovers Arms leg&lt;/a&gt; of the Welsh Castles Relay, the race&amp;#8217;s queen stage, I had to ask Gary, the Swansea Harriers team manager, if I could run it too. He warned me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stage 14 is a nightmare, the road zigzags up the mountain, not for the fainthearted!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zigzags and mountains don&amp;#8217;t scare me. What does scare me is bright sunshine and that&amp;#8217;s what we had on Sunday. I slathered on sunscreen and lurked in the shadows in sunglasses waiting for the stage to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confusion at the briefing.  An illegal rave at the top of the mountain: police had closed the road. We&amp;#8217;ll finish the stage a mile early, the race official said. We&amp;#8217;ll see what we can do. We&amp;#8217;ll try and get you through. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, there&amp;#8217;d been talk of a vintage car rally coming down the mountain at the same time as we we ran up it. No rally, apparently; instead, a rave. I guess anyone holding a 20 stage road race over a summer weekend has to think on their feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off. I settled into a steady pace. There&amp;#8217;d be plenty of opportunity to burn energy later. The rolling route left Builth Wells on the A483 heading west, hills rising ominously to the south. Supporters offered wet sponges and water. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Garth we turned and ducked under the railway line and then the climb started. I was passing runners now. For the first time I could see Matt, not so far ahead of me. At the side of the road a sun-burned and dreadlocked girl huddled against the crash barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary had warned me about the false summit. You get to the top and then you&amp;#8217;ve another couple of miles to go. Except today we hadn&amp;#8217;t and there, at the top of the first climb, suddenly, was the finish line. Oh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/9020573242/&quot; title=&quot;WCR 2013 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2834/9020573242_1fd3662ee2_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;WCR 2013&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The views were spectacular. I felt uncomfortably fresh, especially considering I&amp;#8217;d just run the best part of nine miles the last two which had been uphill. We set off to follow the next two stages of the race. Rob had the top of his BMW down. It took a few tense minutes to negotiate the road past the Drovers, reduced to a single lane by vehicles on the verges. Team vans were trying to head in both directions as the music throbbed and pulsed and ravers staggered around in the sunshone. Down the hill the police were methodically pulling over and questioning people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a period of several minutes on the run into Brecon we overtook the stage 15 runners. Mark Roberts, one of Swansea&amp;#8217;s finest, was near the front; ahead of him some seriously good athletes from Altringham, Port Talbot, Les Croupiers, Hare and Hounds tore up the road. On the way out of Brecon we passed by stage 16, the mountain stage &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html&quot;&gt;I&amp;#8217;d run in filthy weather two years earlier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/n6-3dYvcEeE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swansea Harriers were 11th overall, 2nd in the vets category just 16 minutes behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lescroupierswcr.org/storage/wcr-2013/team%20bath%20newsletter.pdf&quot; title=&quot;The Bath Plug - a great read&quot;&gt;Bath&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s the fastest time we&amp;#8217;ve completed the route in for some years. Thanks to Rob Falconer for providing a lift, the photo, and for putting in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6-3dYvcEeE&quot;&gt;a storming run on stage 13&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks again to Gary Irving: as manager of a veterans&amp;#8217; team I think he accepts and expects a few injuries will upset his plans, but four people pulling out in the final week, that&amp;#8217;s tough!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-06-13</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2013</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2013</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>2012-2013 Cross Country season and some</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I recorded some of my race results since the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012.html&quot;&gt;WCR, 2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next race was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwent-league.org.uk&quot;&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt; opener at Newbridge Fields, Bridgend. I ran this same course the year before on a cold, blustery day, sheets of rain swirling. This time, the weather turned out unseasonably warm. I came &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm121i.htm&quot;&gt;78th with a time of 38:22&lt;/a&gt;, an improvement of 26 places and 3 minutes over my previous outing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/4531393735/&quot; title=&quot;Whiteford Sands lighthouse by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2772/4531393735_eba09f0864.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; alt=&quot;Whiteford Sands lighthouse&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after I ran closer to home in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html&quot;&gt;West Glamorgan League at Llanmadoc&lt;/a&gt;. Although the rain held off on the day, it hadn&amp;#8217;t over the past weeks and the track out to the lighthouse comprised a series of ponds linked by mud. I made a mistake lining up for the start some way from the front of the field and ended up jostled and sodden by the time the race stretched out and settled in. After, I hooked up with Ifan for a warm down; we ran the full route a second time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk/3.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk/resources/_wsb_417x374_West+Glam+League+at+Llanmadoc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;puddles&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaise Castle, Bristol, for the 3rd fixture in the Gwent League. Isobel and Alex ran too. I tried to keep up with Eamon but he pulled away on the second lap. In the closing stages I looked over my shoulder to see Raul storming towards me. I had enough left, or he timed his surge for the line too late; either way I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwent-league.org.uk/2012/sm123i.htm&quot;&gt;finished ahead of him&lt;/a&gt;, but I can&amp;#8217;t see that happening next time we race together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was it, my cross country season over. I was supposed to run the Welsh regional cross country championships but didn&amp;#8217;t make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of January this year I ran the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bristolandwestac.org/bridge-inn-5k&quot;&gt;Bridge Inn 5K&lt;/a&gt; on a very windy night and did well to finish &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/file/d/0BzIFRjtRS2vBVkE3b1dWV0RrUUU/edit&quot;&gt;a few seconds&lt;/a&gt; before Matt Burns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I ran the first of four alliterative &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tach.org.uk/races.php&quot;&gt;TACH races&lt;/a&gt;, the Wrington Woodland run, which I thoroughly enjoyed. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/v2/181608257/218757&quot;&gt;course&lt;/a&gt; started in Cleeve with a long but gradual climb up a woodland track. After a few dry weeks the surface was rocky and rutted. Matt (who I beat in the 5K, remember?) strode ahead a few minutes in, clocking a pace I couldn&amp;#8217;t follow; and, as it turned out, noone else could either. As we crested the top of the climb Andy overtook me. On the descent to Wrington another runner bounded past. I wasn&amp;#8217;t feeling too fresh by Bullnose Lane, the second uphill section, and settled on trying to hold my place rather than catch anyone. Even that proved optimistic and a couple of runners pegged me back before the final descent back to Cleeve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tach.org.uk/result.php?race=wrington_result13.inc&quot;&gt;9th place&lt;/a&gt;. Congratulations to Matt on his well deserved win! A diet of interval training and competitive racing have honed his form and after a series of top ten placings in recent events it came down to when not if.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.southvillerunningclub.co.uk&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.srcbristol.hostoi.com/images/sidebar/bristol_running_club_matt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Burnsy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2013-04-26</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/20122013-cross-country-season-and-some</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Welsh castles relay 2012, 14 seconds and 30 years apart</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/wcr-stage19-profile.png&quot; alt=&quot;WCR stage 19 profile&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2011.html&quot;&gt;I ran a mountain stage&lt;/a&gt; through heavy rain and into the wind. This year I ran a flat stage, well, flat for Wales, and &amp;#8212; despite news reports of flooding and dams bursting &amp;#8212; the weather was just fine: overcast, a light wind, not too hot. We gathered in Navigation Park, Abercynon, just off the A470. For &amp;#8220;park&amp;#8221; read &amp;#8220;industrial estate&amp;#8221;. After waiting a few minutes after the scheduled start time of 14:25 for the Turner Broadcasting runner to (not) appear, we were off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/7371400078/&quot; title=&quot;Stage 19 of 2012 Welsh castles relay by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5453/7371400078_d53029aa40_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;Stage 19 of 2012 Welsh castles relay&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The route climbed over the A470 and curved around to point south. After the usual initial shakeout the race settled down and I could see 7 runners ahead of me; within distance, but ahead. After a brief diversion through the Rhydfelin Housing estate we hit the Taff Trail. I&amp;#8217;d been here before, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cycling-the-celtic-trail.html&quot;&gt;on a bike&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a disused railway line, straight, level and shaded by trees. Cow parsley and nettles towered in the muddy verges. Insects hovered in the humid air. I was running alongside a Sarn Helen runner and could see two runners ahead. Then one pulled up. Over the course of a couple of steady miles we hauled in and passed the other. I looked back &amp;#8212; mistake &amp;#8212; and saw a Vale Royal AC runner approaching fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the Taff Trail we doubled back on to the Old Nantgarw road, a country lane heading sharply upwards. Ifan had warned me about this and now the marshalls at the bottom of the climb warned me again. About a mile uphill, it does get easier, look out for cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;562&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=Nantgarw+Road,+Caerphilly,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;aq=0&amp;amp;oq=nantga&amp;amp;sll=51.587465,-4.195722&amp;amp;sspn=0.021118,0.036864&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Nantgarw+Rd,+Caerphilly,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=51.56495,-3.263349&amp;amp;panoid=_hWpHiBOqTf0Gzom22AVqg&amp;amp;cbp=13,0,,0,0&amp;amp;ll=51.558823,-3.263369&amp;amp;spn=0.021345,0.048237&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;output=svembed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my chance. I&amp;#8217;d lost sight of the runner ahead of me but I used the slope to push ahead of Sarn Helen and Vale Royal. Dig in, don&amp;#8217;t look back. Hills suit my legs. A couple of off-road motorbikes bowled down the hill. More marshalls stood at the turn on to Groeswen Road. I&amp;#8217;d drunk enough water but grabbed a sponge and wrung it over my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The climb sets the stage finish up, that&amp;#8217;s how Ifan had described it, and he should know: he won this stage last year. It&amp;#8217;s all downhill, lots of turns, all the way to Caerphilly. As the road swerved and tilted I saw the castle, a crumbled pile of stones, far away, further than I&amp;#8217;d hoped. Now I looked back &amp;#8212; no sign of anyone. I lengthened my stride, letting gravity swing my tired legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swansea Harriers were marshalling the finish of the stage so I got some welcome support on the run in. You&amp;#8217;re going well, said Gary. How far now? I asked Kevin. About a mile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mile! As good as a miss. Vale Royal had me in sight, blue and yellow squares. Luckily it was a short mile. I turned a corner and suddenly there were flags and people. Is that the finish? I sprinted for the line. My time was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.welshcastlesrelay.org.uk/results/2012/s19p_2012.html&quot; title=&quot;Stage 19 - Navigation Park to Caerphilly Castle&quot;&gt;01:12:08&lt;/a&gt;, 4:09 behind the stage winner. 12 seconds later Vale Royal appeared and another 27 seconds behind him, Sarn Helen. I came 5th, the first runner from a veterans team, but the runners ahead of me were veterans running in the open category. Anyone over 35 counts as a veteran, which makes no sense in endurance events: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haile_Gebrselassie&quot;&gt;Haile Gebrselassie&lt;/a&gt; knocked 27 seconds off his own world marathon record at the age of 35.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t hang around in Caerphilly. I wanted to catch the finish of the next stage &amp;#8212; leg 20, the final stage &amp;#8212; which was scheduled to arrive in Cardiff at 16:00. The car was where Ifan had said it would be. I put my foot down. Djokovic and Nadal slugged it out on the radio. But a car is no match for a runner approachng the capital and by the time I&amp;#8217;d negotiated roundabouts, traffic lights and ticket machines the race was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studying the results later I discovered the first two home were separated by 14 seconds and 30 years! With Paul Hammond&amp;#8217;s permission, here&amp;#8217;s the culmination of 20+ hours of racing over 20 stages and two days. Andrew Greenleaf pips the veteran &amp;#8212; who, at twice the younger runner&amp;#8217;s age, truly &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; a veteran &amp;#8212; Andrew Greenleaf in black pips Martin Rees in white to the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2F&amp;set_id=72157630125808318&amp;jump_to=&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; src=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=109615&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;true&quot; flashvars=&quot;offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2Fthomasguest%2Fsets%2F72157630125808318%2F&amp;set_id=72157630125808318&amp;jump_to=&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The castles relay offers lots of prizes in lots of categories. The grounds of Cardiff castle are a fine venue for an extended awards ceremony. I drank sweet tea from a thermos flask and munched garibaldis and shook my legs to stop them seizing up. My team, Swansea Harriers veterans, came second in their category, some way behind the Les Croupiers vets. We were monarchs of the mountains, collected first veterans team in a couple of mountain stages, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepowerof10.info/athletes/profile.aspx?athleteid=8208&quot;&gt;Matthew Gurmin&lt;/a&gt; won &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.welshcastlesrelay.org.uk/results/2012/s17p_2012.html&quot;&gt;stage 17&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to Paul Hammond for allowing me to reproduce here some of his superb photos of the event. The versions here are low resolution copies. The originals are on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hammy8241&quot;&gt;Paul Hammond&amp;#8217;s Flickr site&lt;/a&gt;. I also want to thank Gary Irving for his immense effort getting the team organised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-06-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/welsh-castles-relay-2012</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cross country catch up</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;About time I posted these old race reports &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Inter-Regional &amp;amp; Masters Championships, Builth Wells, December 10th 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did say, at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/west-wales-cross-country-championships-2011.html&quot;&gt;Fairwood race&lt;/a&gt;, I was invited to represent West Wales in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.welshathletics.org/competitions/events/cross-country/2011/12-dec/welsh-inter-regional-cross-country-championships.aspx&quot;&gt;inter-regional championships&lt;/a&gt;? Well, the day had come, a chill December morning. White frost coated the meadow at Parkmill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ifan took the scenic route through Llandeilo and LLandovery &amp;#8230; I sank back into the passenger seat and watched the hills roll by. We parked outside the showground and crunched across ice and gravel to the race HQ where the tarpaulin they&amp;#8217;d laid down on the floor was already rucked and muddy. Red and white tapes zig-zagged up the hill, marking out the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collected my West Wales vest. When you get a heavy course, like today, one which includes sections of concrete and tarmac, Ifan said, use longer spikes here and shorter ones here, under the ball of the foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just over an hour to go we jogged a warm-up lap, starting with an extended climb through the woods. You can push on here, he said, as we emerged from the trees and passed a static caravan, still climbing, it&amp;#8217;s downhill for a while after this. At the summit stood an enormous speaker, part of the showground&amp;#8217;s PA system. I could see the Builth Wells showground now &amp;#8212; the timber-clad buildings, the neat field, the high boundary fence &amp;#8212; like a stage in the centre of the immense ampitheatre formed by the surrounding hills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunlight poked through the clouds as we lined up at the start, shivering, edgy. One short lap and two long ones. I found my place and settled in. On the first climb my way was blocked by a tall runner. I moved left to overtake. He moved left. I moved right. He moved right. I passed him by the caravan and extended my lead downhill. Briefly, our route intersected the U15 girls&amp;#8217; race and I was dodging elbows, legs, pony-tails. On the long flat section round the playing fields the tall runner pegged me back. I let him go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching the climb for the second time, the ground had softened. I went past a couple of runners who&amp;#8217;d gone out too fast. I dug in as the path steepened, skeetering wide through tree roots, leaf mould and brambles to pass him. I was clear now but there were two more in front to aim at. I remembered Ifan&amp;#8217;s advice and stumbled over the top on empty, relying on gravity to recharge my legs on the descent. I bounded down a final rocky path, arms flailing, and held on till the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6955236875/&quot; title=&quot;13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011 by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7202/6955236875_2d6a00c8d9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; alt=&quot;13th WELSH INTER REGIONAL CROSS COUNTRY CHAMPIONSHIPS 2011&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;West Glamorgan League, Margam, January 8th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at &lt;a href=&quot;http://westglamleague.co.uk/4.html&quot;&gt;Margam&lt;/a&gt; at eleven in time to see the race start without me. Lesson being, the West Glamorgan races are organised differently. The sight of all those humans on the move had animated the park&amp;#8217;s deer herd. I watched them hurtle round their own short course. I ran the route anyway, slowly, and very boggy it was too. Next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cardiff Cross Challenge, January 15th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://cardiffxchallenge.wordpress.com/the-event/&quot;&gt;McCain Cardiff cross challenge&lt;/a&gt;, held just north of the city centre in Blackweir Fields, is &amp;#8220;one of the most prestigious Cross Country events in the UK&amp;#8221;. Isobel was running. Last time she&amp;#8217;d run, in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-singleton-park-2011.html&quot;&gt;Gwent League&lt;/a&gt;, around a foul course in filthy weather, she&amp;#8217;d failed to finish, so it was a crucial event for her. We arrived in good time and registered. She&amp;#8217;d be wearing her Afan-Nedd-Tawe vest. I&amp;#8217;d be running for Swansea Harriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the going looked fine. The sun was out, the wind was down. The course was flat, dry, sheltered. Isobel had a solid run, finishing strongly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, they&amp;#8217;d fine-tuned the schedule, overlapping races, closing and opening routes through the parkland, somehow without any runners getting trampled, confused or impeded, and so it was that the senior men&amp;#8217;s event, the last of the day, would be starting just an hour after Isobel had finished. With 5 minutes to go I made my way to the starting pen. Where was everyone? Suddenly the elite runners appeared, peeling off thermals, shaking long, elastic legs. We&amp;#8217;d be running four times round. I realised I was in danger of getting lapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/IwVLNiAQYps?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily I avoided any such ignominy. The course seemed tame &amp;#8212; where were the hills, swamps, trenches, wild animals? Isobel injected some welcome variety, appearing at random positions to cheer me on, and her encouragement helped me maintain my pace and place. I did pass one runner on the final lap and pushed hard to close the gap on the next, a tall lad in a black vest, but, closing in on the finish, he kicked away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welsh Cross Country Championships, St Fagans, February 18th 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thomasguest/6910503621/&quot; title=&quot;Start and finished by Thomas Guest, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7053/6910503621_5807ae1e07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Start and finished&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torrential rain and wind during the morning made for very difficult conditions on an already tough course for the 108th running of the Welsh Cross Country Championships. While the junior races were run in these treacherous conditions, the rain had stopped by the time the senior athletes were on the starting line; the damage to the course, however, was already done. &amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.welshathletics.org/news--media/news/cross-country/2012/02-feb/jones-and-griffiths-clinch-cross-country-welsh-titles.aspx&quot;&gt;Welsh Athletics race report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hats off to Isobel for getting round this one. She lasted longer than the inflatable start and finish markers, which were swiftly deflated and packed away before the wind ripped them up. After, she went with Gail and Alex to visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.museumwales.ac.uk/en/stfagans/&quot;&gt;National History Museum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain had indeed stopped by the time the men&amp;#8217;s race started but the course was brutal. I slogged my way round one, two, three, four laps, and was glad when it ended. I pulled my bag from the mud and squelched back through the field to the road-side, texting Gail to collect me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2012-06-10</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cross-country-catch-up</link>
<category>Wales</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
