<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >
<channel>
<title>Thomas Guest</title>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org</link>
<description>two wheels good</description>
<dc:creator>tag@wordaligned.org</dc:creator>
<language>en-gb</language>
<item>
<title>Following the Tour</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As ever, I&amp;#8217;m watching the Tour de France &amp;#8212; or maybe I should say I&amp;#8217;m &lt;strong&gt;following&lt;/strong&gt; the tour, since I get much of my fix online, direct from &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/geraintthomas86&quot; title=&quot;Geraint Thomas&quot;&gt;riders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://inrng.com&quot; title=&quot;The Inner Ring&quot;&gt;commentators&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingnews.com&quot; title=&quot;Cycling News&quot;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I like the mountain stages. The scenery, the history, the combat. Winners and losers. The Pyrenees have disappointed with the favourites marking each other and no one prepared to make a sustained attack. We had this in 2010, and we still don&amp;#8217;t know who won that race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll on the Alps. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/inrng&quot; title=&quot;The Inner Ring, on Twitter&quot;&gt;@inrng&lt;/a&gt; points out, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage19&quot; title=&quot;Inner Ring analysis of stage 19&quot;&gt;Alpe d&amp;#8217;Huez stage is just under 110km&lt;/a&gt;, a sprint. Andy Schleck: don&amp;#8217;t look back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2011/jul/09/team-sky-bradley-wiggins&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2011/7/9/1310205980831/Team-Skys-Bradley-Wiggins-007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bradley Wiggins, crashed out on stage 7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrible to see Bradley Wiggins collapsed on the tarmac nursing a broken collarbone and knowing his race was over. What if? He&amp;#8217;d shed so much weight in preparation for the mountains there wasn&amp;#8217;t much left of him but what remained &amp;#8212; self-belief, humour, quality &amp;#8212; well, the climbers wouldn&amp;#8217;t have dropped him and he&amp;#8217;d have smashed them in the final time trial. There may yet be positives. Geraint Thomas is off the leash and riding with flair and abandon. He&amp;#8217;s no threat in the GC and could well grab a breakaway stage. Team Sky will build and regroup and throw everything at the Vuelta where Wiggo could yet become the first Briton to win a Grand Tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the flatter stages have provided better racing. Cavendish has been a great winner. He also lost well, to Greipel, just the once. For the fourth consecutive year, he&amp;#8217;s fastest. Victory margins haven&amp;#8217;t been massive but to end up in green you have to run a marathon and a sprint, repeatedly. Is all about conserving energy. He can do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil Liggett and Paul Sherwen are putting in a solid performance. Ned Boulting too. Chris Boardman sounds dull, especially when voicing the sponsors&amp;#8217; messages which bookend the ad breaks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve often wondered, why do they have second and third place on the podium? &amp;#8230; Yellow isn&amp;#8217;t a colour, it&amp;#8217;s a state of mind &amp;#8230; When my team had to lift me off my bike at the end of a stage, I knew I&amp;#8217;d done enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take (some of) it back about Chris Boardman: his analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;http://inrng.com/2011-tour-de-france-guide/#Stage16&quot;&gt;stage 16&lt;/a&gt;, the one which finished with a treacherous descent into Gap, was spot on. There&amp;#8217;s Andy Schleck moaning people don&amp;#8217;t want to see a race won downhill, yet he hasn&amp;#8217;t raced uphill either, not really. Or as CB described it: throwing the toys out of his pram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2011-07-19</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/following-the-tour</link>
<category>Wiggins</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Week One</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, a rest day today, after a week of quite literal thrills and spills. Yesterday provided a fitting finale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember last year, that final mountain stage on Mont Ventoux? It was meant to decide the general classification but by then Contador, already in yellow, had enough of a lead to ride defensively and cover the attacks. Andy Schleck couldn&amp;#8217;t shake him off. The stage was effectively neutralised. Yesterday, on the first Alpine stage, it looked like Schleck hadn&amp;#8217;t stopped at the summit of Ventoux at all. There he was, still poised on Contador&amp;#8217;s shoulder, a fresh-faced skinny executioner kitted out in white. This time Contador didn&amp;#8217;t look so clever. Schleck may not have taken much time out of his rival but he beat him convincingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingnews.com/races/97th-tour-de-france-gt/stage-8/results&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com//2010/07/11/2/bettiniphoto_0056537_1_full_600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Schleck the skinny executioner&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-12</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-week-one</link>
<category>Wiggins</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>TdF, 2010, Stages 0 and 1</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Chapeau, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itv.com/sport/tourdefrance/&quot;&gt;ITV4&lt;/a&gt;, for the live coverage, even if I can&amp;#8217;t see myself getting to watch much of it. The prologue stage has definitely whetted the appetite. I&amp;#8217;m pleased Cancellara won. &amp;#8220;My body worked at 100% for exactly ten minutes,&amp;#8221; he said. It&amp;#8217;s almost unthinkable that another expert clock-racer, Brad Wiggins, could drop almost a minute over such a short course, but he did. I&amp;#8217;ve read Wiggo&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Pursuit-Glory-Autobiography-Bradley-Wiggins/dp/0752884034&quot;&gt;In Pursuit of Glory: The Autobiography&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; one for the fans, I think, but one thing I did take from it was how accurately Wiggo can calibrate his form on the track. He knows how long it takes for him to ride a kilometre in a covered velodrome to within a second. A wet road in Rotterdam is less predictable, and Wiggo wanted to avoid trouble. Cancellara has more panache and his bike-handling skills are sans pareil. So he won. Can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him attack the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages&quot;&gt;cobbled roads&lt;/a&gt; in stage 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingnews.com/features/2010-tour-de-france-cobbled-stages&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.media.cyclingnews.com/2010/04/09/2/img_0669_600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Going. To. Be. Carnage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hardened campaigner got going when the going got tough. Armstrong took a chunk out of Wiggins and other GC rivals in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.letour.fr/2010/TDF/LIVE/us/0/classement/index.html&quot;&gt;prologue&lt;/a&gt;. He also got the first strike in against Contador (let&amp;#8217;s not forget that he lost 22 seconds to the Spaniard over the same stage last year). I&amp;#8217;ll bet he rattles Contador some more on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/lancearmstrong/status/17414049508&quot;&gt;cobbles&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking forwards to the highlights of Stage One this evening, especially when it became obvious it would end with a bunch sprint. About time to see Cavendish stretch his legs. Except it didn&amp;#8217;t happen like that. Cav has had a rotten run-in to the Tour this year. Always volatile and unpredictable, he&amp;#8217;s turning into very a loose cannon. He tumbled on the final bend taking out rival Oscar Freire. Last year no one got close to Cav. And this year other riders would do well to stay away from him. With Cav down the other riders had to improvise the final kilometre and they made a spectacular mess of it, staging a mass pile up instead of a mass sprint. Quelle horreur!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2010-07-04</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/tdf-2010-stages-0-and-1</link>
<category>Wiggins</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>In Search of Robert Millar</title>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strangely, the cyclists who seem to cope least well when the curtain falls on their careers are the climbers. I mean the &lt;em&gt;pure&lt;/em&gt; climbers &amp;#8212; the very few who, when the road soars upwards, are able to take flight, as if they are fleeing those whom Millar nick-named the &amp;#8220;animals&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; all-rounders like Hinault, LeMond, Indurain, Armstrong. Necessarily, the climbing specialists are small, fragile, birdlike in build, power-to-weight ratio being all important in the mountains. And perhaps, in some cases, a rider&amp;#8217;s physical build is not so easily separated from his psychological make-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Richard Moore, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;In Search of Robert Millar&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tag.wordaligned.org/images/in-search-of-robert-millar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book cover. In Search of Robert Millar&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Moore_%28journalist%29&quot;&gt;Richard Moore&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s superb book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Robert-Millar-Unravelling-Surrounding/dp/000723502X&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;In Search of Robert Millar&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, has provided me with the perfect come down after the thrills of this year&amp;#8217;s Tour de France.  Any talk of Bradley Wiggins being &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/news/latest/384420/tour-comment-is-bradley-wiggins-the-best-ever-brit.html&quot;&gt;the best ever British tour rider&lt;/a&gt; is premature: no one can seriously dispute the book&amp;#8217;s tagline, &amp;#8220;Unravelling the mystery surrounding Britain&amp;#8217;s most successful  Tour de France cyclist&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; unless, that is, they want to remove any qualification of Millar&amp;#8217;s achievements and nominate him simply as Britain&amp;#8217;s most successful road cyclist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millar&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Millar#Palmares&quot;&gt;palmares&lt;/a&gt; includes king of the mountains in the Giro and the Tour, a 4th place finish in the 1984 Tour, 2nd places in the Vuelta and the Giro, and victory in the Dauphin&amp;eacute; Lib&amp;eacute;r&amp;eacute;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is no hagiography. Millar is revealed as a complex and contradictory character; a man who defies any attempt to get close to him. He comes across as awkward, shy, and abrasive. Many people fail to get his sense of humour. Moore believes Millar had the ability and drive to win a grand tour but lacked the personality. Winning such a race requires the respect of your team and indeed of the peleton, political skills which Millar lacks; and Moore identifies this weakness as the main cause of the conspiracy which tricked him out of victory in the 1985 Vuelta. Millar eventually seemed happier as a super-domestique, a professional who would work for the team, but who remained capable of stealing stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millar refuses to play the media game. He has often been rude to commentators and journalists. Yet he has also proved himself to be an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rouleur.cc/recent-features/240-previewissue13&quot;&gt;articulate thinker and writer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since retiring from the sport Millar has again taken flight. Where is he now? What is he up to? Few people know. Email is the only way of reaching him, and in the book&amp;#8217;s epilogue Moore does at last make contact with Millar. He reprints their brief email exchange, ending his book with Millar&amp;#8217;s own words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a satisfying, thoroughly researched, well written book. Certainly it asks and investigates difficult questions, but the answers aren&amp;#8217;t always forthcoming. The story continues &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color:gold;font-size:400%;&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&amp;#x2605;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-08-14</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/in-search-of-robert-millar</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/in-search-of-robert-millar</link>
<category>Wiggins</category>
</item>

<item>
<title>Someone race Cavendish, please</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/routes/overseas/345690/etape-du-tour-2009-route-recce.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cyclingweekly.co.uk/imageBank/e/etape-2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;540px&quot; height=&quot;360px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tour de France takes a rest today (though not for the riders in the &amp;Eacute;tape du Tour, who&amp;#8217;ll take on Mont Ventoux six days before the pros), giving me a chance to try and make sense of a strange and compelling weekend of racing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;#8217;s short sharp climb to Verbier made perfect sense and settled a few outstanding questions. Noone climbs like Contador, and the Madrile&amp;ntilde;o confirmed his position as race favourite and Astana team leader. The way he dances up the steepest slopes is truly thrilling. I can&amp;#8217;t wait to see him climb Ventoux. Armstrong rode with the elite riders, but I&amp;#8217;d say Kl&amp;ouml;den may well be shaping up as the Astana number 2 &amp;#8212; he&amp;#8217;s a strong time trial rider who looked in fine shape on the climb, edging Armstrong at the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how about Brad Wiggins? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/blog/2009/jul/19/bradley-wiggins-tour-de-france&quot;&gt;Shedding 9% of his bodyweight&lt;/a&gt; has morphed him from track rider into Grand Tour contender. Best of all, he&amp;#8217;s enjoying himself. I think he could come out of Thursday&amp;#8217;s time trial &amp;#8212; his favourite discipline &amp;#8212; as Contador&amp;#8217;s main rival for yellow. Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/14/mark-cavendish-tour-de-france-stage-10&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2009/7/14/1247596770216/Mark-Cavendish-001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Why isn&#x27;t Cav in green?&quot; width=&quot;460px&quot; height=&quot;276px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday&amp;#8217;s stage was more complex. I&amp;#8217;m struggling to understand what Mark Cavendish was playing at. Cavendish already has a remarkable 4 stage victories in this year&amp;#8217;s Tour, matching the 4 he took last year. Well, the number is remarkable, but this year the sprint finishes have seemed routine: the Columbia train leads him out over the final few kilometres, then his team-mates peel away in sequence leaving him to deliver the killer blow. The trouble is, Cavendish&amp;#8217;s rivals have already rolled over and died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Sport evolves and, if you go back to the 1970s, I never, ever had a lead-out man, not once,&amp;#8221; Hoban said this week. &amp;#8220;Everyone was there, man to man. The way they do it now, with a team like that, if they are leading out at 65kph very few people are going to come over that. Anyone to challenge Mark going at 65kph has got to do 70kph.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2009/jul/19/tour-de-france-history-hoban-cavendish&quot;&gt;Barry Hoban&lt;/a&gt;, quoted in the Observer newspaper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d have thought this supremacy would leave Cavendish way out in front in the green jersey but he hasn&amp;#8217;t chased enough intermediate sprints. This leaves him (left him) head to head with the mighty Thor Hushovd in the points competition. My opinion? I don&amp;#8217;t think Cavendish relishes scrabbling for points and it&amp;#8217;s brought out his petulant side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He says he&amp;#8217;s fastest. His rivals admit he&amp;#8217;s fastest. He is fastest. But he still wants a race!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we had a strange situation. Popular Columbia rider, George Hincapie, was in a breakaway and had a realistic shot at yellow. So team Columbia wanted to slow the chase. But team Columbia also wanted Cavendish to win the peloton sprint for the points given to the 13th place finisher; and so, once more, the train chugged down the final kilometre with everyone watching the clock. Cavendish barely bothered to race for the line. Yes, he blocked Hushovd when he could and should have flown away from him. He wanted to win but in as slow a time as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event Hincapie missed out on yellow by just 5 seconds. You can&amp;#8217;t blame Cavendish for that, but Cavendish is a team player and I suspect he cared more about his team missing yellow than his subsequent disqualification in the sprint. He just wasn&amp;#8217;t bothered about a race for 13th place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, it&amp;#8217;s probably cost him the green jersey and taken the edge off the showdown next Sunday. I hope he stops feeling hard done by and comes out ready to race. I know he cares more about being fastest on the Champs-&amp;Eacute;lys&amp;eacute;es than the points competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<dc:date>2009-07-20</dc:date>
<guid>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race</guid>
<author>tag@wordaligned.org (Thomas Guest)</author>
<link>http://tag.wordaligned.org/posts/cav-wants-race</link>
<category>Wiggins</category>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
